<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-hypnotism</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064205/1887-06-29/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;
q=hypnosis+HYPNOTIC+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotized&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=-0.045,0.145,0.645,0.494,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>EYPNOTIC PHENOMENA
Marrelous Demonstrations bj Eminont
French Scientists Peisons and
Objects Made Invisible at Will
sterlonsEffects
o
Effects Produced l y the Use
Magnets Wise Men
Mystified
Boston Herald
One of the most notable features of the
scientific tendencies of the present day is
the extraordinary interest taken in the in
vestigation ofthosejeculiar physical and
psychical conditions now known collec
tively under the name of hypnotism
varying from lethargy catalepsy etc to
somnambulism Until quite recently
these investigations have been frowned
upon and taboed in scientific circles and
the fact that any man of scientific inclina
tions was known to feel an interest in
matters associated with mesmerism or
animal magnetism was sullicient to
make him an object of suspicion and in
jure his good standing among his fellow
scientists The result of these socalled
investigations instituted by the French
academy pronouncing in effect the whole
subject a humbug and delusion has lain
like an interdict upon further re
searches and the whole matter was left
over for the most parr to charlatans or
to persons hardly capable of forming
sound judgment or proceeding according
to the accurate methods demanded by
modern science Science however in
the remarkable progress made of late
23 advanced so far upon certain lines
vt It has been hardly possible to pro
od further in those directions without
leering upon the forbidden fied There
re the old signboards against trespass
is have bten taken down For
mesmerism that verbal scarecrow has
been substituted hypnotism which
word has had a wonderfully legitimizing
effect while animal magnetism that
once llouted idea has been proven to be
sn existing fact by methods as accurate
as those adopted by Faraday or
Edison to verily their observations
EFFORTS OK SCIENTISTS
Many of the most eminent scientists of
Europe are now devoting themselves
assiduously to these researches Periodi
cals making a specialty of the subject are
now published in France Germany and
England A catalogue of the recent
literature of hypnotism and related phe
nomena compiled by Max Dessoir was
printed in the number of the German
magazine called the Sphinx for February
of this year and this catalogue occupied
nine pages The list is limited to those
words written on the lines laid under the
methods of the modern school all books
being excluded whose authors hold to
mesmeric theories or who are even
professional magnetizers The catalogue
is therefore as strictly scientific as pos
sible and being classified with German
thoroughness under the different branches
of the subject such as hysterohypnot
ism suggestion fascination etc
it will prove a valuable assistance to the
udent
In this country the interest of scient
1s has not yet been aroused to an ex
mt comparable to that of European in
jstigators Old prejudices have not
5tirely lost their potency One of the
most eminent professors of s leading
university is said to have been subjected
to ridicule from his colleagues because of
a marked interest shown in the subject
and a Boston physician of high standing
within a few months confided to the
writer that he had made use of hypnotic
methods with gratifying success in the
case of a patient where ordinary reme
dies hd proved unavailing but he did
not venture to make the result public
since his fellowdoctors might be inclined
to condemn his action as irregular
A work embracing the whole subject
has lately appeared in Paris and as it is
to form a volume of the valuable Inter
national Scientific series published in
English French German and Italian it
can hardly fail to diffuse a correct popu
lar understanding of the results thus far
attained The book is called Le Mag
netism Animal Animal Magnetism
and its authors are Messrs Alfred Binet
and Charles Fere of the medical staff of
the Saltpetrier Hospital for Nervous Dis
orders in Paris It gives a history of the
patient researches conducted at that in
stitution by the medical staff under the
celebrated Professor Charcote during the
past nine years These experiments have
been prosecuted according to the most
exact scientific methods and with the
most extreme caution The endeavor
has been to obtain first of all the
most elementary psychic phenomenon
and to test every step in the
investigations by separate experiments
specially devised to prove the good faith
of the subject and the reality of his hal
lucination to eliminate the possibility of
unconscious suggestion to establish re
lations with similar phenomena of disease
or health in tne domain of physiology
and to note the modifications which can
be brought about by altering the condi
tions of the experiments The authors
possess the great scientific virtue of
never dogmatizing In the entire book
not a single law is laid down not a
single hypothesis is advanced which is
not reached by the most improved in
ductive processes A great service of
the book lies in its enunciation of new
and trustworthy methods for studying
the physiology of the brain in health and
disease while It brings into the realm of
physical experiment vexed questions ot
psychology heretofore given over to met
aphysical methods exclusively
THE HYPNOTIC SLEEP
is described as a different form of natu
ral sleep and all the causes which bring
on fatigue are capable of bringing on
hypnotism on suitable subjects Two
of the leading hypnotic states are lethar
gy and catalepsy the former being anala
gous to deep sleep and the latter to a
light slumber In lethargy the respirato
ry movements are slow and deep cat
alepsy slight shallow very slow and
separated by a long interval In lethargy
the application of a magnet over the re
gion of the stomach causes profound mod
ifications in the breathing and circulation
while there is eo such effect in catalepsy
This shows the connection of hypnotism
with magnetism and various other ex
periments with magnets have produced
some wonderful results Here it may be
added that Dr Geesmam a Vienna
scientist who has made a specialty of
hypnotic 8titdies has Invented and suc
cessfully applied an Instrument called a
hypnoscope consisting of an arrangement
of magnets for the purpose of ascertain
ing whether any persons is a good hyp
notic subject
The experiments demonstrate that
sensation In the hypnotic states varies
Detween the two opposite poles of
hypetcc3thesia and antesthesia in other
words the senses may be extraordinarily
excited as in somnambulism or as in
lethargy they may be extinct except
sometimes hearing In somnambulism
the field of vision and acutebess of sight
are about double hearing is made very
acute and smell is so intensely develop
ed that a subject can find by scent the
fragments of a card previously given to
him to feeJ and torn up and hidden The
memory of somnambulism is similarly
exalted When awakened the subject
does not as a rule remember anything
that occurred when he was entranced
but when again hypnotized his memory
includes all the facts of his sleep his life
when awake and his former sleeps
ltichet attests how somnambules recall
with a luxury of detail scenes in which
they have taken part and places they
have visited long ago M one of
his somiambules sings the air of the
second act of the opera LAfricaine when
she is asleep but cnnot remember a
note of it when awake
There is a theory that no experience
wlmtever of a person is lost to the mem
ory it is only the power to recall it that
is defective The authors of this work say
that while the exaltation of the memory
during somnambulism does not give ab
solute proof to the theory that nothing is
lost it proves at any rate that the mem
ory of preservation is much greater than
is generally imagined in comparison with I tauce of
ing recollection more
or less vivid per
sists for a lew seconds then becomes ef
faced This forgetfulness is even more
marked in the case of hypnosis On re
turning to natural consciousness the sub
ject cannot recompose o single one of the
scenes in which he has played his part as
a witness or actor The loss howeveri3
not complete for often a word or two is
sufficient to bring back a whole scene
though this word or two coming from
operator to subject partakes more or less
of the nature ot a suzgestion
</text>
		</result>
		<result>
			<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93063557/1888-03-02/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotization+hypnotized/</id>
			<rel>1</rel>
			<text>Tcoplc fiuseeptlblo to JtypnntlMn.
Pcrsons of n nervous constitution, nnd
ln particular thoso subject to hysteria,
nro most npt to fnll Into nrtiflciai Klcop.
Thcro is thcn produccd in thein n pecu
liar neurosis, hypnotism, having psjxhl
cal nnd physical charactcra of its own a
genuino disease prcscnting n diversity of
Byinptoms. Hcnco hypnotic phenomena
ouglit not to be callcd forth rnshly nor
without the )recaution8 suggestcd by
inedical scienco. 'VVomcn aro spccially
Biiscoptiblo to hypnotio manipulation, par
tictilarly during tho period bctwoen the
18tlinnd tho 30th ycar, whcn tho ner
vous system is in full nctivity. Young
lncn may bo hypnotized, but it is very
difllcult to produco hypnotic slccp in old
uion or in ehildren. Pcrsons who in carly
llfo nro subject to naturnl somnambulism
or slecp walldng are latcr in life good
hypnotio subjccts, just as they aro nlo
likely to Imj victiius of hysteria and othcr
nervous complaints.
Jlany aro tlio processes oniploycd for
prodticing hypnoais. One that is very
frecjucntly used consists in fixing tiio gazo
upon soino hriglit object placed a littlo
abovo tho eycs and in front of tho median
lino of tho forohcad, so that visunl fntiguo
uiay cnsuo quickly, tiio eyeballs being
dircctod upward and iuward. This pro
cess, or othcrs of a liko kind, may Ihj otn
ployed in tho caso of pcrsons wlio havo
novcr bcforc been hypnotized. Dtit after
awliile, when the subject has, so to speak,
been eduoated. various nioro exix?ditious
uiethods may be employed. Thus a jct
of elcctrio light or a violcnt blow stmck
on a gong near tlio ear of tho subject will
quickly induco sleep. Again, in hypno
tizablo ixji-sons, the surface of tlie body
often prescnts special points, "hypnogenic
zoncs, as thoy aro called, analagous to
tho ''hysterogcuic zones." Simplo pres
8uro upon theso produces hypnosis.
Even in tho caso of tho most susceptiblo
individuals rarely does sleep nppear when
tliey. for tho flrst time, undergo tho hyp
notizing manipulations, howcver skilled
tho ojwrator may be. Tliero is necded a
completo surrender of ono's will and nb
senco of all mental preoccupation, and
on tho part of the company prcsent abso
lutc silcnce. In most cases exhibitions
of hypnotization develop, at flrst, only
vaguo jihcnomena not easily classified,
foreshadowing, 60 to 6)eak, what will
follow later. North American Eoview.
		</text>
      </result>
      <result>
		<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84037890/1888-07-25/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotizing&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=0.504,0.298,0.325,0.249,0</id>
		<rel>1</rel>
		<text>Study of the Hypnotic State.
Dr. A. Dichas has mado n detailed study
of tho memory In tho hypnotic state, nnd
summarizes his main conclusions
as follows: (1) during tlio hypnotic
sleep tho subject remembers the experiences
of his wiking Ufo ns well rs of
previous hypnosis; (2) in hypnotism tlicro
is often an exalt tion of tho memory, and
at times n cliang in Its content, leading
to tho assumpti n of a foreign
(3) tho mo nory of what has been
going on during hypnosis is usually lost,
it can often bo ruvlvcd by n simplo suggestion,
and at times the memory of a
suggested hallucination may l!.,jor on.
and influenco thu waking condition; (4)
tho operator cau at his wjll havo any of
tho nets of the liypnotK state remembered
or forgotten by maMug this a part
of tho suggestion; (5) sitgjfcstion seems to
bo largely explicable 'as unconscious
memory.
Dr. Cybulski has studied tho power of
hypnotic subjects to hypnotlzo themselves.
IIo finds that such subjects
strongly Imagiuo for a mlnuto or less that
that tho operator commands them to go
to sleep, nnd tho desired result ensues.
Furthermore, If tlio subject, on going to
sleep, imagines himself controlled by a
certain person, then, even though another
sent him to sleep, he will bo subject to
tlio former, nnd not to tho operator.
These observations show the Importance
of tho subjectivo clement in tho process
of hypnotism, nnd Indicate tho method by
which tho subject unconsciously takes
suggestions and acts upon them. Dr.
Bcrkhan has applied hypnotism to the
amelioration of the hearing of tho deaf.
Ho tested tho hearing of nino deaf boys,
and, after hypnotizing them, spoko to
them and had varions.noises made before
them Tho hearing of four of them was
found to bo Improved, and tho improve
merit is reported as still persisting after
eighteen months Science.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	  <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1899-09-24/ed-1/?sp=21&amp;
q=Hypnotic+HYPNOTISM+Hypnotism+Hypnotize+Hypnotized+medicine&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=0.707,0.439,0.462,0.354,0</id>
	  <rel>1</rel>
	  <text>WHAT IS HYPNOTISM swim. Anyone who desires can l arn how to Hyp-
nottte. Anyone who learns can practise It. The Held
Is Htpnotltedt What form l exerted that after for Its exercise Is as wide as humanity Itself. As a
makingRmnn sleeproiidcn him ton false wakeful. study It Is neither deep nor dlfflerilt. The most
nc s In which he obejr anysuirKettlon loses hit IJon- ordinary capacity and attention are all that arc re
itltr. jiiMXt ii UfiRuiRf for- quired. The study Is not only easy but delightful
dun to him feels rontrmtlc- and Inspiring. You must Irurn It. You cannot
torjrirnnMloni ntmtakesrart afford to neglect n science so full of grand poMlblll-
In ttrnnec scene ami Ihcnii ties. If you desire to make the most of Ufa you
suddenly aroused to Imvc no should master Its powers for yourself and nse them
memory of what hns hap for your own gain advancement and Inflne nee. Why
pened not.yourself sway the minds of othtrs.control friend
These questions are airtta. ship and altcctlon. heal the sick and sultorlng gKo
tins the minds of untold proOtablo entertainment In publto or private and dis
thousands throughout the cover at your v. 111 the hidden aveimn of success and
world toitAr. What do you material wealth Others nrodolng lu Whynotyouf
know about Hypnotism r
Nothing. Then 1 will tell jou HOW YOU MAY LEARN HYPNOTISM.
nil about It.
I will show rou that It Is I am recognized aa the
the tnout wotiilrrfnl leading Hypnotist InAmer
tliltiR on rnrth. I will lea. 1 lint e practised and
taught the Art of Hypnotism
provo to on that Ilrpnottim
cures diseasethat ItbanUhc tism for years. Nearly all
pain that It unravels the mjrt- thechlcf Hypnotists of the
lory of crimp that It aid Jus- land have been my pupils.
ttco that It fosters brainpower No other Hypnotist has

power ml tint It can bruucd won greater renown In this
by all who know It to mnko those dear to them happy field or haa done so much
nnd auccetif ul to reform the crrlnff and degraded and for the promotion of this
to confer n thousand blessings on ttio feeble the un wonderful Science. 1 am
happy the poverty-stricken on the unetlnp of mind the conceded authority on
nnd body who arc al ays and everywhere a largo ele this subject In this coun
ment In our surroundings. try. I have given the best of my days to tha study
and demonstration of thin darling sclcnco. Its wonderful
1 win ihow jou that every day la revealing new
wonders deeper mysteries nnd wander possibilities derful powers and mysteries have become a part of
In thin the Selrnco of the Century and that you my being and fill mo with an enthusiasm that over
rnn learn to utlllie thin wonderful force In all Iti flows In the longing to Impart them to others. I nm
form and phases. I will tell you about a wonderful like one who has found gold-mine and cannot keep
Illumined book on Hypnotism which for the asking the secret of his wealth. All the plaudits I have won
w HI conio to you postage paid without any charge or In my exhibitions and all the money I hm e made by
cost whatever. But first you Ik them could not gratify mo half to much as to
know that others were cherishing the snmo science
WHAT IS HYPNOTISM and would further the development of Its possibili
ties for good I want to Interest the whole world la
Hypnotism Isaniipll or trance-like sleep i that one Hypnotism. I want you to learn It. 1 want you to
person by certain simple methods east orcr another. understand It because It will give you the mastery of
while In thlsstatcthasubjectorhypn minds the ability to mould at pleasure the Impe
oncan bo made to perform the most rial human will. Hypnotism will do n thousand
urprlstnR and amazing feats bodily times more than this. It Is n healer of disease. It
nnd mental of which they are totally .Isnwlnncrof human affections. It
Incapable whtlo In their waking Isn spell of hnp. It Is an agency of
hours. The mind of the subject Is success position wealth nnd fame.
entirely under tlio control of the It Is n tutrncle. worker and an Influ
operator. Ho may be made to see ence In all the ltal concerns
and bcnr nnd think and feel exactly as the of Individuals families and so1 1
Hypnotist wishes and just so long and no clety. Not to know such n
longer 1 science Is to ho Ignorant Indeed
Not to use. such a weapon 1st
THE WONDERS OF HYPNOTISM. prcmo folly. It Is a\ntlabl
to young or old of cither
In attempting to stale what Hypnotism Is sex and It Is my proud
I can gl\olntho space hero available but n boast to have made It
bnro outline of Its tremendous powers. No
pen could adcquatclydescrlbetheinarvclsihat FREE TO ALL.
may bo bronght about through Hypnotism.
You must sco It and learn to use It before I I have publfshed at great
you can fully renllto how wonderful Is that eixpnnao n MA51-
Nllout nnil mynterlouH force which en MOTII ir.i.us-
ables one man to seize on Its very throne the TKATljn TK15AT-
will of another and'mako him conform to his IHF. or limtriirtor
Bllgbtest wish In every act and feeling. In llypnotlamwhlcli
tein ovcrythlnir
THE USE OF HYPNOTISM. te about this Art. A
copy of It Is at your
The possession of Hypnotic power will open _ eervlca If you tnko
up to you whole regions of good to your fellow mor the trouble to write for It.
tals and a sure way for yourself to honors and wealth There Is positively no cost nor charge In connection
no less than to scientific progress and pleasant pas- with this gift. If you wrlto for It oven on a postal
time. If you are an eager student It will unfold to card 1 will send It promptly nnd free by mall. Kv-
you a now and fascinating realm of science. If you eryhodv who has read It pronounces It a wonderful
are a person of means and book. It Is a clear exposition of the Importance
S leisure Itwlll provide you with methods wonders and uses of Hypnotic Sclcncn
v endless recreation. If you are down even to the details of entertainments given
generous and philanthropic for money-making purposes. Never before \\ai
\Itwlllcnablcyoutuheapblcsi- such a gift made In the Interests of any science.
lIngs on less fortunate fellow-
j beings. If you are the head THIS WONDERFUL BOOK IS FREE.
j will of a make family or household. It It Is the most valuable and Interesting work of the
nnd you the physician kind ever published. It explains the Mysteries or
true ot
comforter those
lu Hypnotism from A to Z. It tells you Just what Hyp
your that caro. And finally notism Is and what It will accomplish. It tells you
suppose ago or fortune how you may control the minds of others perform ns-
arc frowning upon you or that tonlimng feats and produce amusement by the hour.
you arestlllyoung.fortuneless It covers the whole ground of Hypnntlo methods In
and and have
friendless to
yet caryo In
your way
such that ou can learn rapidly. It tells you
away
the world all these various privileges will be In
your
all should know about Hypnotism Its phenomena
and with them you
grasp along a sure means to position
na Its mysteries and Its advantages to you personally
Influence happiness and golden wealth. If
your
wealth. Influence
for the certain attainment of
ally
choice Is not already taken or desire to make
you a
cannot fiord to bo without
health and happiness. Ton n
change can also 11 ml In Hypnotism Itself lu-
you a
and honorable out this knowledge. You need not alt In darkncsa
crtithe. tbat
permiinant profession while such light Is free. Do sensible send for a copy
will give you fame and competence during your active
of this book and Icnrn to Hypnotize.
with and
tive years security distinction for the
evening ot life.
HYPNOTISM IN DISEASE.
Hypnotism has Indeed grand and glorious utili
ties It has gains aa well as enjoyments for all who
master It. Among these the
place of honor limy well bo
1 plven to Us wonderful efficacy
llu alleviating human gutter-
ling and curing disease. With-
lout doubt It la the Krcat
Ihcnlorof the future. No
/Anodyne ever known Is equal
f to It In the relief and allcvl-
r atton of pain. No medicine
ever prepared can wrestle so
effectively with the ravages of
disease. The delicate and nervous
vous woman tbo overworked
man and the sickly and fretful child may all alike be
benefited by Its application. It Ii a boon and bless
ing to the entire race.
AS A MEANS OF AMUSEMENT.
The fun makln possibilities of Hypnotism are
Imply unlimited. Ha\o you over been present at
an exhibition ot Hypnotism given cither to a publto
or private audience If you have you will readily
agree that as a means of entertainment of genuine
hilarity and fun this wonderful power Is beyond all
rivalry. Not all the comedy ever teen on the mimic
stage Is so absurd and mirth-provoking or so full of
laughable and yet harmless surprises.
The absurd and ridiculous things a Hypnotized
person will do are almost beyond belief Uo will do
anything you command or ftuRgcst to him.
A f uw persons wlillo under the Influence of Hypno
tism will produce more genuine amusement moro
astonishment and amazement than a minstrel show
and comic openi combined. This crand work contains hundreds or tbo most ar
This fact will at once tistic Illustrations ever produced. Tlio cover Is n
suggest that If you have no remarkable work of art. Above all clto the subject
accomplishments Hypno- matter Is ably handled and Is new llcly and fascin
tlsm would provo of Im ating. Everything Is told In plain lanijunRO Kvcry
mense value to you. You fact method and phenomenon described can lie un
would no longer ho kept derstood by anybody who knows how to read. Kvcry
In the background at a par process that calls for pictorial help will bo found
ty or publlu gathering for fully Illustrated so that you will bo carried along
with the abfilty to llyp- pleasantly until you know all the Ins and outs of tlio
notlze you can produce subject. Everything about the work shows that no
amusement for hours at a expense was spared In getting It up and when you
time. With a few subjects consider tbat It
or even one you can keep _ COSTS ABSOLUTELY NOTHING
an audience lu a continual roar of laughter.
you must admit that this Is tha most generous offer
YOU CAN LEARN IT. uvcr made lu behalf of this marvelous science.
Let me mail you a copy of tuU book. If you nro
Reader you can become a Hypnotist. There Is no not surprised auddcllRhted with It If you do no t con-
reason on earth to the contrary. It is a faculty Inborn elder It tlio most valuable and Interesting Rift ever
born In every Individual just like the faculty of offered the American public I will Rladly reimburse
speech. It only requires cultivation In order to bo you for the slight trouble of wrltlnc for It. Hcincm-
developed and applied. In fact. It Is as easy to learn herltls free as nlr. A postal card will bring It by
how to Hypnotize aa It Is to learn how to waltz or return mallpostage paid. Bend for It today. Address</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042405/1892-12-15/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;
q=hypnosis+Hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+HYPNOTISM+hypnotized+hypnotizing&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=0.07,0.543,0.297,0.227,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE ABUSE OF HYPNOTISM.
Quack* and CliarlntaiM Wlio Mukti I'M OL
It to iiull the Public.
Wliilo tho benefits from hypnotism
thus fur have been few anil small, the
evils have been many nml great. Its
Bleeplike btato is not a normal sleep,
bringing health and Htrength to the
sliuuberer, but a morbid conditiou bor­
dering u|iou disease. It irritates the en­
tire nervous organization and tempora­
rily if not organically weakens the sys­
tem. This drawback is serious enough.
Darker and more terrible effects lie in
the suppression of the object's will for
the time being, and the substitution
therefor of the operator's. In this re­
gard it opens avenues to crime and crimi­
nals such us has never been equaled
heretofore. Already so many discredit­
able actions, not to use a stronger word,
have been committed in Europe by
means of hypnotism that in Italy, Aus
tro-Hungary, parts of Switzerland, Co­
penhagen and other municipalities laws
have been enacted prohibiting its public
practice by any except physicians. So,
on the other hand, tip police, without
any statute on the subject, have treated
traveling mesmerists as disorderly char­
acters. Thus Donato was expelled from
Italy, and Hansen, another hypnotist,
from Austria, was notified never to re­
turn under penalty of arrest, fine and
imprisonment.
This Donato (whose real name, by the
way, is Dhont) hypnotized an Italian ar­
tillery officer, who immediately became
half crazy. From time to time he would
go into somnambulism at the sight of a
bright object. He would follow carriage
iamps. and unless prevented would walk
toward locomotive or steamer lights.
An architectural student was mesmer­
ized by staring at his compasses, after
which it was impossible for him to draw
without going to sleep.
A young girl of Milan, of beauty and
character, was hypnotized and impressed
with the notion that she was married 'o
a man she had never seen but once, and
then in the darkness. She went crazy
and died in a hospital.
Another voting girl (of Paris, this
time) was put under a similar spell and
was ruined. She finally entered the
Saltpetriere hospital, where, after along
and painful remedy, what was left of
her former self was pronounced cured.
In New York a hypnotized person was
made to believe that he had taken slow
poison. He fell sick and wasted away
to a shadow. Not until the attending
physician discovered the true nature of
the hallucination and relivpnotized the
subject was there any symptom of con­
valescence.
In Turin, at a series of hypnotic lec­
tures and public experiments, a large
proportion of those who attended were
taken sick with headache, insomnia and
other nervous ailments. A few of those
who were of a hysterical temperament
remained ill for along time.
In the foregoing cases the hypnotizing
was done with no evil intent, but there
are hundreds of recorded instances where
it was done with intent of evil.—Phila­
delphia Times.</text>
      </result>
	   <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1894-12-16/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=Hypnosis+hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotically+Hypnotism+hypnotism+hypnotize+Hypnotized+hypnotized+hypnotizing/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Hypnotism and Its Relation to Crime.
None are more bigoted than infidels.
The science of a generation ago was
proud of its infidelity. Without a dem
onstration in (acts it would believe
nothing; nor, indeed, beyond its nar
row physical range did it desire to see
anything, to know anything:. No Span
ish padre in Mm train of Isabella, no
exhorting captain of Cromwell's pray
erful warriors, no hadji at the well of
Zem-Zem, was ever blinder to enlight
enment, more invincible to argument.
In the opinion of tnia scientific omnis
cience, astrology, witchcraft, magic,
omens, premonitions, spiritualism, clair
voyance, mesmerism, personal magnet
ism and ghosts were alike ridiculous
and incredible. These alleged phenom
ena could not be brought under the
microscope nor submitted to the rule of
three. They were therefore impossible
in both the English and the French
sense of the word. This arrogant,
bigoted devotion to the purely physical
exhibited none of the lofty ideality of
that pure, if uninstructed, soul who
exciat&amp;
ed "I believe it, because it is
impossible!" These scientists were "of
the earth, earthy."
1 test limit Truth could not, however,
lone endure this degradation. The
things undreamt of by iiuratio existed
nevvriliuless. They will always exist:
nor will ignoring them obliterate them.
Science accused Religion of believing
too much, but Science herself believed
too little. To fall by dark into a ditch
and believe it a well may not be sensi
ble; to ignore that you are in the ditch
because you cannot see it, is scarcely
iiiur« reasonable.
The rebound of this great intellectual
movement has, perhaps, already «oue
too far. We have become as fond of
mysteries as a priest of Thebes. We
believe all that our grandfathers be
lieved, and much that those venerable
men would have ridiculed. As childreu
around the dying tire, we must have our
tfliost storius before we sleep. Solemn
London editors gravely describe the
mysterious pictures that present them
selves in a ball of crystal to the eyes of
the editors' female friends. The editors
themselves cannot see these pictures,
but, of course, they exist. Nobody
would deny that. Thought transference
is an established fact. The young man
reflects uitrhtly upon the superexcel
ieuce of his fiancee, and he is sure that
Marie smiles responsive in her dreams.
The virtues of faith cure are self-evi
dent. Only beliova that the forceps are
made of sponge, and you will never
know when the tooth is cut.
But the greatest of these new beliefs
is hypnotism. Its growth bids tair to
divide the nation. From recent events
it would seem that some Democrats
have already disappeared, and soon
there will be no Republicans. The
"iniquitous doctrines" of the Hypnotiz
ers will be assailed ore long la the na
tioual platform of the Hypnotized.
Everywhere intrudes the hypnotic
"suggestion." We may think we paid
a delicate compliment to the rector, but
tii c wife of our bosom put it into our
head. Little Reginald was "thinkin' of
them Christmas presents rigbtalong."
But to th« criminal, the condemned of
man, comes the new doctrine as a
heavenly aid. The glories of iisanity
are past. It is not now conceded that
Mr. Brown, of i'psilanti, who killed his
neighbor Rogers, should be at once dis
charged because th« town records of
Boston recall the incarceration of an
ancestral Brown "forasmuch as lie was
distraught of his intellects."
The new method is much simpler,
much easier. The cashier robs a great
bank systematically for years. He was
perfectly honest himself, but was under
the control of another man, who got
most of the money. A scoundrel slays
an innocent woman through a hired as
sassin. The actual murderer had the
best intentions, but he cou'd not help
adopting the elaborate plan proposed by
the hypnotizing villain. The plan was
known to intelligent men, but they were
"hypnotized," and could no.t warn the
victim. Various girls elope with mar
ried men, but they are "model young
ladies" under hypnotic influence.
If all these things are true, anarchy is
already upon us. bins Sins and J oliet
are our proper universities. Matters,
however, might be exaggerated—by the
other newspapers. A late inquiry among
prominent local representatives of tho
medical and legal professions has been
most reassuring. The following com
munications exhibit the true nature of
hypnotism and its possible relations to
crime. The articles set forth the most
recent and approved views upon a dif
ficult and complicated subject, and ex
emplify the heights to which have risen
the sciences of Galen and Triboniau,
PROF. W. XAVIER SUDDUTH.
University of Minnesota.
In answer to your letter of inquiry re
garding the relation of hypnosis to
crime, would say that 1 no not consider
that there is any relation, and in proof
i>t my position cite the fact that hypno
tism is as old as man and has been
known as far back as Biblical record
goes- The Egyptians also were familiar
with it, and so have been all modern
nations; but in all this time, so far a3
my knowledge extends, there has not
been a single well-authenticated case
on the criminal records of any country
where hypnosis has been used to coiu
del any one to commit any crime, not a
single case where a pre viously virtuous
woman hns been led from the path of
virtue, nor any individual swindled out
of money by means of hypnotic sugges
tion, nor do I believe there ever will be.
Hypnosis is not a condition like ether
or chloroform narcosis, but a mental
state into which the individual volun
tarily enters. No one can be hypno
tised against his will, nor be kept in the
hypnotic state any longer than he is
willing to be. The Idea that many per
sons have that only weak-minded people
can be hypnotized is entirely false. The
best subjects I have ever had have been
this best educated and possessed of the
strongest wills. All that is necessary
for such people to do In order to become
subjects is to desire to &lt;\\i&gt;experience the
sensation and put themselves in a stale
of absolute passivity.
Idiots, insane people and skeptics can
not be hypnotized. In order to be a
good subject a person must first be will
ing—he must have will power sufficient
to will to do as he is told, and last, but
not least, be must possess faith in the
operator.
Mo one can bo hypnotized who do.-s
not know that he is going to be.
The process is purely one of suggestion.
There is no mysterious fluid that passes
from one individual to the other.
Neither is it a condition of paralysis,
in which the individual is unable
to resist the will of the operator.
The suggestion of acts to a person in the
hypnotic state that are contrary to his
ideas of right and wrong will always
meet with failure, and if the sugges
tion is persisted in will cause the indi
vidual to awaken. Constant repetition
may, as iv the waking state, educate
him iv the premises, but a person iv
the hypnotic state is less susceptible to
criminal suggestion than ho wuuhl be
in the waking condition, for th» reason
that in the hypnotic state nil sense of
material relations is set aside for tho'
time being. The personality of the in
dividual la not, however, materially al
tered, only Modified, partially domi
nated hy the will ol another for the time
being, but only in so far as his own
ideas of rieht and wrong are not seri
ously crossed. Any strong countor
cturent of ideas will break the relation
ship nnd arouse him from the. hypnotic
state.
Furthermore, there must be a condi
tion of absolute sympathy and confi
dence presented in order to secure' the
best results. Faith in the ability and'
good intentions of the operator is an 'es- 1
Mattel element in hypnotism. No sane
person would go to sleep with a burglar
under his bed if he knew it, neither
would he permit a rascal to hypnotize
him. The sensational stories that go the
rounds of cheap literature regarding
theft, arson and murder committed in
the hypnotic state, by reason of that
state, are the creations of diseased
minds. Unless a person is a thief or
murderer at heart, he can no more be
made one in the hypnotic than he can in
the waking state, in considering this
subject, however, it must b» remem
bered that there are people in the world
who are negatively virtuous and gener
ally well behaved—people who are good
simply because they have never been
tempted to be bad. Such persons,
tempted either in the waking or hyp
notic state, might or would fall
simply because they have no In
dwelling force of character. Such
people are only safe in a cloister or be
liir.a prison bars, and there, in my esti
mation, is where a considerable portion
of the inhabitants of a village in a
neighboring state should be placed. If
wo can believe the accounts in the
papers, an innocent man is being perse
cuted at the Instigation of two hysterical
girls who have the power of throwing
themselves into the trance state. The
days of Salem witchcraft are being en
acted over again. 1 have never seen
anything yet in my fifteen years' study
of the subject that has led me to believe
in telepathy, and I fully concur in the
opinion of Judge Bailey as to the ad
mission of •'hypnotically" secured testi
mony in court.
The basis of hypnotism is suggestion,
and this may be given in the waking as
well as the hypnotic state, and need not
be by word alone. Anything that stands
for an idea to the mind of the indi
vidual is sufficient to produce the
effect. Suggestions in the waking
state sometimes produce epidem
ics, as in the middle ages, when
men, women and children were carried
away by the miliion with the idea of
of rescuing the Holy city. Epidemics
of crime seem to spring up as the result
of some dastardly deed as the incentive.
"Lynching bees" follow each other in
rapid succession. Train robberies go
in groups, although widely separated
geographically. To sucii an extent do
these things occur that sometimes .it
seems as if people were ere atures «f im
pulse and suggestion rather than rea
soning beings.
The danger in hypnosis lies in its
abuse, and not in its use. Every power
has its good and its bad aspect, and so
has this one; but hypnosis offers its own
remedy. If, when abused,* hypnosis
may weaken the will,even as morphine,
ether, chloral and all other narcotics, rt
may also be used to strengthen the will
again, whereas'the other analgesics can
not. No one has ever diod from hyp
nosis used as an aosesthetic, while
hundreds have died under chloroform.
My prediction is that, when the atmos
phere has been cleared of supersti
tion, bigotry and professional jealousy,
hypnosis will come into general use as
an analgesic and anaesthetic To inhibit
or even limit the use of this potent
remedy for the relief of pain would be
an outrage upon the community. Far
better educate the people up to its right
use and point out the danger of its
abuse.
If it is to be controlled by legislation,
where will the line be drawn? Let me
cite a few places where it is now used.
A little child is playing with Its blocks
or dollies, aud the nurse enters to put
the little one into its crib for its regular
afternoon nap. The child does not feel
sleepy, but insists on being allowed to
finish the house he is building, but the
nurse persists, and by blandishment*
and promises ot sugar plums finally
succeeds in tretting the child into its
crib or into her lap, and then begins the
monotonous motion of rocking it to
sleep, meanwhile emphasizing the
suggestion by the low droning of the
lullaby song accompanied by the com
maud: "Go to sleep, darling—go to
sieep sleep sleep"—and the child
"iocs" to sleep—hypnotized.
Again, a child at its play In
some way hurts its finger, and
runs to mamma, crying: the moth
er soothes away the pain by ca
resses and diversion of the attention,
and in all probability, if injury is con
siderable, ending by rocking and sing
intr it to sleep while the tears yet glis
ten between its closed lids.
In yonder darkened chamber lies a
person suffering from that terribly
painful affliction —"a sick head
ache"—the slightest jar giving ex
cruciating agony, such as is to be
appreciated only by one who has
had it. A friend, hearing of the case,
comes in, and by gently stroking the
fevered brow soon quiets the throbbing
pulse and puts the sufferer to aleep, to
awake entirely free from pain.
A person suffuringifrom an acute neu
ralgia, caused an by exposed pulp in a de
cayed tooth, calls upon me at my house in
the evening. I apply some simple house
hold remedy, and, by a tew gentle but
firm passes over the face in the painful
region, suggest freedom from pain, and
send the sufferer home to pass a com
fortable night in sleep, instead of walk
ing the floor, as many a person has done.
A prominent man, whose voice, no
doubt, will be heard in the halls ot our
legislature the coming winter on this
subject, if it comes up, recently went
to a "painless joint" and had twoachiiur
teeth removed with odontuader, or
something of a like nature, and after
wards suffered intense neuralgia. He
Bought me at my home just at dinner
time. 1 applied topical remedies, but
failed to relieve him. I finally suggested
hypnosis, and, placing him upon a
lounge in my study, soon had him
asleep, and left him to rest until 1 could
tret my dinner. On returning I found
him awake, the pain having oeen
stronger than my au^estiou to sleep
I again hypnotized him, and remained
with him, finally securing immunity
from the neuralgia, and sent him home
to a quiet night's rest, a firm believer
hi the efficacy of hypnosis as an anal*
gesic.
A lady came to the late clinic at
the university with a tumor of long
standing, the removal of which had
been a constant dread, undermining
her health and inducing morbid nerv
ous symptom*. The tumor was
successfully removed under hyp
nosis, and the patient subsequently
treated for her nervousness.with marked
improvement and promise of final cure
A woman stiffenmk from a known
heart lesion, who had permitted her
teeth to decay to the jjum line tHjcauso
an anesthetic had been inteudicted by
hei family physician, presented for
treatment. She proved a Kd subject,
and had a lance number of badly dis~
eased teeth and roots removed under
hypnosis, waking up vvitli a smile on
her face, having been perfectly obliv
ious to auy paiu, and remained free
from any subsequent bad effects of neu
ralgia or shock.
A man suffering from hysterio-er>i
lepsy of several years' standing
presented for treatment. {Suppur
ation of the antrum and frontal
sinuses was diagnosed, and, as these
cases coutraindicate the ordinary an
aesthetics, hypnosis wan used in the
presence of several physicians with
absolute success and tubes placed in the
several sinuses. The operation was
followed np by the use of suggestion in
the treatment of the epileptic attacks,
and, although the case is still under
treatment, every indication points to a
cuie. The epileptic seizures are
under full control, and all internal
Medication has been dropped these
many days.
A woman in the fifth month of a
"vomiting pregnancy," with other
serious complications, wasted to a
shadow, and only existing on three
quarters ot a grain of morphine
daily, administered hypodermatically,
was put under hypnotic control, and
the morphine stopped at the second
sitting. At the third site was taught to
hypnotize herself. The vomiting was
treated L*y suggestion, as well as some
other annoying complications, and the
patient remains to this day, nearly one
month since the first treatment, free
from the use of morphine, a"iid doing as
well as .could be expected of one iv her
condition.
A large number of stammerers have
also come under my treatment, with
varying decrees of success; none,
however, witnout improvement, and
several have been dismissed as
cured. In the licht ot tlie above expe
rience, of which the cases cited are only
examples, is it strange that I should be
a firm believer in hypnosis as an anal
tesie and an aim-schetic in the treat
ment of neuralgia? The following
clippiug from the New York Evening
Post very clearly sets forth the present
status of hypnosis in its relation to med
icine:
The extent to which therapeutic experi
ments in hypnotic suggestion are exciting
the attention of physicians and awakening
the interest of the general public may be in
ferred from the fact that during: the past
year more than 100 books and brochures,
especially devoted to the discussion of this
subject, have been published. One of the
most valuable of these is the small volume
just issued by Bong, in Berlin, entitled "Die
Bedeutuug der Uynotischen Suggestion als
Ileilmittel." The author. Dr. J. Grossman,
editor of the Zeitschrift fur Hypotismus,
prints communications from thirty of the
most eminent professors and physicians ot
Europe, firing the results of their experi
ence in the application of hypnotic sugges
tions to the healing of disease. Thus Van
.'edeu and Van Reuterghem. of Amsterdam,
report that from May 5,1557, to June 30, 1893,
in the institution under their charge, 1.098
patients were subjected to the treatment;
of those £8.28 percent were entirely cured.
2&amp;
6!) per cent permanently improved, 21.02
per cent slightly bettered, 17.81 per cent
unaffected, and in U.lB per cent of the
cases the results were unknown. Dr.
Wetterstrand, of Stockholm, has used this
method of medical treatment in 7,000, and
Dr. Bornneim, of Nancy, in 12,000 cases, and
both express themselves strongly in favor of
it. Indeed, Dr. Bernheim does not hesitate
to declare that the study of Hypnotic sugges
tion should be made obligatory in all medical
school?, and that nowadays a physician who
ignores the psychical element in disease, and
has no knowledge of the part it plays in
palhogeny and therapeutics, is no better
than a horse doctor, and should confine him
self to veterinary practice. Another impor
tant point brought out by Dr. Kraltt-Ebing,
of Vienna, is the influence of "a utosugges
tion" in the production of disease. The
number of ailments and morbid conditions
of this) kind, that have their origin in the
nervous system, and are indicated by pains,
paralysis and other symptoms of hysterical,
hypochondriac and neurasthenic affections,
is astonishing. Although not merely i mag
inary complaints, they cease with the re
moval of the "autosuargestive cause," which
may be effected by any change of scene ban
ishing it from the thoughts, or by heterosug
gestion (fremd-suggestlon) on the part of a
physician, who may impart it verbally or in
the disguise of a dose of medicine. In obsti
nate cases, in which the autosuggestion is
firmly entrenched in mental imbecility, su
perstituiion, morbid appetites and passions,
inveterate habits, or abnormities of charac
ter, recourse must be had to hypnotism. That
the great majority of mankind are capable of
being hypnotized is shown by the experi
ments of Dr. Freihorr yon Schrank Noizing,
of Munich, on 5.705 persons of different na
tionalities, of whom only per cent proved
to be entirely unsusceptible."
The following paragraph is taken
from a letter of mine published in the
Minneapolis Journal:
"I have observed from a perusal of the
literature on the- sub ject that nearly al! the
work done so far has been in the direction
of investigating its value as a therapeutic
agent, rather than as au an a-sthetie. Tiie
special line of work that I have been and am
still engaged upon is its application to sur
gery, upon which little or nothing has been
written. The value of hypnosis as an anal
gesic in neuralgia has long been known.
That I entered uuon the work with consid
erable trepidation is shown by the fact that,
although I have been a close student of the
subject formauy years past, aud have uieJ it
in my private practice, yet I bad never given
a public demonstration until last year. I
cannot do belter in closing this letter than to
quote the opening paragraph of the first
paper I ever wrote upon the subject: "The
liae of detnarkaiiou between the sublime aud
the ridiculous, between the mysterious ana
the miraculous, Between belief and iucredu
l.ty, between respect and diversion in this life,
is so narrow that to espouse auy causa that
is not woll understood, or in at verges on tne
occult, is really dangerous to oue's reputa
tion; and la treating of hypnosis I should be
vain Indeed did did I expect to escape the
lot of others who have iv the past essayed
the role of interpreters of ibis ruueh-abused,
but Httle understood, science.' 1 The clinic
at the -U." while ruuulng. daily demon
strated its value as au amesthetic. It was
fitting that a dental clinic stiould bo the first
10 take the lead in the maUor, us dentistry
has always b'en in the front rank iv ex peri
meiu with aiuesthetics, and with excellent
results.' 1
I As to who can use hypnosis there is
no limit. All are more or less suscepti
ble to its influence. All that the hyp
notizer can do is to direct the course to
be pursued,and the result depends upon
the Individual. I have taught a great
many persons to hypnotize themselves,
to their great benefit. When it is fully
understood that it is a mental state and
not a physical condition, ana that no
one can bo hypnotized against his will,
then tho dread that some good pcoDle
have of it will cease, and hypnotic sug
gestion will come to occupy th place it
deservedly should among household
remedies.
_
Call and see what George Refer, Ml
Wubasha street, has to offer in Pure
Wines for the holidays.
HON. C. D. O'BRIEN.
As to whether the law recognizes an
alleged hypnotic influence, under which
a crime was committed, as being a de
fense fur the party charged with the
commission of such crime, 1 will say
that, so far as the existence of the con
dition called hypnotism is concerned, or
whether it exists as a condition or as a
fact. lam unable to state. From what
is said about it ami written about it, it
aDpears that some people have the fac
ulty of producing on others an influ
ence called hysterical or hypnotic, un
der which the subject apparently ap
pears to have abandoned all self-power
and self-consciousness, and to be en
tirely under the domination of the op
erator.
But so far the law has nol, recognized
the existence of any such condition;
that is, it has not been satisfactorily
proven ift any court of justice, to my
knowledge, that either tbe operator
possesses the alleged power, or that the
subject can be entirely subordinated to
the will of the operator to the extent
that it is claimed that he can—that is, so
as to produce an abnormal condition in
which the individuality of the subject is
completely wiped out, and he or she be
comes the more instrument of the de
sires or wishes of the operator.
Now, I say the law does not recognize
the existence of that condition; there
fore, up to this time, there is, so far as 1
know, no adjudicated case which holds
that a defense based upon a theory that
a criminal act was committed by one
because of and while under the power
of hypnotic influence can be sustained.
I very much doubt whether such a de
fense ever will b« sustained, because I
do not tluiik the law will ever recogniz
a hypnotic condition as a defense to a
criminal act committed by one who
claims to be in that state when so
committing the crime. Neither would
the law recognize, without a direct
statutory enactment in that behalf, a
criminal act committed by the operator
in the hypnotic suggestion. In other
words, to make it plain, if it should be
claimed that the operator hypnotized
the subject, and then, while the subject
was under the influence, suggested to
the subject the commission of a crime,
which such person so under the influence
should then proceed to commit, the legal
consequences would be, very likely, that
both of them would be indicted for the
crime and both Dunislied as principal
and accessory both before and after the
fact.
You now ask me whether the hypno
tizing of a person against his will,
winch results in the mental or physical
injury of the person so hypnotized,
would be considered in law a crime.
Under the penal code of this state there
is no provision that will reach such a
e.ise that lam aware of. As this state
has abolished common law jurisdiction
for crimes, and nothing is a crime unless
so specifically designated iv the statutes
(and we have no statute upon the sub
ject of hypnotism or occult Influence),
there could be no charge predicated upon
the hypnotizing of an individual, pro
vided the subject consented to the ex
periment; but if it should be proved iv
court that such a thing as hypnotic in
fluence existed, and that a person was
hypnotized against his will, thereby
producing a physical injury to him, 1
should think that certainly, under the
common law jurisdiction, and, perhaps,
under our penal code, a prosecution for
assault might be maintained, for it has
been held that the administration of
anesthetics to a patient against his will
do's constitute an assault.
Speaking generally of the subject, the
most remarkable thing connected with
the so-called hypnotic manifestations is
the resemblance which they bear to the
old theories of witchcraft, both in Eu
rope and iv this country.
The alleged case of hypnotism re
cently occurring in Eau Claire, and the
manifestations of the hypnotic subjects,
as reported in the Globs on last Sun
day, are remarkably similar to the man
ifestations of witchcraft delusion as we
read them, both in the histories of Eu
rope and of New England. The state
ments of the two girls in Eau Claire
concerning the Influence of J)r. Pickin,
and the hysterical or cataleptic con
dition which they ascribe to his in
fluence, are almost precisely the same
as the manifestations of witchcraft aud
the charges made against those unfor
tunate people that are alleged to have
practiced the art In New England dur
ii.sr the early history of the country.
When you add to this the sympathetic
symptoms between the two s-irls, you
have, if you choose to call it so, a case of
witchcraft or possession produced by
witchcraft, or absolutely similar symp
toms; and it is a very remarkable thing
that in tiie year 18U4, at what we consider
the acme of our development in civili
zation, progress and culture, we should
find ourselves confronted with a condi
tion, or popular delusion, which has
heretofore been entirely ascribed to the
ignorance and superstition of former
ages.
You ask me if a confession or testi
mony obtained under hypnotic Influence
could be used in a court of law, or would
the procuring of a confession under surh
circumstances be a violation of personal
right. The entire value of a confession
rests upon the eireumstamces under
which it is obtained. It must be volun
tary, and not induced by undue influence
of any kind. The mind of the party
confessing must not be overcome Liy any
influence such as threats, or hope of re
ward or of escaping punishment. It
therefore follows that a confession
obtained from a person who, it
is conceded, was at the time unable to
contiol his own faculties, would be
worthless, nor would a person under
what is called hypnotic influence be
permitted to testify in a court of com
mon law while in that condition, if such
condition were known to the court. 11 a
person BeSerinf under temporary or
permanent aberration of mind is dis
qualified as a witness, so would a per
son be who waa under the influence
either of narcotics or intoxicants to such
an extent as to atlect his judgment. If
you once assume that a person can be
placed under hypnotic influence and the
law should recognize it, it would cer
tainly disqualify that person from testi
fying while in that condition.
HON. CHARLES E. FLANDRAU.
On the subject of hypnotism 1 know
nothing, and do not suppose any one
knows any more than I do, therefore 1
will say nothing about it.
As to whether the plea of having been
under hypnotic influence at tho time of
the commission of a crime would be re
ceived by a court as a defense, all I can
say is to Quote a very familiar principle
in criminal law, winch is that intention
is Mm gist of oil crime. No ohm can be
guilty of a crime unless lie perpetrated
it knowingly. Responsibility for ciime
depends wholly upon intention.
A familiar instance of this principle i
is the. plea of insanity, if the party is
insane when the act is committed, he is
not himself, is not impelled b\ his own i
reason, but by some delusion thai clouds
bn mind and destroys his will. .So he j
is not held responsible for his act.
If any one person possesses the power
of absolutely controlling the actions of
another (which [seriously doubt, unless
such other is so mentally diseased as to
be generally irresponsible), and should
by such influence and power impel such
person to commit a crime. tii«?n, of
course, the one exerting the influence
would be the criminal, and not the party
performing the involuntary act. This
is on the principle that he acted without
intention on hi* part, but by an irre
sistible impulse exerted by another.
Whether courts will accept any ex
pert evidence on a matter of this kind.
1, of course, am unable to say; but. in
the light of experience, science and
common sense, I think they should be
very careful In listening to anything of
the kind.
Charles E. Flasdkau.
DR. W. E. HALLOWELL.
A great deal of nonsense has been
printed in the daily press lately about
hypnotism, «nd people generally seem
willing to set hardly any limit to the
powers of the dreadful individuals who
"influence," in accordance with their
own sweet will, any and everybody with
whom they come into contact, and be
fore whom neither virtue, life nor prop
erty is supposed to be safe. If one may
judge by the tone of the press in the
:.ews and editorial eolutnus,an epidemic
of hypnotic crime is threatening the in-</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1896-08-22/ed-1/?sp=19&amp;
q=Hypnosis+HYPNOSIS+hypnosis+hypnot+hypnotic+Hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotized+hypnotizer/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HYPNOSIS MACHINES
Devices to Produce the M umrne
8tate Mechanicaly.
"Ill' ERB AD CM lTtm
Influence of Certain Chemicals
Upon Sensitive Subjects.
USES OF THE POWER
VEN HYPNOSIS
may now be pro
duced by machinery.
We are approaching
a day when the di
rect influence of
Svengalles will not
be necessary to
throw Trilbies Into
subjective at ate a.
when hypnotists will
exert their powers
through machinery
set to operate at
given times, the
presence of the Instruments being un
known to the subjects. The mechanical
mesmerizer will then find an essential
place In the burglar's tool kit, and we will
have to look under our beds to see If such
traps have been set by our enemies. The
mechanical hypnotizer as now made, how
ever, is strictly a scientific instrument.
The government's bureau of education re
cently purchased a collection of such appar
atus, which are new In this country. They
will be used by a specialist for studying
the values of hypnotic suggestion in the
education of the abnormal classes. Ex
periments will be made determining their
effect upon the sensibilities, emotions,
breathing,. circulation and temperature of
the body'.
An Elaborate Apparatus.
The most elaborate form of hypnotiser
is a small box, containing clock work, sur
mounted by two horizontal oblong fans,
one over the other, revolving rapidly In op
posite directions. The fans are studded
on each side with a row of circular mir
rors, about the size of nickel pieces. The
rapid rotation produces an odd flashing
effect which greatly fatigues the eyelid
muscles of the beholder. This machine is
found to be very effective when used upon
sersitives who can be thrown into a hyp
notic sleep by concentration or sight stimu
lus.
A simpler form of mechanical hypnotizer
is a belt of broad tape to be placed upon
the forehead and over the temples, being
tied at the back of the head. From a me
tallic plate In front protrudes a wire, ex
terding upward In an S-like curve and
holding a bright ball of nickel, about the
size of a marble, at the end. When this is
placed upon the st'bject the wire Is bent
until the ball reaches a point above the
eye, where it may be seen by the wearer
only by intensely straining the eyelids.
The same effect, as produced by the former
rr achine is accomplished by this simpler ap
paratus. These instruments have been
Irvented to serve in substitution for the
gestures, known as passes, commonly ma
by hypnotists. The scientific hypnotist
makes movements before and above tho
eyes of his subject to concentrate his at
tention and to fatigue the eyelid muscles
both by causing the eyes to follow the
movements and by fannirig air against
them. Fatigue of the muscles of the eye
lids is found to he one of the direct causes
of sleep. Persons in no mental need of sleep
may "read themselves sleepy" under a too
bright or a too (im light. A severe breeze
against the eyelids will cause the same
effect.
Magnetic Influentea.
Another form of hypnotizer, in this col
lection, is a large horshoe magnet with an
attached armature. It is given to a sensi
tive who is told to continuously separate
and fit together the two parts. A similar
magnetic hypnotizer is a steel ring to fit
the index finger. The ring is of magnetized
steel and is broken at one place, the space
being filled by a small steel armature.
These two contrivances are used princi
pally for humoring the more unsophisti
cated and superstitious sensitives who fos
ter the belief that hypnotism is supernat
ural. The magnet in most cases suggests
mystery to the ignorant and sensitives of
that class are readily excited by it. The
ring device, also called a hypnoscope, Is
used by some hypnotists for determining
sensitives. Hypnotizable persons are al
leged to experience certain tinglings in the
skin and twitchings of the muscles while
wearing it. A more complicated instru
ment in this collection, which may be used
as a hypnoscope, is a bulb-shaped rod, re
sembling an electrode, which may be
made to create pressure against the
palm of the hand by a spring inside. When
the pressure Is applied the subject is asked
if he feels an electric shock. If he so con
fesses he is rated as a hynotic sensitive.
Sometimes the whole frame will tremble
as a result of this imaginary electrical
fluid.
Crystal Viaions.
Equally interesting devices of a related
class, now growing in vogue among certain
experimental hypnotists, are for applica
tion to sensitives for the purpose of caus
ing hallucinations known as crystal visions.
One instrument of this class is a ball of
crystal mounted upon a handle. Mirrors
and other polished or transparent surfaces
are employed for the same effect. The
crystal or reflecting medium by producing
partly obscured or scattered reflections to
the sensitive mind's eye aid the subje-t
in perceiving unnatural mental embodi
ments of various objects. Many abnormal
persons, habitually haunted by phantasms,
for which visions they develop appetites,
so to speak, employ these crystals and re
flectors for throwing themselves into states
during which they may experience what Is
alleged to be the actual or imagined "sixth
sense" or "second sight." Crystal gazing
has lately become so popular that many
psychic experimentalists in Europe are in
viting tests with the paraphernalia thus
employed, and agents were some time
since engaged by the Society for Psychical
Research to furnish balls for the purpose.
Prof. Win. Romaine Newbold of the Uni
versity 'of Pennsylvania recently made an
extensive Investigation of crystal vision
and found that twenty-two subjects out of
eighty-six could perceive illusions by gaz
ing into mirrors, surfaces of water- and
objects of glass varying in form. Phan
tasms appeared to the sensitives usually
within five minutes, being prec~ed direct
ly by cloudiness, hazes of color or illumin
ations before the eyes. The phantasms
varied from dim outlines to brilliant col
ored pictures. Like dreams some of these
forms were based upon recent experiences
of the subjects, while others were purely
fantastic.
An Experiment.
A simple experiment in thi\ line may be
tried at home by any one who *11 sit before
an open window, at twilight, keeping his
gaze fixed preferably upon some landscape,
distant row of houses or collection of con
spicuous clouds. If the temptation to wink
the eyelids can be resisted until the eyes
become greatly fatigued, so as to remain
open only at a great strain, the natural
images will gradually grow more and more
indistinct, and will apparently arrange
themselves into fantastic groups or fade in
to rapidly changing forms. The abnormal
imagination of a person subject to Uight
hallucinations would readily discern weird
phantoms in such a picture.
Drugs, such as urethane, suiphonal, peaa
dehyde, etc., are now used successfully to
produce a sleep which to all appearances is
hypnotic. Some foreign hypnotists use
ether and chloroform to induce hypnosis.
Recent experiments indicate that there is
a great similarity between hypnosis and theI
action of hasheesh,as well as the newly test
ed mescal, which is used by certain of our
western Indians to produce trances. Phe
nomena very similar to hypnosis is now
noticed also during the ordinary sleep pro
duced by simple anaesthetics, and the ques
tion is being asked, Do anaesthetics produce
hypnosis? A member of the Royal Chemi
cal Society of London recently demonstrated
that man possesses two distinct conscious
nesses. He says that persons under the in
fluence of anaesthetics. while not conscious
of what is happening at the time of the
operation, are sometimes able, several days
after, to describe in detail what was hap
pnnto e them. Wrhat he.n call t.."o
Best Natural A
25 Years' S.5
Highest Reputation
CAUTION: None genuine
of the
"Andreas E
On the
aday consciousnE as" was absent at the time.
but the "subliminal consciousness." he says.
was present during the operation. Hence
anaesthetics destroy the former and only
postpone the enregistering of the sensation
conductors controlling the latter conscious
ness. It may be that this "subliminal con
sciousness" is the one affected by hypnot
ists.
Senlttve to Drmss.
Recent laboratory experiments have also
been made to ascertain the effects of drugs
upon persons in a hypnotic state. Some
subjects are found to be so sensitive to
drugs while in this condition that they con
tort themselves in various ways when the
substances are not applied directly, but
merely held in proximity to their skin, not
even touching it. Some chemical substanc+-s,
even when sealed in tubes, will cause sen
sitives to alter their bodily appearances and
physical conditions, producing violent con
vulsions, hallucinations, alterations of the
pupils, changes In the pulse-beats, symp
toms of joy, grief or anger and other emo
tional conditions.
The influence of color upon hypnotized
persons has also been tested in the labo
ratcry by subjecting sensitives to rays of
light passing through various screens of
different colored glass. Blue light is found
to produce sadness, red light joy, yellow
light strong sffection and violet or green
light variable conditions. Charcot used a
sudden ray of Intense light as one means
or throwing sensitives into the hypnotic
state.
Just as these instruments for producing
hypnosis are applied to the sense of sight,
other physical methods are applied, in its
induction, to the senses of hearing and
touch. The condition does not seem to be
induced by stimulations of either taste smell. Charcot threw some of his subjects
into hypnotic states by the sharp and
sudden sounding of a large gong. The
ticking of a watch has been used with
the same success by others, the sensitive
being required to concentrate his mind
upon the sound. just as he does upon the
seeing of the revolving fans or nickel ball.
The monotonous chants sung by semi
civilized nations are found to produce the
same effect.
Strokes and Passes.
For creating hypnosis through the sense
of touch, strokings or pressure upon the
skin are resorted to by some hypnotists,
while others apply warm plates of metal
to different parts of the body. Physicians
realize that warmth induces natural sleep,
while coldness tends to prevent it. Some
foreign hypnotists maintain that the crown
of the head, roof of the nose, the thumb
or elbow are most sensitive to hypnotic
stimulation by touch. Some merely
s'ratch the skin of the neck or touch the
forehead. The electric battery has been
resorted to by a few experimenters, who
claim that it is successful. as an inducing
agent. It is said to cause the same imag
inary effect as the magnet.
It is now an easy matter for certain hyp
niotists to transform natural sleep into
hypnotic sleep without the subject's knowl
edge. Thus one .who gces to sleep in a
public place may never remember what
foolish actions he has been made to do
Ouring that period. Hypnotic suggestion is
the latest phase of this whole subject which
is now interesting experimenters. A sensi
tive, under hypnotic influence, receives a
command fram the hypnotist which he
will obey on awakening, altough he is un
(onsciou of ever having received such a
(ommand. This power is used by a physi
cian in Massachusetts, who is said to be
able to stop the most severe pain by sug
gestion. Several people report to the Soci
ety for Psychical Research that he has
given thcm suggestions before they have
gone to the dentist, %ith the result that
their dentstry has invariably been painless,
kxperiments are now being made as to the
valu. of hypnotic suggestion in education.
Its medical value has already neen proven
in France. where such conditions as ner
vous insomnia, sonambulism, kleptomania,
ilziness and varicus forms of moral degen
eracy have been cured by its means.
Ues of Hypnosis.
The power of suggestic n as an agent in
crime is now being talked about in this
country. Men are believed to have been
banged for committing murder while acting
under hypnotic Influence from another.
Some celebrated medico-legalists have pro
posed that laws should be passed defining
the responsible murderers in such cases.
In such an event hypnotism will be as both
ersome a plea of defense as insanity is to
day. The dangers threatened by the vicious
or careless hypnotist have become legally
realized In France and Russia. In the
former hypnotism is forbidden for purposes
of public amusement, and in the latter no
persons except, licensed physicians can
practice It It is said that tilt per cent of
ithe people In thne world are hypnotizable.
The hypnotists, on the other hand, are dis
covering and improving their powers faster
and faster each day. Will they at some
future century become the governing class
If a door is hung
to swnmy one way,
I there s no use
trying to push it
the other w ay.
.1 There is a right
and a wrong way
to do things.
Many thousands
of women in
and would like to
be well. T he y
aremaking efforts
to get well, hut
they are making them in the wrong way.
They are taking medicines prepared by in
competent nurses, or inexperienced physi
cians. They ar alubmitting to exam
inations and local treatment, for which thesem
Is generally no necessity. They are grow
ngsteadily worse instead of steadily better.
Tere is no reason why almost every wo
man should not be well and strong. Over
thirty years ago, Dr. R. V. Pierce, of Buf
falo, an eminent and successful specialist in
the treatment of the diseases of women,
discovered a wonderful specific for woman's
diseases las since become world
mous as .r Pirce's Favorite Prescription,
It cures all forms of female weakness ad
disease, Its effect is immediately ecpi
ble in the better feeling of the palnit
forces ont impuiy soothes e infianema
tion that is always present in disorders of
this kind, promotes regularity, and stops
debilitating drains on the system. It cures
nevuness, ritailty 19epe.mesa*, lac
CREAT FiEDICAL. BOOK FREE.
Every' womaan should have a coyof Dusder
Pierce's Comamou Sense Medical Adviser. R ts
a handosey illustrated wolusa
of womnen. It is writtn a
thre hnrd illsttissu
colored plates. Untif recently,
it was aoid at a dollar and a
hafa ,and at tis price,
of sia hundred and eighty thu
sand copies. Rt Is now oareed,
mlerba~d. bssistey fwa to any woman who
to cove the o mail o Westd'
dhbnding if ihdn is, a each
thty ai in aleLm
!orld's
perient Water.
cess in U. S.
.A Over the Worm.
without the signature
firm
axlehner,
Label.
es of the earth, and will the great host of
sensitives become their slaves? Perhaps
that is somewhat the case now. Trust
worthy authorities relate hypnotism with
the same power by which the teacher Im
Presses his students, the preacher converts
his congregation, the pleader convinces the
jury, the cross-examiner "rattles" the wit
new. or by which the orator holds his audi
ence with bated breath. receiving cheers at
every nod. although heard and understood
by few. According to this. Mr. Bryan is a
hypnottst. and doubtless Mr. McKinley is
one. JOHN ELFRETH WATKINS. Jr.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-09-06/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;
q=hypnotic+Hypnotic+HYPNOTISM+Hypnotism+hypnotism+science/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HYPNOTISM IN A VERY PAINFUL DENTAL OPERATION
Bvj a J4ere WaVe of tke jiarxd Ir\ter\se
Suffering Was pVeVerxted
In the rooms of the Stomatological Club,
at Post and Stockton streets, on Tuesday
afternoon last, a clinic was held in the
presence of nearly all the members, in i
which hypnotism was introduced as a sub
stitute for anesthesia.
It was an experiment and the experi
ment was successful in the highest degree,
insomuch that it is safe to say that it
fixes the date of a subsidence of old and
the beginning of entirely new methods in
the operating-rooms of San Francisco
dentists.
Hypnotism is not a new thing in dentis
try any more than it is in therapeutics. It
has just landed in San Francisco, how
ever preceded, to be sure, by tales of
great successes in Paris, Berlin, London
and New York. That San Francisco
dentists are fully alive to the progress that
has been making in their science and
eager to keep the best pace that is being
made in the world was made evident by
the number in attendance and the inter
est manifested in the clinic
The demonstration was arranged by Dr.
M. W. Levkowicz. His subject was a boy
of 17, Alfred Boulton, a native of Victoria,
B. C, but who has returned but a few
weeks from a residence of some years in
Honolulu. He was an admirable subject
for a test of the possibilities of applied
hypnotism, in that he was a bright-eyed,
intelligent lad of nervous temperament,
and in that he had a couple of very sore
teeth.
J. B. Earley, a teacher of hypnotism,
was present to make the magic passes and
show the congregated doctors how easily
it might be done. The clinic began
shortly after 4 o'clock, the subject or pa
tient being placed in the red-plush chair,
so full of terrors to the tooth-aching con
tingent, and all of which tenors were to
be driven away by the wave of a hand.
But tne thing was an experiment, and
the terrors have been long intrenched in
tnat red-plush chair. Tney laughed at
this mild attempt to dislodge them— at
first they did.
The chair was placed in a wide bay-win
dow that extends out from an upper floor
immediately at the corner— the southeast
corner of Post and Stockton streets. There
was plenty of light and platform steps sur
rounded the chair, and on these the mem
bers of tie society were gathered, full of
interest. The boy took his place and Pro
fe^-sor Earley told him to close his ejea.
He did so. ''You cannot open them,"
said the professor, and he could not.
"Open them," said the professor, and be
did "Piace your hand! together— there;
you cannot take them apart," and he
could not.
"Now when I count ten you will be
sound asleep and your sense ol feeling
will have entirely left you, bo that you
wili feel no »aia."
The professor counted ten slowly and
deliberately. The boy waited a moment
and then opened bis eyes, quite es wide
awake as before. The professor smiled re
assuringly and placing his hands upon
the boy's head, with his thumbs at the
bridge of the nose, repeated his statement
in quiet confidence. Still the boy looked
up with wide-awake eyes. The terror of
the red cliair was upon him.
Two or three times the charm was tried
again, but it would not work. The doctors
watched and waited patiently enough, but
their comments and discussions, however
quiet, were distracting. The professor
saw his influence slipping away. He took
the boy out of the red chair and led him
to a rocter in the corner, as unlike the red
cbair as possible.
Still the boy's eyes H
would open. It be-
gan to look like a ,fl
I hopeless case. The J
I doctors broke up in jl
j knots and talked of
I other things.
Finally it was SU2- I
gested that the pro- I
fessor lake the sub- I
ject into a room I
I apart and to them- I
selves. He did so and I
the doctors waited I
waited quite a little I
j while. Then the sep- I
arating door opened I
and the doctor en- I
tered, leading the I
boy, his eyes fast H
shut, impossible for I
him to open them, I
but still not asleep. I
He was led to the I
chair, and the profes- I
sor told the doctors I
to go ahead.
"This boy is not I
asleep," said the pro- I
fessor. 'He is in a I
semi-conscious state, I
but he has nofeelin.-. I
You can work witli I
him with perfect free- I
dom." He spoke to I
the boy. "Now. my I
boy, you will feel no I
pain whatever. Do I
not think of the den- I
tist; think of me; no I
harm will come to I
I you; you need have I
Ino fear; lie there I
quietly and dream I
pleasant dreams."
Dr. Levkowicz be- I
gan to work with no I
more ado. The boy I
responded to his in- I
structions, opening I
his mouth wide and I
holding it as desired. I
He had what the den- I
tists call a "fungoid I
growm 01 me pulp
of a back molar. rffi^^s^^^^^^he
"nerve," as it is popularly called, was ex
posed and had filled up the large cavity of
a decayed tooth.
As explained afterward by the doctor
"This is a most sensitive and painful con
dition. To touch such a tooth under or
dinary conditions will cause great pain,
and dentists do not attempt to work with
such a tooth until after two or three days,
and then with iodine and arsenic The
THE SAN FRANCISCO CALL, SUNDAY, SEPTEMBER 6, 1896.
THE LAST BOAT
pulp bleeds prof us°ly upon tne slightest
touch. Now, I wished to demonstrate
that with the patient under the influence
of hypnotism this painful and distressing
growth could be removed quickly and
without pain."
The doctor began digging into the sensi
tive tooth with his cold steel instruments
with speedy and certain touch. In fifteen
minutes the growth had been wholly re-
Scene at the Clinic in the Rooms of the. Stomatological Club When the Hypnotic Experiment Was Made
moved and the cavity made clean for a
fiiling. And during those fifteen minuted
the boy lay in the chair apparently as
comfortable as though he were enjoying
a siesta in a hammock. The professor
had said at the beginning that there
j would be a minimum of blood flow from
i the operation. The doctor took up what
little there was in the customary way with
I small pellets of absorbent cotton in the
I tooth. One of the doctors remarked that
there seemed to be a good deal of saliva
in the mouth. "I will stop it," said the
professor, and he did so by merely speak
in^ the word.
When it was finished and the doctors
had examined and approved and mar
veled at the demonstration, the boy said,
"I would like to open my eyes."
"Oh, certainly," said the professor, "you
may open your eyes, but you will still re
main without pain without being sus
ceptible to pain."
The boy opened his eyes— as clear and
as intelligent as when he had closed them.
Then Doctor Frank 8. Pague stepped up
with a pair of forceps and from the other
side of the afflicted mouth he pulled a
tooth. It was well planted and resisted
at first and broke off. The doctor took
another hold, pushed the forceps down
hard upon the fragment remaining,
twisted it in tbe fetching way that dentists
have, until it yielded and came out. It
was then discovered to have an ulcerated
root.
"That should hurt you, boy."
"Should it?" he answered.
"Didn't you feel it?"
"Oh, yes; I felt you were pulling my
tooth, but it did not hurt."
"Such a tooth ordinarily is very painful
in being drawn," explained the doctor.
J\ Remarkable Derr\or\stratior\ of tke
JMystericxis Sciervce
"For fifteen minutes, and sometimes an
hour, alter pulling an ulcerated tooth the
patient usually suffers greatly. It is cer
tainly a convincing demonstration of the
great beneficence of hypnotism in den
tistry that this patient did not. Further
more, I felt his pulse when he took a seat
in the chair under the hypnotic influence
and it was beating wildly. During the
progress of this ordinarily painful opera-
tion it quieted down until it became en
tirely normaL"
But this was not the end of the demon
stration. The operation for the day being
finished, the boy said, "1 would like
to be released now; I want my sense of
feeling."
"Certainly," said the professor, "I will
give you that again." But to show the
doctors that the subject's entire body was
without feeling he ran a needle through
the flesh of the arm and drew it away
without any blood following.
"Now," he said, "you have your sense
of feeling all except in your teeth ttat
have been operated upon. Tney will re
main painless until the operation is over
and they have healed up. You are to go
up to Dr. Levkowicz' office to-morrow
morning at 10 o'clock and this tooth will
be filled. It will give you no pain what-
ever remember
I that. Now you have
sense of feeling
Hagain except as 1
Hhave said."
The clinic being at
Han end a general dis-
Heussion of the mys-
Htery of hypnotism
Hran on for some time.
I"I will show you,"
Hsaid Professor Earley,
H"the difference in the
Hamenability of the
I patient to the influ-
Hence, now that the
Hfear of the dental op-
Herat ion is removed.
HaII the surroundings
I were beiore alarming
H and distracting.
H>'ow, my boy," said
I the professor, ad-
H dressing young 80l-
Hton, "take that chair
I over there in the cor-
I ncr as far from me
las you can get. Sit
Hdown. That's right.
Bw'hen I count ten
Hyou will be sound
I asleep." The profes-
I sor coanted ten and
I the boy was I asleep. He was put
Ito convincing tests
I that it was so.
B "Now," said the
Hproiessor, "when you
Ha wake and have
Hialked with these gen-
Htienien in your nor-
Hmal condition you
Hwill fall asleep again
Himmediately upon
Hseein? me draw my
H watch from my pock-
Het. "Then the pro-
Hfessor snapped his
H ringers and told him
Htowakeup. He came
Hto instantly, lie was
H questioned as to how
Ihe lelt and the con-
Hversation became
Hg ener al. Professor
Earley casually drew his watch while
the boy was looking his way, and
the latter instantly dropped over asleep.
The doctors present, as stated, made them
selves certain that the demonstration was
in all particulars just what it seemed.
On Wednesday rooming young Boulton
went to the office of Dr. Levkowicz
and bad that sensitive tooth filled without
feeling any pain, the "post hypnotic sug
gestion," as they call it, holding good.
All the dentists present at the clinic and
aware of the circumstances are agreed
that the results are nothing less than
wonderful and that they mean a revolu
tion in the science of dentistry.
"It means that by a wave of the hand a
patient having a painful operation to go
through may be set at ease. It means
much for both the dentist and the suffer
ing public," said one of them.
The Stomatological Club is a rather ex
clusive organization and its members were
at first blush greatly opposed to having the
fact made public that it had lent itself to
a countenancing of hypnotism. Dr.
Levkowicz explained this feeling:
"We know, as scientific men, the trend
of the times and the necessity of keeping
pace with them if we are to keep in the
race at all. Dr. Bernheim's work in the
hospitals of France is familiar to all well
informed practitionera his success, the
wonderful results he has attained. We
know also the charlatanism that obtains in
this mystic art, and we know that the pub
lic at large, generally less well informed in
scientific matters than the practitioner, is
inclined to be wary of men whopraciice it.
While we feel it our duty to investigate it
we do not wish the impression to go
abroad that the members of the Stomato
logical Club are rushing into hypnotism
as a fad. We approach the subject with
the conservative care of a scientific propo
sition. We feel that it would be a great
beneficence to a patient if the pain of the
dentist's chair might be done away with
by a word. But, while we have had a
number of experiments of the kind at the
clubrooms, I am free to say that this of
Professor Earley is the only one that has
proved entirely convincing as to the util
ity of hypnotism in the science of den
tistry. All persons may not be hypno
tized, however. Dr. Bumheim himself, I
believe, brings under the influence only
about 80 per cent of those he attempts.
And, at all events, the consent of the
patient must be obtained. As I say, with
the Stomatological Club it is a scientific
experiment."
Following were the members of the club
who were present at the clinic; Clinician,
M. W. Levkowicz; William J. Younger,
president of the club; Russell H. Cool,
vice-president; S. E. Knowles, secretary;
Thomas Morffew, treasurer; Luther A.
Teague, A. J. Merriman Jr., J. A. W.
Lundborg, Walter F. Lewis, Clyde S.
Payne, W. Z. King, H. R. Morton Sr., F.
M. Hackett, J. S. Knowlton. F. L. Platt,
S. L. Btrickland, M. A. Greenlaw, J. J.
Giusti, E. A. Younger, George W. Cool, J.
E. Cummings, A. H. Millberry. Cecil
Corwin, Arthur H. Wallace, Frank C.
Pague, J. L. Asay, Max Sichel, Alfred
Cane, H. D. Boyes, F. K. Ledyard.
As for Professor J. B. Parley, who
worked the strange influence, he is a new
comer to the City. He is a man of slight
figure and quiet manner, wearing the ap
pearance of the student. His voice is low
and kindly rather than stern and com
manding. His eyes and the expression of
his face are calm and reassuring. He said
"I cannot attempt to explain the mystery of
hypnotism any more than Edison will try
to tell you what electricity is," he said.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-07-14/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnotism/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>/S hypnotism to be part and
parcel of medical practice?
Judging from zt'hat some of
the doctors say, it is so useful an
aid to medicine that zve may expect
to see it in the near future
packed away hi every neatly mono
grammed black leather case that
accompanies a frock coat.
Judging from what others of the
doctors say, it> is all one with
quackery, with foolery, with fak-
Dr. Q. J. Fitzgibbon.
Dr. C. Kenz.
Dr. C. C. Kenyon.
Dr. F. "W. D'Evelyn.
Dr. George F. Shiels.
It is only the effort to reduce results to a scien
tific causation that has attracted so much atten
tion to the psychical condition of hypnosis. That
this power should have not only a significance
but utility is not an illogical conclusion, arid any
Hypnotism will never take the place of
an anesthetic. I have not taken much In
terest in it because I do no»think It is of
any' benefit' In therapeutics, except In
cases of nervousness or hysteria. The
immense amount of time it takes to treat
by hypnotic influence is one thing against
it, and its limitations are another.
Dr. J. "W. Thorn.
Hypnotism exists and has always done
bo. It is coeval with man and the evolu
tion of the higher animal forms, as l\ is
rot either in its presence or phenomena
eciely confined to the former. The weird
influence of the Hindoo fakir o\'er the
eerpent of the field, or in turn, the subtle
fascination of the reptile over Its para
lyzed prey, are in fact based upon the
same principle as the experiments of a
Paracelsus or a Charcot— viz., the elimina
tion and concentration of a force or in
fluence which pervades life, creating an
atmosphere of reflexodism— as palpable as
It is universal.
;It is! a 'very dangerous force, and I do
net approve of its use cither by physicians
or. any one else. When put to -legitimate
purpose it Is not of any., great''"* benefit
either, in medicine; or surgery.. It" could
not possibly take the place of an-anes
thetic, although It has been substituted
for it in mild 'operations -where the pain
would not, even were the .patient con
scious, De very severe.
[stsrlng Intently': at their reflection- In a
i mirror. These cases surely are paralleled:
?by a large and not unfamiliar class,. who
so persistently see "self ever-reflected
self— that they finally, rest in the calm and
peaceful- hypnosis that -amidst all- mun
dane phenomena they are ever IT. Would
it not be cruel to awake them?
The use. of hypnotism Is riot a matter of
indifference and demands the same -pre
cautions as would be employed in the
therapeusis of any potent agent. It is in
teresting to. note a certain phase of auto-
Infection— of a consolatory- and flattering
'character— not'infrequently found in will
ingly hypnotized patients, viz., a power to
produce the hypnotic- state simply by
¦^-•y/v-T" r j,
the; '"weak-minded", that are amenable;
¦on' theicontrary, .the mentally strong pro^
vlded -they are -passive— often" afford the
most profound 'results.-
i Children iare of ten beneficially treated,
not whichin children is apt to produce a feel
•Ing 'of .awe j or fear, akin I to 'that begotten
by. the; mention of a bogyman, but by con
centration of the mind upon some phy
sical "exercise which throws Into- activity
the set bf organs— contrary to those eni-'
ployed in produclpg the 1 morbid phe
nomena.
In true organic disease Its
power would essentially be lim-
Hed"to the modification of cer-.
tain symptoms associated
therewith, e. g.jhraln, sleepless
ness," fear. All persons are not
equally.; susceptible,- nor must
it be concluded that it is "only
Hypnotism has been success
fully employed;as a '''/medicinal
agent," but its field, probably
for the reason above stated, Is
at present limited.' If we should
define a class of maladies, in
which j it .has proved and will
likely prove most valuable, we
should say. It- will be- that of
functional nervous diseases.' J
f all should j probably be at
tributed to. our faulty, interpre
tation rather than to lack -of
functional'activlty upon part of
the force or bower.
I have used hypnotism a great deal In
my. practice, and yet I consider Its use
very limited, almost entirely to nervous
and hysterlcalpatlents, and I do not think
it' possible for it to ever take the place
of an anesthetic because of the length of
time it requires, and also because some
are not susceptible to its influence.' No
one knows what type of person is the
most susceptible, as opposites in charac
teristics and temperament prove both sus
ceptible and resistant. »I have used hyp
notism on nearly, a hundred patients, but
it only after all supplemented In a smaller
degree medicine. \lt cannot touch organic
trouble, and the length of time consumed
in' hypnotizing a patient is a great draw
back.; I do not thlnkthe morphine' habit
can be cured by it; ,--C-'
Dr. A. A. D'Ancona.
The salaries of lawmakers In many
parts of Europe seem trifling, according to
American standards. In- London, for in
*stance, there are 150 members in the upper
and 250 in the lower branch. The former
get no pay at all and the latter but*$300
a And if any session lasts lonser
than four months they are paid at the rate
of $2 GO a day additional. The Parliament
of Holland. comprises 150 members in two
-houses.. Members of the Upper House re
ceive 54 a day and of the second body $300
a year and mileage. Parliament of
Holland costs $300,000 a year.
The most scantily paid of any of the
regularly salaried lawmakers are those
of Austria. There are two legislative
bodies for Aastria, one meeting in Vienna
and -one in Budapest. The total cost is
$SOO,000 a year. An Austrian law provides
that the members receive 10 florins.' of J2 a
THE most expensive Parliament la
Europe is that of France, which
costs $1,500,000 a year. The French
people are very well represented.
There are 300 Senators and 5S4 Deputies, a
total in excess of £00. Each 'receives a sal
ary of S1S00 a year.
In the United States the ninety Senators
and 3G0 Congressmen are paid $2,500,000 In
salaries.
The members of the British Parliament
serve without salary. The incidental ex
penses of this body last "year were but
$260,000. The German Reichstag, with its
two branches, costs the voters on an aver
age S1C0.C00 a year.
Russia has no Parliament in the Amer
ican or French sense, ao that this item is
entirely saved. The legislators In the
Italian Parliament receive no salaries, but
have free transportation on railroads. The
cost of the Italian Parliament last year,
nevertheless, was $420,000.,
LAWMAKERS AND
THEIR PAY.
The evil that could be done with the
aid of hypnotism Is practically unllmlte-i
and the good eo very limited that on the
whole it should better be frowned upon
by all, including the medical profession.
I have never tried to hypnotize any one,
though I have seen something of It. It is
not to be depended on and there Is very
little to recommend it.
Its use is so limited, almost entirely to
hysterical patients, and it might assist in
nervous trouble. It has no curative qual
ities, and I do not think it has made much
progress or headway.
I do not favor hypnotism. It is a bad
agent in the hands of unprincipled per
sons, and I think the majority of physi
cians in good standing disapprove of It.
I know there are some good physicians
¦who favor its use, but they are the ex
ception that prove the rule to the con
trary.
Hypnotism! Why, I really never tried
it, and have not even seen much of it, so
my opinion on It would not amount to
anything. Of course, there Is such a
thing, but I always feel like classing it
with the work of mediums and clairvoy
ants. It is so associated In my mind,
though some physicians approve of it. I
do not think the majority favor it. Hys
terical patients are about the only class
benefited by it.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1904-05-13/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnotism+hypnotize+HYPNOTIZES/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PROMINENT PHYSiGIANS'S QUEER
DELUSION; HYPNOTIZES HIMSELF
NEW YORK, May 13.—At his own re
quest Dr. Paul H. Collins, of 408 Central
Park Wept, is now undergoing treatment
at Bellevue hospital tor the strangest
malady, or whatever it might be called,
ill.l the physician.* at that institution
have ever had to (leal with.
He believes that he can hypnotise him
self.
For long be hag delved into the im-!«iie.«
of hypnotism, and it in believed that bis
mind has become so imbued with the sub
ject M to result in a moat singular im
pairment.
On other subjects the unfortunate physi
cian it perfectly rational. Physically his
condition in good. He seem* to realise
that his self-hypnosis is a weird delusion,
a nightmare of a disordered mind, but try
as he will, so far he has been utterly un i
able to rid himself of it.
For a year it has haunted him night and
day. "The end can only be death," he
repeats pathetically. And Dr. Collins I
dreads the very name of death, and, no j
wonder, for he firmly believes that it will
come to him in a ghastly manner.
"I will gome day hypnotize myself." li« i
tells the hospital physicians, "into a state
of coma, and then be buried alive.'' This
dread thought is with him ever.
Dr. Parker, head of the psychopathic
ward, is unable to state what will be the
ultimate result of this strange case. The
alienist does not believe self-hypnosis pos
sible.
To your correspondent he said: "There
is do authenticated record of inch a thing.
It i- ,c remarkable delusion, more remark
able in the Fact that on oilier subject*
Dr. Collins can converse sanely, even bril
liantly. As for hit- intense fear of death
any one would have that who carried con
stantly with him the braln-rnking idea
that his certain fate- was to "be buried
alive."
Other members of the medical profession
■who have known Dr. Collins in the past,
state that he has been a great student, lias
ample funds, and is of a liberal mind and
generous disposition. He is a big man,
aged somewhere in the titties, and has
never married. His mother lives in the
northern part of New York state. His
brother is in Buffalo.
When Dr. Collins went to the hospital
he astonished Dr. Parker by exclaiming:
"I am .1 doctor, like yourself, and I want
you to thoroughly examine me and tell me
whether I am going crazy."
"What seems to be the trouble?" asked
Dr. Parker.
And then came the story that reminds
one sonic of Jekyl and Hyde. Dr. Collins
told how he had studied deeply into he
art of hypnotism anil had attained remark
able success in its practice. He went on:
'•Finally came the time when I discov
ered that I could sit alone and hypnotize
myself. The sensation is indescribable
"and decidedly uncomfortable, and 1 realize
QjsS^> WISH</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1912-12-29/ed-1/?sp=45&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnot+hypnotic+Hypnotism+HYPNOTISM+hypnotism+hypnotized&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=-0.251,-0.075,1.503,1.503,0/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>INCREASED USE
OF HYPNOTISM
Dr. J. D. QuackenboG Tells of Its Great
Value to Physicians and Its
Help to Sufferers
W
HEN the police of London.
England, forcihly chocked thu
activities of fortune teller,
crystal globe gazers and simi
lar charlatans who prey on tho credulity
of men and women, us was told in a recent
cablegram to Tim SU.v their action had
indirectly an important bearlni' on the i
public health. As a result of tlieptittiiii;
of tho swindlers out of business the fact
has been brought prominently to public
attention that not only has the value of
hypnotism and the treatment of patients
oy mental suggestion come to be better
appreciated bul also thut many highly
cpinlilicd physicians in Knglaud and oNo
whero in Europe are making n specialty
of psychic treatment. With the down
fall of the charlatan fortune tellers and
others of their typo who have sought to
make illegitimate uso of hypnotism the
number of reputable pructitioners who
have adopted mental suggestion is grow
ing. Certain physicians in the United States
huve for borne time made u.e of mental
suggestion or hypnotism in their practice
and, the')' say, with distinct benefit to their
patients, Dr. John D. Quackcnbo.s, who
is n proiossor emeritus of Columbia Uni
versity and who for a nutii'i' r o' "-a-has
lectured on psychology in and outside
of tho college, ha tused mental sii.-g t i 1
on hypnotized persons, or sleeping sub
jeels, as ho t -run them, moro than lo.'OO
times nnd always, ho believes, with suo
ci'is in tho casiM of tlicno s Pfe.-ing f-om
physical as well as from nuntal diso.m).
"Very much interest hr.s been ere.. tod
ln.r.t i'u 11 t-itunlt iT 'l'lll. Kl.v'a f t.tn.im-n
'r., i., ,f .1... ,.'...i. i... f ,i,
lolico there ,.g. Inst dlshon.'st users of outrols the congestion, hyper-secretion,
hypnotism end ly the. elded statemet t f"1'1:'"4 "r ",0 H-ad und asihina.
that there is evidence, of 1111 iniTei-sed -.Slamtiiering unci other hjieech defects
use of mental sugrostion by physicians appropriate conditions for treat mem
in England and in the Continent," s..id!''' l'ymotis.n. while pulhologieul bush
Dr. (JuackenU.s. 'This was emlv to bo f "ess or morbid Milf-consciotisness.
e'xpocii'el. for tho value of such treatment
h .si eonelemonstratedbv such tihvsl I l.s
of worldwide reputition rs Pr. I.loyd-
Tuckey and Pr. MllnoHramwoll of London,
who are using this instniino:it.;llty to
re-scuo the sick nnd mentally do.iresseel
with marked suce'essj Dr. l area a'.el Dr.
Iicrillon in Paris, vim h vo a school of
psychology, where public) trc-.tmont is
dally given; Dr. (Srossm n of llerlln,
who Ronio time npo ctte:.ilesl the C.irlna
of 1'ussi.i, giving her psychio troatmer.t;
Prof. Froel in .ttrieh if.d Prof. Paul
Dubois r.t Porno, Swltzer'and; Dr. vort
Velscn nt Brussels, Itelgium; Dr. von
.Schrcnolc-Notzliig ut Munich, Germ my
and Dr. von nontorghoi aid Dr. van
Ecdcn at Amsterdam. Hollmd, all of
them using mental suggestion li 0110
form or another. In tho United St ;tcs
such treatment is constantly Increaslni;.
"As a mutter of fact the greatest value
of psychio treatment is in cases of neuras
thenia, delusions and Imperative con
ceptions which are largely dependent on
chemical conditions which lire remediable.
No dNeuse is purely mental or purely
physle-il. The advanced physician not
only offers specillo tre it merit to thes
subjects but rights tho chemistry o'
the body by removing tho ititostina
poisoning that in so markedly responsibh
for the.e delusions.
I "Hypnotism is specUlly applicable t
j the cure of phobias oi fair, such .s tin
fear of lightning, dust, crowds, solitude
klhe fe.ir of responsibility, ilNo-so, of
becoming deformed, of blushing; tlio fair
of sleeple-sness; tho fear of dogsor rabies,
to s. y nothing of continual impulses to
strike mine one, to strangle children,
or to commit other crimes which r.re ex
pressions of true psychaMhenia or mental
e.xli uistion.
"It Is a peculiar thing that sometimes
people with the best intentions in the
world will often bo huuntcd by impera
tive impulses to lnjtir their neighbors
or even their own children. Theso im
putes aro as a rule controlled, but seem
simply to torture the subject. They de
pend on an exhaustion of tho nervous
substance in tho brain cells from over
work, worry or shock.
"An an illustration, I had a patient who
wIi-mi business became unusually active,
111 for instance just before the holidays,
was seized witli nil impulse to take ti
hatchet anil I. ill some one. This ImpuUe
was so great that he was induced to koep
away from hatchets, clubs or similai
implements with which he might do harm
were they in his sight.
"There is i distinct elifferenco betweer
this cnndlMon and tho homicidal impulse
of an insane person, for tho neurasthenic
will never do harm when observed, while
the insane person is liliel.' to carry out
his homicidal Impulse at any time. Il
is in such cases that mental suggestion
affords the only relief.
"Psychio suggestion lias boon largely
employed in the treatment of e-pilopsy.
Ilystero-i.pile.psy, the hysterical counter
feit or epilepsy, is absolutely curable In my
experience.
"Another elisease that yields to meiitul
suggestion supplemented by regular
treatment l.s diabetes. Tho patient under
hypnosis is urged to correct the perverted
nervous function, ho that first tlmsturchy
matter constinnsl as food shall bo prop
erly assimilated and second that sugar
shall not bo manufactured in tlio body
to excess. Mental simci-stioiis uro nddod
I to counteract the appetite for swei'ts nnd
eNccsslve thirst. All my patients have
I been markedly beiirliteel or cut irely cured
I by hypnotic! treatment, which I now give
n connection w ith the llulgariati bacillus.
1 In my last case of this treatment the
sugar dropped from ll'4 lot) per cent.
I "The lliilgarian bacillus, it may be
explained, is thu enemy of tho bacteriu
that produco putrefaction in tho intes
tines, and that are regiiided (is one
cause of diabetes. It is so named becutisi
in llulguria S,(h u persons huo been fuimi
who were more than 100 years of age
and who were still healthy and active
Investigation showed that their longevit;
was duo to tlie fact that they lived largol.
oil sour milk products, i hereforo th'
1 liaracterNlio bacillus of tho sour mil.
has been naturally termed the llulgariai
bacillus. In all cases or diabetes remark
able gains in energy have followe el th.
early treatments by psychics suggestion
I "In buy fever, again, mental suggestion
Idoatroys (he irritability or tho nasn
mucous membrane, lis sensibility te
Irrl.uting substuuees in tho atmosphere
I t"o way. is extremely common
nmoli'? public speukcrs. singers, actors
and even business men und women, is
readily cured by upproprinto mental
suggestion. In tho treatment of such
cases tho sleeping nubject or tho person
under hypnosis must bo. imbued with a
feeling of equality, and all unso of in
feriority in tho presence of his follow
beings removed, lie le inudo to seo that
tho undervaluation or pulf is immoral
I localise It Billitraets irom 111s oiuciciicy
or capacity for happluess.
".Mental suggestion, or hypnotUm,
whichever phrase you prefer, properly
administered upiN to tho God part
of tlio person under treat tnimt. That is
tho truth, and thnt, ipilto likoly, is tho
necret of its grout v.iluo anil omcaoy
This lelng so there can Im no ground for
objection to nor criticism of its uso hi
healing the sick. It Is an advanced stop
in tho proctico of tnediolno, and whatever
benefits suffering mankind must In all
justice be welcomed."</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1913-05-19/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;
q=Hugo+hypnotic+hypnotism+Hypnotism+HYPNOTISM+hypnotize+Hypnotize+hypnotized+Munsterberg&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=-0.482,-0.46,1.202,0.92,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HYPNOTISM NO LONGER A MYSTERY
What Was Once the Showman's Art Is Now
Explained By Psychologists and Used By
Physicians in Curing Diseases.
Professor Fakirlno, the "World's
Greatest Hypnotist," who visited all
the country towns a quarter of a cen
tury ago, was a mystical looking per
son with flowing black hair and a
"powerful hypnotic eye." Under the
spell of his mysterious words and ges
tures, village youths went Into trances,
and at his suggestion picked apples
from chandeliers, played baseball- with
toothpicks and even proposed to the
homeliest old maids in the audience.
And everybody ccreed that the pro
fessor was a great magician.
Next came the spiritualists, mediums
and clairvoyants. Of course they did
not admit that they used hypnotism.
They did not tell their followers that
they hypnotized them Into hearing
spirit rappings and receiving mes
sages from the dead. They did not
tell them either that the trances Into
which they themselves went were only
self-Induced ypuotlc states. And ev
erybody, according as they believed or
disbelieved, said this was the work
or the Lord or the devil.
And then came science, and with
this hypnotism lost all or Its mystery
and much of Its charm. "Hypnotism,"
said science, "Is only a peculiar con
dition of the nervous system produced
by artificial means. It is a state al
lied to sleep walking. In which the sub
conscious elements are uppermost.
Then science went about establishing
hypnotism on a practical basis and
making it of service in medicine, in
surgery and In detecting crime.
Anyone Can Hypnotize.
But the greatest blow of science to
the old mythical hypnotism was to
shear Professor Fakirlno and his kind
of their power. "Anybody can hypno
tize anybody else," says Dr. Hugo
Munsterberg of Harvard, "just as any
body can fall in love or be loved."
"There Is nothing to this so-called
hypnotic power," says Dr. Max Meyer
of the University. "Anyone can be a
hypnotist. All that is required Is a
little skill, not .any more though than
is needed to become a 'good shoe
maker. It Is just a way of talking and
it is above all self confidence. More
over anybody can hypnotize himself.
All he has to do is to look- steadily
at some object long enough. He may
select a table leg or a more striking
object as a bright crystal. This Is
called 'auto-hypnosls.'
However, some persons are much
more easily hypnotized than others,
a cording to Doctor Meyer. "A per
son who is hypnotized very easily,
must be abnormal," he says. "He Is
hysterical in a high degree. Now, we
are all of us more or less hysterical
although we won't admit It The per
son who is least so is the most difficult
to hypnotize. After a person has been
hypnotized once he is more amenable
to it in the future."
Many of the strange things attribut
ed to hypnotism do not belong to it.
Doctor Meyer believes. The Idea that
It gives certain evil men power to
make women fall in love with them Is
a mistake, he thinks. "Hypnotism Is
too transitory an Influence for that,"
he says. "Besides it does not make
anyone do anything opposed to his na
ture. It would not have made Trilby
a wonderful singer. It usually makes
us do foolish things such as wearing
straw hats in December. However,
many of us do a great many foolish
things even when we are not hypno
tized." Methods Used Are Simple.
There are several methods of hypno
tizing persons. One is to arrest their
attention by a bright object Another
is to make monotonous sleep sugges
lons. IiTboth, the subject's confidence
in the hypnotist must be established
first, for one cannot be hypnotized by
a new person ror the first time
against one's will. The steps in the
process of hypnotism are relaxed eye
muscles, vacant stare, Indolent atten
tion, passive brain, blank mind, re
verie, sleep.
A dangerous use or hypnotism, Doc
tor Meyer says, is that or extorting
confessions from accused criminals,
ir hypnotic sleep is imposed on a per
son or not over-strong mentality he
will say anything that is suggested to
him. Doctor Meyer referred tp the
Ivcns case or Chicago In this connec
tion. Richard Ivens, a young man or
good character but low mentality, was
hypnotized by the Chicago police about
six years ago and made to confess to
a crime which psychologists have
agreed he never committed. He was
executed for the crime and because of
this many psychologists protest strong
ly against the use of hypnotism in
criminal procedure.
However, hypnotism may be valuable i appearance or the grounds and or Co
in less serious detective work. Doc- lumbia. All were impressed with the
tor Munsterberg tells or a student who j fact that things were done on such a
had the cocaine habit but who main- large scale at the state Institution
tained most emphatically that he had which they consider their own.
no cocaine in his rooms. Doctor Muns- The Agricultural Building and the
tTberg hypnotized him and he de- new Chemistry' and Physics Buildings
MONDAY, MAY 19, WIS
rate y the place where the
scribed accu
cocaine was hidden.
Hypnotism Used by Doctors.
Hypnotism Is being used extensively
in the practice of medicine. Doctor
Meyer says. In the treatment of func-
tional diseases. Very seldom, how
ever, are patients put In a deep
hypnotic states but suggestions are
made to them in the first stages. It
is said that if a person has a bad
habit he wishes to be rid of, he may
as he Is about yielding to slumber for,
the night resolve to break I and he
will find it easier to carry out his res-,
olutlon the next day.
A subject can be made to periorm,
long after the hypnosis has ended.
"You may be told In a hypnotic spell,"
says Doctor Meyer, "to go at 4 o'clock
tomorrow afternoon to a friend, stand
on one leg and repeat the alphabet
This you will do although the spell
may have ended long ago."
This fact has been taken by
..-mlt
to prove uiai iierouuo uncu vuutum.
crimes at the suggestion of others who
have hypnotized them some time before.
"That never occurs." saya Doctor
Meyer. "The only persons who would
do this would be feeble-minded per-
.lmtnn1o DaaMoa trio
guilty one who suggested the 'crime
would probably be caught anyway." I
Hypnotism should not be demon-
straiea in snows, uocior mi "c
lieves. "It should not be made a Piay- der was shot away todav through
thing to be trifled with, for this might Rugsla ,n celebrat,on of the forty.
have serious consequences. It is just flfth blrthday of Czar Nlchoia8. It waa
like saying. 'Come pay 10 cents and, e8t,mated that $100000 worth of pow.
see a drunk man.' The principle is K wm n fir,ng hour,y sa,utes
the same although the drunken man Is i &amp;
t fortress Qf gt peter an(J pau,
not quite so unusual a sight as a and durIng the morning celebration In
hypnotized person. Perhaps though Petersburg Thanksglvlng servIces
one may De as commuii a me uiuci
in the future. Who knows?" M. L.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1915-02-17/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnot+Hypnotic+hypnotic+hypnotism+Hypnotism+hypnotized+hypnotizer/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Hypnotic Treatment Often
Responsible fo Complete
Loss of the Will Power
By DR. LEONA11D KEENE HIRSHBERG,
iCopyrlfAt. 1815. Newspaper Feature 8"rvUe. ln.
MEDICAL men, universities, ami
medical schools properly oast
an eye of suspicion upon hyp
notism, and physicians piay go
around among hospitals and laborato
ries throughout long medical carcera
and never hear a word about hypnot
ism Ih connection with practice.
Upon Inquiry at recent largj medi
cal meeting, there was only one person
present who know anything about It.
cither academically or from personal
practice. This man, strange to say, waa
an Instructor of zoology, and did not
teach medicine, lie
alone of the medi
cal hosts assem
bled knew the dato
of Mesmer's Intro
duction of piactl
cal hypnotism, in
177?.
True enough, the
magicians of the
Pharaohs' courts
thousands of yeais
ngo, the Yogi and
faklis of India,
and many others
use what Is knownDR. HIRSIIBKRC;.
today as hypnotism
oi mesmerism At the Athenia Acio
poli, (he Temple of Aesculapius, as
I well as In Tacitus, Pliny, and other an
cient writeis. emphasis is laid upon
piacllccs vvhlfh were undoubtedly hyp
notic. Hypnotism Artificial Sleep
When in 177s-. Mesmcr Introduced hjv
notism into France, the intense, tnough
unconscious, jealousy, and enmttv of
the whole medical profession wltn all
its weight was directed aga'nst the
I man King l.ouls VI was persu.iueu in
174 to appoint a loyal commission of
Investigation. It members wcr seleet
ril foi theli acknowledged hostility.
The report nt was expected, condemned
Mesinei as a fraud, quack, renegade,
I and othei vile things.
Tlie attention of Prussia was thus al
li.'icterl in Mesmer's methods .mil Tirac-
i tlce A omin ssion was appointed there, I
wlilcli nought in a fuvoraine report.
ami JlcsUTiiT became in Prussia vreater
thin he could hae bet onie in France.
Hypnotism is tin piactice of produc
ing artificial!' suggested sleep, during
which urlous state there Is a suspen
slon of the patient's own will and a
siibi'isntlon of his activities and
thoughts to the will of the hypnotizer.
Hypnotism is not a type of treatment,
las manv Interested ones wrongly main
tain. Hypnotism, plus the suggestion
which usually ncompanles it. Is like
l '.akin gas. liquor or ether, plus sug
1 testion Drugs, like hypnotism, weaken
j l lie will nnd permit some one else to
.substitute his will and thoughts for
that of the subject. The will of the one
hypnotized Is not only weakened and in
abeyance at the time of artificial semi
sleep, but it becomes permanently more
and more feeble
Many would-be Hippocrates, Galens,
Antiseptic
Individual
Size,
50c
Druggists:
Paul Pearson,
ISth and Flu. .Ve. N. W.
Tipton Myers,
liM 14th St. N. S'
R. L. Quigley,
2 1 st and G Sts. N. W
G. G. C. Simms Pharmacy,
723 14th St. Cor. N. V. Ave.
PeopVs Drug Stores,
7th and K Sts
"til and i: Sts
The Henry Evans Company. Inc.,
1 ith and Columbia Itoad
F. H. Ridgway Pharmacy.
Connecticut and Florida Aver
Associated Drug Stores, 7th and (i St5.
BLBBBBF'
Chemist, Inc., Washington, D. C.
and ncar-pundlls, through lack of ex
perience and practical knowledge, fal
laciously hold that suggestion In ordi
nary life, "peyeho-therapy, new
thought, and psycho-analysis are much
the name as hypnotism. Nothlne could
be farther from the truth. Hypnotism
means a form of. artificial sleep, wjth a
strongly willed, powerfully suggested
waking stale, In which the teason
lodgment, emotions and will of tho sub
ject nrc absent and replaced bv the
vigorously enforced emotions, decision',
nctlons, and will of (ho experimenter
One Possible Dangre.
When one is hypnotized be is neces
sarily ausccptlbli; to the stronsej vvlll of
the tnentneilzei. Fhsl, there is dtowr
ness. then follows light sleep with tight
ly closed eyes and lai k of will power
but n retention of the inenioty Finally
there Is somnambulism and the memoi
lades. Indeed, It Is the ability to re0g
nUf the past from the present the i
loundlngs of the moment, event if
other days, recollection, retention, ai d
iccall, which have most to ilu with the
Htato called hypnosis.
I?v subjugating nnothei's will jidi
ment, memory, vmotions and Intellee
tual processes and the transference of
those of the hypnotizer, memory and
knowledge can be altered, reduced, en
larged, exaggerated not onlv for tho
period undei hypnosis, but for subse
quent periods. Svengall in Du Maurlei'a
"Trilby" Illustrates correctly the power
of hypnotism over the thoughts, the ac
tions, the voice, the emotions, and the
will. To be sure. Trilby hud to be pe
culiarly and naturallv weak-willed and
hypermiscoptlbie to Svengall.
This Is the event in all Instances. Th
best hypnotizer can only find a few pet
sons hypersueceptlble enough to bring
about HUi li a state, and most, penpl
could not with the best ability of hvp
notize an infant
Notwithstanding the rarity of hvp
nolle power, it Is not i ountenanced b
those most experienced Its practice
Kvery malady thnt was ever cured v
It is CTpable of successful ticatment b'
other and safer methods, Moreovei
crimes can be committed upon hypne
tlzeri persons, and hypnotism is capa'
I
of pausing persons seemingly poife'
normal to give absurdly false swor
testimony. It can also impel hvperus
ccptlWe persons to commit cnmti,il
acts which would be abhoircnt to th'i"
in a normal state.
Children, women, those ictarded 'n
moral development and education env
tional persons, and others susceptible in
the hypnotic Influence, are prone to br
come mentally Injured by Its upe upoi
them.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1917-09-01/ed-1/?sp=16&amp;
q=Hypnosis+hypnosis+hypnotic+Hypnotism+HYPNOTISM+hypnotism/&amp;
r=-0.364,0,1.729,1.205,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Mysteries of Hypnotism
and Transferenceof Thought
Tfje Former, Says Garrett P. Serviss, Noted
Scientific Writer, Is a Real Phenomenon That Has
Possibilities of Important Service to Mankind, But
It Must Be Handled Cautiously. Telepathy, in the
Shadow Land of Science, Still Has to Prove Its Case,
Although Investigators Report Apparently Well
Authenticated Manifestations of Its Existence.
By Garrett
Ii It a fact that one perion can
hypnotise another person, or Is It
Jut mere talk? Does science ap
prove of mental telepathy" O. A.
A.. Streator, III
HYPNOTISM Is an estab
lished fact, but the ex
planation of it is still more
or less obscure. It is recognized
by high authorities as a valuable
method of treatment in disorders
that are subject to mental influ
ence, but great caution and expert
knowledge are required in order
to render its employment safe.
No person should ever submit
to hypnotic influence except under
the advice of a regular physician
of the highest standing, and at the
hands of a practitioner concerning
whose motives and capability there
can bo no question. Amateur ex
perimentation with this strange
power is perilous and should al
ways be avoided.
There Is undoubtedly c great
amount of quackery abroad in con
nection with hypnotism, and while
I believe that it is capable of ren
dering immense service to man
kind, yet it is still but partially
developed as a subject of scien
tific study, and the number of
those who can be trusted to apply
it, as well as the number of ac
credited physicians who would
even undertake to apply it, is
small. But this Is not to say that
its methods when fully developed
and understood may not become a
very important branch of medical
practice.
It has been proved that the hyp
notic State can be indueed in the
majority of persons who willingly
submit to it, but it is doubtful
whether any person can be hypno
tized against his vill. A state of
complete confidence between the
operator and the patient must be
established as a preliminary. That
being done, It Is said that hardlv
10 per cent of those experimented
upon prove refractory to hypnotic
influence.
Its Value Already Proved
As Mental Remedy and
Prophylactic.
The valuable feature of hypno
tism is found in the suggestions
tending toward healthy conditions
which can be imparted to the hyp--notlzed
subject without his being
conscious of their origin after
awakening from the trance. It is
somewhat as If, by the temporary
arrest of his external conscious
ness, his body were transformed
into a mere machine, whose bent
cogs and pinions can then be re
dressed and oiled without his
knowledge, so that after he has
come to himself again and resumed
his normal life he finds the mech
anism working better.
All that the operator has really
done is to correct abnormal habits
by suggestions conveyed to the
nervous system of l" patient
P. S-e x v i s s
when the latter is in a state of
recepUveness freed from the dis
tractions of waking life. Mani
festly, only diseases that are asso
ciated In some decided way with
nervous action can come under the
control of hypnotic suggestion,
but such diseases are very numer
ous and of vast importance to
human comfort and happiness.
Pains, especially rheumatic and
neuralgic pains, have been relieved
in this way, and it has been
claimed that such habits as drunk
enness have been cr-ed by hyp
noUc suggestion. Morbid, nerv
ous and bodily tendencies, like in
somnia, hysteria and constipation,
also appear to be amenable to this
treatment.
It might at first slgU be sup
posed that serious mental dis
orders would yield to hypnotic
treatment, but It has been found
that they do not, the apparent
reason being that, since it Is
through the brain that the hyp
notic influence works, it is essen
tial that that organ should be in
sound condition. To vield to hyp
notic treatment is not an indica
tion of mental weakness.
Hypnosis Allied to Sleep,
Although Condition Is
Not Identical
Many theories have been pro
posed to explain hypnotism. In a
general way hypnosis resembles
sleep, and the two states are re
garded as being allied though not
identical. One explanation of hyp
nosis is that under its influence a
state of relative dissociation oc
curs among the brain cells, so that
the operator can accentuate the
activity of certain impressions
without interference through other
nervous links. This would account
for such a phenomenon as the
anesthesia of one evj of the sub
ject while the other remains un
affected. Thus if the operator tells the
subject that he cannot see with
his right eye, but only with his
left one though both eyes be nor
mal and wide open, it will be
found that the ritht eye really
does lose its power of seeing as
completely as if it were actually
blind, until the operator, by a
command, removes the disability.
Telepathy, which has been de
fined as "the conveyance of
thoughts and feelings from mind
to mind by other than the ordinary
channelb of sense," is a phenome
non not well established, like hyp
notism, by experimental evidence.
It has been associated with hyp
notism by attempts to Induce the
hypnotic state in subjects at a dis
tance from the operator. Dr.
Pierre Janet, in Franco, claimed to
have succeeded in nineteen out of
twenty-five attempts of this kind,
while Prof. Richet reported that
in nine attempts he had succeed
ed twice completely and four times
partially. I think that telepathy
has not yet got upon its scientific
legs.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1919-02-23/ed-1/?sp=25&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotist/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>How Innocent Little Norma
McLeod Convinced
a Learned
IIRhk jNR
A Wistful, Appealing Photo
graph of Little Miss McLeod,
Showing Her Youthful Face,
Figure and Curls.
FOR the first time In legal history, a
court of law has taken cognizance of
hypnotism as a defense against a
criminal charge and has released a pris
oner on the ground that in performing the
criminal act the accused was only a ma
chine, animated by and helplessly obeying
the will of a master mind.
Thus in real life we have the exact sit
uation which .made Du Maurier's famous
novel, "Trilby," a classic of fiction.
Norma McLeod is the name of this pres
ent day incarnation of the novelist's fancy.
Scarcely twenty-one, trembling, shaken
down to the very depths of her soul by her
experiences but once again mistress of
that soul, her heart and her body she con
vinced a wise judge, skeptical lawyers and
medical experts of the truth of her story,
forcing them to accept what to them
seemed at first and to many still may
seem, the incredible.
And when she was finished Judge
Thomas C. Craln, of the Court of Special
Sessions, whose hair has grown white in
his service of justice, said to her:
"The court releases you on a suspended
sentence of five years because it believes
that you were not responsible for the act
you committed, but that you acted under
the control of a will stronger than your
own."
Harry Sanderson, a soldier of fortune,
"Who, Norma McLeod says, was the Sven
gali to her Trilby, is missing with the po
lice seeking him so that he may be put in
a place where the uncanny force of which
he seems to be a master may be exerted
against unimaginative, wholly practical
jailers.
But unlike DuMaurier's Svengali, San
derson does not seem to have had to de
pend upon the use of staring eyes, mystic
passes with the hands and all the other
tricks of the stage hypnotist. Svengali's
methods were described by Du Maurier
thus:
"But all at once with one wave of his
hand over her with one look of his eye
with a word Svengali could turn her into
the other Trilby, his Trilby and make her
do whatever he liked.
"He had but to say 'sleep and she sud
denly became an unconscious Trilby who
could produce just the sounds he wanted
and nothing else and think his thoughts
and wish his wishes and love him at his
bidding with a strange, unreal love just
his own love for himself turned inside
ut a renvers and reflected back on him
as from a mirror."
Miss McLeod says that her master was
always very gentle with her, but that what
he told her to do she had to do-, that she
possessed no will, no thought except his
when he chose to exert his power over her.
And that, like Trilby's, her heart, her body
and her soul were at his mercy.
The specific charges upon which Miss
McLeod was arrested was the forgery on
a check of the name of Louis Missi, the
landlord of the apartment house at 248
West Forty-eighth street, where Sander
son and the girl lived. Sanderson had a
fancied grievance against Missi; he thought
the latter was obstructing telephone mes
sages'' to him. The forged check was pun
ishment. To wreak this punishment he
used Miss McLeod Just as he would have
used a pen or a pencil. Under his will she
was nothing more than one of these instru
ments in the hand of the adventurer' and
no more to blame for what was written
than pen or pencil would have been. This,
in effect, was the opinion of the court that
freed her.
What kind of a girl is Miss McLeod that
all her consciousness, her will and consci
ence could be so thrust out of her, leaving
her body only a shell in which worked
another's will and consciousness? How
did she fall into the power of the master
Judge That She
Was Blameless of
the Crime She Did,
Helpless Beneath
Thralldom of
Hypnotist's Evil
Will Just Like
the Helpless
Trilby of
Fiction, and the
Wicked Svengali
mind that controlled her? What were the
methods by which slowly he possessed her-
soul, heart and body?
Norma McLeod was, apparently, a normal
child. She was high strung, Imaginative
with a curious strain of stubbornness hut
these qualities are not unusual. There was
some mystery about her origin. She was
brought up by foster-parents and there is
a story that her real father and mother
were members of the company of a dis
tinguished French actress who had left her
behind when they sailed back to France.
She received an excellent education, mar
ried a young man of good family and lived
for a time happily In a suburban town.
Then ambition to become an actress
seized her. Another curious parallel with
Du Maurier's heroine now appears. Trilby,
it will be remembered, posed in artists'
studios. Norma McLeod's pet'te figure, her
wistful, childlike face and gentle personal
ity "registered," as the motion picture
people say, on the screen. She took sev
eral fairly important parts in a number of
successful films and seemed to be on the
high road to success as a star when sud
denly she met Sanderson.
Somewhat shy, reserved, she had made
no intimate friends. She was estranged
from her husband. Her foster-parents, as
she ipats it, "were so sternly good that
when I went on the stage they would have
nothing to do with me." She had been
taken ill. No one can be as lonely any
where as one can be in New York. Norma
McLeod lay in her apartment as lonely as
any one in New York had ever been.
Trilby, you remember, after her beloved
Littl2 Billee, the Laird and Taffee sailed
back to .England and left her, went to
Svengali and not till then!
"I do not think I would ever have had
thisterrible story to tell if I had not been
ill." she said. "I am not weak-minded.
There are to traits uppermost in my
character stubbornness and gratitude.
No one, when I was growir up in Min
neapolis, nor among those in the com
panies in which I played, ever thought I
was easily swayed by the will of others.
One actress once said to me: "You are the
stubbornest girl in thp company. I wouldn't
have jour obstinacy for the world."
"One morning when I awoke feeling
more wretched than ever, I saw a little
square of white paper under my door. I
crept out of bed and opened It. It was
a note:
"'Poor little girl,' it said. 'I am sorry
you're sick. I'd like to help you. If there
is anything I can do, let me know.
"It was signed 'Harry Sanderson.'
"A few minutes later there was a rap at
the door. I cried, 'Come in.' A man came
into the room. He brought me toast and
coffee, and he was very kind to me. It
was Sanderson.
"I was so grateful to him for his kind
ness that I could have kissed his hand. He
bought me a kitten. Gradually I got to
think of nothing but him. He said we
would be married, and when he proposed
moving away from that apartment house
to another I went with him. He talked
a great deal about when we should go back
to England. He never once spoke harshly
to me.
'"And at last I found that whatever he
told me to do that I must do! I who had
been so stubborn had no thought but his,
no will but his when he commanded me.
Soul, heart and body he was their master!
"Now that I am free I remember some
very odd things. There was, for instance,
what I might call the 'command of the
black suit case.' He put the black suit
case In my room one day, pointed to it and
told me I must never open it. I used to
sit by the hour looking at that suit case,
wishing to open it. and every time I tried
I could not even touch it. Some-
the
a
HBHHhmHV raHHHrVU lmn l I iVv Xalw2 I WSs "Ho 'Se Iss' iSSSA
illBBWlii I W I iWiviiiiiili'i'iii1' iIitWWhI MMm III ISMik Vv vS )S3 MBf iMm-M
times he left his key
ring behind and on
it I would see the lit
tle, shining brass key
that would open the
case. I could not use it
I could not even
touch it to the black
suit case. Whenever I
tried something seemed
to reach out and kill my
will to do it!
"Harry after a while grew short of funds.
The landlord began to quarrel with him.
Harry would sit and brood. Then he
would burst out In terrific rages at Louis
Missi. Missi kept the house where we
lived at No. 248 West Forty-eighth Street
Harry said messages had come for him by
telephone, that Missi didn't take the
trouble to give him. He said they were
offers of work, and he lost the work. He
said by neglecting those telephones Missi
had done ub both a great wrong. He had
ruined our careers and made us penniless.
One day he said, Til put up a check on
him.'
"Now, I am naturally honest. They used
to Joke with mo in companies because
they said I 'kept books.' If I borrowed a
dollar I always repaid it If I borrowed
rouge from another girl I not only returned
the rouge, but I returned the same shade
of rouge. Yet the disintegration of my
morality under;thc spell of this constant
hypnosis was such that I Interposed no
objection to 'putting up a check.' I only
said, 'What's the use? He hasn't any
money.' 'O, yes, he has,' Harry answered.
'I know because while we were friendly I
walked down to the bank with him and
saw him deposit noney.'
'It will serve him right,' he said. 'He
has kept me from making money.' He sat
and practiced Louis Missi's signature for
three days. He copied it from a receipt for
rent which we had. When he thought he
had the handwriting he slowly and care
fully filled out the check and signed the
name. He was so careful that it seemed
hours that he was at work on that cherk.
Then he turned it over and endorsed it in
the same name, Louis Missi.
"Then he said to me: 'Now sit down
and write Louise Missi under it'
"'Who is Louise Missi?' I asked.
'Nobody. he answored. 'but the bank
will think it is his sifter'
"Even in the strange state I was in I
thoimht of another woman, f said:
"Are you sure there isn't any Louise
Missi that this might get into trouble?'
'No,' he answered, looking steadily at
me. 'Sit down.' I took my spat at the
desk. He dinped the pen In the ink and
handed it to me. He was always
courteous.
'Sign.' he said.
"I never thought of doing other than he
told me. If he had told me to kill myself;
If he had asked me to sit in a building that
was on fire and wait until it burned to the
ground, I would have done so.
"When I had written the name, ho said:
'It will be better for you to go to the bank
to cash this. They are not so likely to sus
pect a woman. If they ask who you are
say you are his sister.'
"I hurried into my street clothes, and
put on my hat and almost ran to the bank
to reacli it before it was closed.
Copyrisht, 1919. by Star Company.
f Sti4mjy RF -w
'"sign!9 he rW frt?V SBmmKL
said. H y .JBMmi;- -i.,
never yJQ JnSHVr SPSulSfc.
thought of ww iPfW 4
doing other r5 JRt Wfo JmL.
than he told yb iBKffh ,J6BiflSl3ll.y" ioftii
me. If he BRf? f Ik1 jPSI
had told me to' kill myself; if he had flBfe $F I f Ri' t CHlik
asked me to sit in a building that was 'KJSr JL Jm f&amp;
IHR
on fire and wait until it burned to the tiMflBHr F W1" X fl 'Hb
ground I would have done so" VhSsHl 4 s r &amp;
s WL. "w&amp;
m
"I joined the line.
The teller looked at
me and said, 'Who
are you?' I said, I
am Louise Missi.
He said, 'Who is
Louise Missi?' I
answered, 'I am
Louis Missi's sis
ter.' He paid the
money. I took it
and went home and
gave It to Harry.
"Three days later
he 'put up' another
check and sent me
to the bank for the
money. That time
I didn't get the
money. The telldr
said 'the account is
overdrawn.'
"One day the de
tectives came to
the house in East Fifty-fifth street, where
we had moved from Louis Missi's. They
arrested me for passing the check. They
arrested him on a charge of theft.
"We were taken to the West Fifty
fourth Street Court. He remained In a
little side room. There was a door be
tween the rooms. It was open. Harry sat
and looked at me. I was taken before the
judge. The judge asked me questions. I
didn't heeni to understand the questions. I
would turn to look at Harry. The judge
said: 'Did you endorse the check?' I
looked at Harry. He nodded. I said, 'Yes.'
The Judge said: 'Did you present the
check at the bank?' I looked at Harry
again. He nodded. I said. 'Yes.'
"I was sent to the Tombs. He got away.
For he really hadn't stolen the things they
hart specified in the warrant.
"Those first weeks in the Tombs I can't
remember. It Is as though I had died,
and had come back to life. Or, as though
I had been In a long, deep sleep and awak
ened. That is about the way it feels to
come out of a trance after one has been
hynotized. It may be the reaction was so
terrible in my case because I was In a
continuous state of hypnotism.
"I shall do everything I can to aid the
Great Britain Rights Reserved.
rrTH -jEdr tfw r 'v x -v Jfcj, st kf
3f, 4i ''o' JK. .v .-&amp;
g3ftOflk
Miss McLeod as She Is Now, Freed from the Sinister Influence of
the Mind That Mastered Her.
police in his capture. He may try to re
gain possession of my soul. But he will
not. Not if I have to destroy this poor
shell that is its house!
"I thought I was fairly happy while I
was with this master of my will. But in
the tormenting weeks when I was pain
fully coming out from beneath his spell I
knew that I had been as wretched as a
doomed soul in hell. It is one of the
greatest of life's tragedies to lose control
of your will. When there is no free will
one is a prisoner, a prisoner of evil!"
This, the story she told a representative
of this newspaper, Is substantially the
story that convinced Judge Cairns.
Dr. Perry Lichtenstein, the Tombs phy
sician, testified before the court:
"She seemed to talk as though things
were at a long distance, as if she could
not grasp the subject. She was unable to
keep up a conversation long at a time and -would
look off into space at that time.
"I do not believe that at the time she
committed the act, nor at the time she
came to the City Prison, she knew the na
ture nor quality of her act; She may have
known that she was writing. She may
have known that she gave her name, or
put somebody else's name on the back of
that check, but she did not realize the na
ture nor quality of her act. That is, she
did not know that she was doing wrong.
My opinion is that while she committed
the act and for two weeks afterward she
was irresponsible."
Tas Tombs had never swung back its
iron gates to admit a more pitiable pris
oner. "She lived and acted and talked like
some one who was far away," said Mrs.
Helen Timko, the kindly Investigator for
the Voluntary Defenders Committee. "If
ever a girl was under hypnotic spell it was
she. She was wholly irresponsible.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1921-01-11/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;
q=hypnosis+hypnot+HYPNOTIZED/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PROFESSOR IS SHOT
BY HYPNOTIZED GIRL
By Carl D. Groat.
(United Press Correspondent)
Berlin. (By Mail).The danger
that amateur hypnotists will further
impair public morals i3 seen by the
Vienna ^feddcal weekly, in a discus
scion of the* recent attack on Prof.
Wagner-Juaregg, Vienna, by a hyp
notized girl.
Jauregg bad asserted that crime
could not be induced by hypnosis
whereupon an amateur hypnotist sug
gested to a seventeen-year old girl the
asrassination of the professor and
provided her with a pistol loaded
with paper bullets. She made the at
tack. The medical journal, however,
contends that Juaregg*s theory was
not entirely disproved since the hyp
notist induced the attack under false
premises and suggested to his sub
ject that the whole affair was harm
lessas it was. Hence it was not a
crime.
But, the paper contends that the
amateur hypnotists can perhaps
spread a suggestion among the public
for disruption of the whole process
of criminal justice. If sqch a process
were undertaken, then there would
be no need for "compulsory hypnosis"
as in the Jauregg case, in order to
establish a plea for light punishment,
since the public would not require
punishment. Incidentally, the paper
sayi there have been cases in the
past of "compulsory (or intentional)
drunkenness," undertaken as a basis
for a plea to escape justice
The Jauregg case has* aroused the
Interest of psychologists and hypnot
ists thruout central Europe. Since
the attack, the girl has been the sub
ject of experiments which revealed
the process to which she was sub
mitted in the course of the amateur's
efforts to disprove the expert's theory.
Under hypnosis, she revealed that the
CHIROPRACTIC
Consists Entirely of Relieving Pressure on the
Nerves at the Point Where They Leave tjie Soine
DO CHIROPRACTORS BELIEVE IN GERMS?
germs exist is certain knowledge, but that they are the cause of disease is quite
a different statement.
The three distinct theories of disease, viz.: Chiropractic, germ and bio-chemjc
are mutually exclusive. They may all be wrong, but'the^y cannot all be right.
The germ theory waB promulgated by a German, Dr. Koch, in 1882, and is by
no means generally accepted by medical men or scientists. In fact, some of its strong-
est opponents are medical men who marshal the most incontrovertible facts with un-
assailable logic, while'the great general public have for centuries lived, laughed, and
loved in perfect ignorance and disregard of theory.
It is the dictum of science that we live in a sea of life and that in every drop of
water, in every breath of air and every bite of food there are myriads of germs.
If germs cause disease, it follows that the introduction of germs into the living
organism would produce disease in every case.
instances that prove this untrue are so legion that the germ theorists have
been compelled to explain that the germs are impotent UNLESS THE POWER
OF RESISTANCE OF THE PATIENT IS SUBNORMAL. For instance, some people
cannot be successfully vaccinated while others are so successfully vaccinated that
they die. "Germ Theorists" explain the susceptibility of the patient is the measure of
his power of resistance.
Power of resistance may be measured in terms of life current or vitality. The
stronger the life current the greater the resistance and vice versa, the weaker the life
current the weaker the resistance. So we may conclude that where 100 per cent of life
current, or vitality, exists the susceptibility is zero, and where 50 per cent qxists the re-
sistance is small and the susceptibility correspondingly great.
It requires but little reasoning from these facts to conclude that those who
contract typhoid, for instance, owe their susceptibility to a lack Of vital force in the
bowels, and those who contract tuberculosis, pneumonia, etc., to a lack of resistance
in the lung tissue, and so on through the entire list of germ diseases.
HIROHtAdTiC goes several links farther back in theNshain of cause and effect Whilei the gertn
theoriste stop at the susceptibility of the patient, the Chiropractor says that susceptibility Is the
result of Utfk of vital power, or mental impulses, due to pressure on a nerve caused by a mis-
aligned vertebra and that when the vertebra is adjusted the normal power will again.flow over the
nerve, the affected parts will again become normal and the disease germs and every other incidental
effect will disappear.
No clearer demonstration tof the relative merits of antipodal theories could be given than that
furnished by the statistics of the recent "flu" epidemic in Iowa, where the death rate was as, follows:
Medically Treated, One Death Out of Every 16 Cases
Chiropractically Adjusted, One Death Outof Ev*ry886 Cases
These figures are at once a death blow to the germ theory and a wonderful recommendation
for Chiropractic.
DR. A. DANNENBERG
maSSn
*-wa*
THEBEMIDJI DAILY PIONEER
amateur had suggested to her that
Jauregg had killed her sweetheart
that she ought to take revenge and
that if she would do it, she could have
a theatrical engagement. She had
replied she disliked to kill Jauregg
and was afraid of -a* pistol, but later
she relaxed as the hypnotist assured
her it was harmless..
Jauregg holds that this statement
as to harmlesBneas robbed the action
of the actual criminal element, since
the subject was not actually commit
ting a crime.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025327/1963-11-15/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;
q=hypnosis</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Speaking o YOUR HEALTH...
ﬁypno;isy Is Not A Pa'rl.o.r Game
THE REAL impact of the
potential danger of hypnosis
wag dramatically brought to
the attention of the American
people recently.
A. 13-year-old high school stu
dent, along with several other
classmates, was hypnotized dur
fng a school assembly program.,
The demonstra~
tion was suce
_cessfully per
formed by an
amateur hypno
tist, using this
serious tech
nique with par
lor game £lip
poney -7 ‘T
E o o
‘m. Coleman Although he
was eble to lull
Ehozo students into hypnotio
france; one of them was unexs
ctedly projected into state
Emnu hysteria, She had to
admitted to a hospital
@here, under psyehiatric care,
&amp;
.wu treated and finally re
sed in good emotional cone
dition,
Potential Dangen: i
The reckless use of hypnosis
&amp;
8 a form of entertainment
should be forbidden. The po
tential dangers of hypnosis are
pot respected by those who use
¢his valuable medical tool only
&amp;
8 source of commercializa~
tion and entertainment.
Hypnosis has evolved from a
@tate of disrepute in the 18th
sentury to a position of yecog
@ized importance as an ac
eredited form of medical treat
tent,
For many gears, hypnosls
was performed withHout any
gigid medical controls. Enter
gmng showmen demonstrated
eir Svengaili and Rasputin
powers to enthralled gudiences
es night club act.
Use And Abus,
The use and abuss of hYpavsls
by those who have no veal
knowledge of its potency as a
psychological phenomenon has
@one this science a great in-
Justice,
Today physicians, psychia
trists and dentists have been
taught how to use hypnosis as
valuable addition to the treat
ment of physical and psycholog
1968, King Featw</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016244/1960-07-04/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;
q=hypnosis&amp;
r=-0.03,0.301,1.081,0.827,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Hypnosis Is Aid To Doctors
By ALTON BLAKESLEE
Associated Press Science Writer

The odds are good, and grow*:
ing, that your doctor will suggest
hypnotizing you as part of your I
medical treatment, or to aid in
surgery or childbirth.
Before you rear back in dismay, j
or start calling him a stagestruck
charlatan, consider current medi-(
cal facts and viewpoints on hyp
nosis.
Today at least 7,000 U.S. physi
cians and as many dentists are
actively using hypnosis, and many
are taking courses to learn how.(
Medical journals and speakers
increasingly report benefits from
hypnosis to kill pain in hopeless
cancer, or pain after surgery, as
an aid to breaking some bad
habits, or in losing weight, or in
having babies with less or some
times no anesthesia.
They also warn it’s no panacea,
that it has limitations and even
hazards if used unwisely.
Two years ago the American
Medical Assn, approved hypnosis
as an acceptable type of medical
treatment.
Hypnosis dates way back to ear
ly human times, and bears some
taint of theatrical magic since it's
often used to provide mystifying
and entertaining stage shows.
Nor is hypnosis news in medi
cine. It has waxed and waned be-'
fore in popularity. But in this lat-j
est revival, hypnosis is being
studied scientifically, to pin down
benefits and limitation*, and this
time it bids to stay.
Based on medical literature and
interviews, here are some ques
tions and answers concerning hyp-(
nosis in medicine:
Q: Exactly what is hypnosis’
A: There is no satisfactory def-'
inition yet, any more than there
are real definitions of sleep or
consciousness, says Dr. Lewis R.
jWolberg, New York psychiatrist,
who has employed hypnosis as
one technique of therapy for 20
years. Hypnosis lies somewhere
between sleep and wakefulness,
5— r
What’s Your Postal I. Q.?</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038485/1915-01-03/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;
q=hypnosis&amp;
r=0.324,0.787,0.754,0.577,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025840/1959-03-27/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;
q=hypnosis</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Doctor Performs Painless Childbirth
In Atlanta, Georgia a 24-ycar
old school teacher, Mrs. Myrtice
Ballard, preparing to have a sec.
ond child, expressed the desire to
be aware of what was going on
during the long tiring hours of
delivery. She states in an exclu
sive article in the April issue of
Ebony Magazine, “I felt I had
missed something.’’
Her physician, Dr. R. P. Jack
son, suggested that she submit to
hypnosis, since an increasing
number of physicians believe it
has marvelous potential in reliev
ing the pain of childbirth.
The Ebony article reveals the
entire process, showing the var
ious steps used by Dr. Jackson,
including the moment before de
livery, the complete delivery and
the awaking of the mother and
her first glimpse of the newborn.
Dr. Jackson reveals that there
are no dangers in using hypnosis
in childbirth, however, he does
concede that not all persons will
accept hypnosis; nor can all per
sons be hypnotized.
Although this was Mrs. Ballard’®
first hypnosis experience she
states that she doesn't plan tc
have any more children, but i f
she does she would prefer birth
by hypnosis.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068401/1934-08-23/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;
q=hypnosis</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Hypnotism Not All Humbug
But Is Real Trance State
By LOGAN CLENDENING, M. D.
A NUMBER OF inquiries about
hypnotism which have been coming
to this desk, indicate that interest in
the subject is re
vivinor TVir.,,
Dr. Clendening
viving. They can
perhaps best be
answered in the
form of a ques
tionnaire.
Is there such
a thing as hyp
notism or is it
humbug?
Certainly hyp
notism is real,
not humbug. A
trance state,
hypnosis, can be
Induced in near
ly any person,
the subject, by
any experienced
hypnotist (oper
ator).
What induces hypnotic trances?
Hie commonest method is by the
rhythmic stimulation of a single
sense—as the regular flashing of a
minor in the eyes, or the regular
sound of a melodious gong—with the
body lelaxed and the other senses at
rest.
In the recent revival of “The
Witching Hour'' on the screen, the
lawyer flashed his diamond studded
cilgaret case in the juryman's eyes
and so hypnotized him: This was
tin authentic' scene: The English
physician. Braid, used to induce
h\ pilosis by fixing his patient’s eyes
fill tile reflected light-from the sur
face of las lancet-ease.
Experienced .hypnotists have, how’-
Bver, abandoned these “mechanical”
methods, and rely largely on sugges
tion. The patient is convinced that
chs hypnotic state ts going to occur,
he sits in a risa.\ed condition, and
the operator strokes the skin of the
face a few times, suggests “Sleep”
in an earnest voice, with the desired
result.
Can a person be hypnotized
against hjs will?
Seldom, if ever. This idea, upon
which so manv stories, including
GOVERNOR pinchot inspects dam
hbsrfg -SHF WdMhfe J
BA
In dedicating the l’ymaiuning
reservoir, in western Pennsyl
vania, Gov. Gifford Pinchot
prophecies that its waters will bd
unexcelled for sportsmen. The
reservoir, which has 16,000 acres
in Pennsylvania, and 5,000 in
He Won’t Give Up His Dogs
Hill
Wfclfsre officials g» ve E rnest Booth, 72, of Saugus, Mass., the choice of
o'i.-rirt.v U p his four dogs or losing his weeldy state relief allowance,
wouldn’t go baea on me; I won’t go back on them,” he said,
choosing to them from being chloroformed.
Central Prpjit)
“Trilby” is based, is erroneous.
What percentage of people eannol
be hypnotized?
Much small"! than is generally
supposed. At. least 80 per cent oi
an average group are easily hypno
tized. Children are more easily
hypnotized than adults. The higher
the intelligence the more susceptible
the subject. The insane, idiots, im
beciles, morons and unintelligent
stupid people cannot be hypnotized.
Mild examples of mental derange
ment, such as melancholia, can, how
ever, be hypnotized.
What is tiie nature of the hypnotic
state?
Neither sleep nor waking. The
eyes are closed, the muscles often
stiffened, the subject responds to
questions sensibly, remembers much
ot events which belong to the wak
ing state, but almost never remem
bers what occurred during hypnosis.
What the state of the personality
is during hypnosis has never been
satisfactorily explained. I have
stated merely objective facts. The
essential character of the hypnotic
state is the subject’s far-reaching
power over his own organism. Will
is increased and the moral standard
raised.
Will a person perform an act sug
gested during the hypnotic state, at
a definite time after waking?
Yes. in HO per cent of instances
The French physician, Pelhoeuf. dis
covered this and employed it in
treatment One instance:
Mr. .1. hypnotized at tidto a m
Suggestion at the end of 30 hours
was to pull the cook’s nose. Result:
Suggestion carried out one hour too
soon.
Is a person who has been hypno
tized under the will of the operator
forever afterwards?
No, certainly not. Hypnosis can
not be induced at a distance—i e.,
in the absence of the operator Al
though self-hypnosis is frequently
performed by subjects who hav*
once been hypnotized.
Is hypnotism valuable in medi
cine? Is hypnotism dangerous?
These questions will be answered
in subsequent articles.</text>
      </result>
	  
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-oscar-wilde</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1881-07-31/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;
q=NEW+PUBLICATIONS+Oscar+Wilde&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=-0.1,0.313,0.822,0.629,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ESTHETIC POET.
tor.:-!.?'. I IB Wit' l6mo., pp. 2S0. Bo*ert?
Brothers.
A -.til?n" ?if Terses by (he le?atea brrtywlio
|g known to be (I af Dn Manner*?
end is m kB*
li.?'? g.0 IWen's Pat* L? entitled toa
kful notice, PoBtletiiwaite and Bnothorue
represent smnetbJng more than rndividoal in?
fcrieity. The anrniar asatl who lanshes npen mi
tenti mplatioti of lily?
a nost ialenar yonagmaa,
il yeti vinili:? man.
An ultra-poetical, siipenestliencn.
Oui u
Is Ina bj antan f aoeial disorder arbieh t'.
cvnic ami IBS leaghing philo t B?kS
may consider worthy ??f attention. Mr, Osear
Wilde v..:^ Bot ti?-? inventor ?>f the toluol witb
i his I M at all
|j tlrit Ii?? lias dono muob to pn
i;? u\., m?. Rebasan 11 that frivo?
luiis Been ?y arhieb runs nad after all the extrem?
es of pre-BaphaeHtiem .ml mi m all it? rath,
hat p he has had the daring to poab the attesta
Horn o? the nbool to a length which appears, per?
hapg "not BBprems, ani oh, ojnite too all-bnt
j aal, and the adroitnon t dieguisi bin
travesty t' ntthnslaen that It may pan with the
Bsaof taahionable enltnre tor the real thine*.
He la the product, In abort, of his environment, and
as eneh In- nay slain a atady arhieb wi should
n.-vci- Ihiuh in*keslowliig enonhnparaonnl achieve
UK-Ills.
I? .ii!?l lie iitnli-estooi!, liowcver, at the start
that Mr. Oscar Wilde is set an Idiot, as those who
know hi'ii only by Ilio berlesQUM of Panal and tli?
Gilbert ?nul Sullivan opera night believe. Than
is BOTOething in his verseci aid lie indulges mudi
less iu the jarttoii of the ?esthetes than in? ganan ai Ibelk'otherhood'who hive placed voi
gneeof poetry Bpoa Ihe world. H?. is noi oneoi
those who only despair droopingly, und ari limi?,
ami wnoeling] and it he hi
?fond lu stained glass all liudea,
?if he siiiil's Mi Unes ?rttfa asphodel, jacinth,
Beeaagraaatee, daffodilliea all in bloom, anoary
paarn, anrjr told, argent foreheads, sapphire.
violet, vermilion, azure, tnuuiihoo 1, paniOB
ato NaMaead. high-tunn-cd limbs, Ana iv.
amorous pieasaunoe. Usen on th mouth,
tlip Barrlatagaahii na, nrieked shepherds,
end eiii'xry, unii paleta I lily m limos' e\ery third
??r I'ourth stanza, i? musi ;?.iknos 1??Aged that his
far-fet?'hed words n re iisuilly atgeinenatj and lint
the}' are eonh?nedwith a ?In?- regard lo asme?
thing like aenas. Mr, Wilde baa, appar
en fly, neghi to Y hot h ih?? m-iisii
ous charm of Keats and the sensuality
of Swinburne. Of Ihe l;ti poet he leeoeed? in
aaeUngj ea far na ene of hii eharacteristios is oon
rticd, a sl.-utlinu copy an of the Other he pio?
tine? s a eroi ttkin^ travesty. LikeBenthome, be is "a
fleshly ptxt," rather than an idyllic ami like Hun
tliortic, h" n? ver tires of bidding OS remark the hor?
rors of hie tortur.-'l in-i?'??. He assures Ofl th it In has
surrendered himself to sweet Bad sins," end that be
?writes for thon wh-> have feasted as he basen the joys
tliat kill. H?- would not have rained then Joys for
aacrthing. He is desperately wicked, in an amorona
way, and he thinks it ig note thin probable that be
lias lost his s..ni, which anjees hi',? particularly pic
tur?'s|iie, ami after all ?Iocs not much natter to ?ni?
who can ??in nie himself by fondling a lily. "Oh!"
i-xclaiius Banthorne in th? (day, Ih, 1 an enrsed
thin?.'' And h- adda, Doa*1 be frightened it's only
poetry." With Mr. Wilds, too, it's only poetry.
His volumi? apena with a sort of prelude in italic
type, entitle?! Helas!" ami beginning with the fol?
lowing lines:
Te drift with every penice till my so:i1
Is a strinse?! luit- on which all winds can play,
1* il fin tiii-tint: I Inr.t away
Mine alien ut wisdom ami au-teie control
Tins indicates the sens?- in which he Trisan |Q be
taken,?as a poet umlei? tin- sway of treni? 1" is
eiu'-tioas, alwajn spoiiiaiieous an l aeoereJIy ?ui
BBjsanri and in earrjing ont Ins idea he b careful to
commit hine H to the most contradictory Beati?
incuts. Hilton ami Swinburne, Cromwell, the
"divine" William Morris, Napoleon IV., th?? men
of tin- berrieadee, Pius ix. end Diana, an bjr
turns the snbjecti of his paarirrnatr eulogy.
Tlirouiili on?: whole division of his book he in a
HU|M-rheatc?l Caiholie, and a few ininui.s
later he is the m. ut. in?lau?cd of Mas
ziuiuns. H?? is a puithci.-t. He is a pagan,
He worship-* humanity. Be worships the h?hi1 of
the aadveree. Be worship? Ihe Saints Re worships
aha grand white feet of .j mm ami tin- argent splen
dor of hit?? limits of the other divinities of koine.
He would be the Piccadilly Tannhuiver who has
tarried in the Yeiinsberg, and has knelt at the
?hriii?' of tin- Madonna, ami who break? in Bpou the
pure ?haut of the minstrels with arlad SOBgS of fever?
ish delight?
A liciti- profilier of peat mysteries,
Au .inlcni ?tliiol'olis liiiii ?1,
"The New Ht ?en,''on?? gf the poems which he
prints und? r the tft-iu-ial title of "liosa Mystica,"
ia a remai kahle specimen of his audacity in min
ajhnjth? aaeade devotional with the paeudo-erotio.
Hut then- is Ba> reality IB it. Wts cannot help pul
tiiiir into Mr. Wilde's mouth the famous words of
the Fat Boy, 1 nanti to make your l]?'s]i creep." It
isso intircstiii!/ to he arleked il is a mark of such
ram ?-ultiire to he on inlin ii terms with l'an and
Aphrodite, and Faene and Dryade ansila celebrata
the ?m? ?eut rites in Nuiicliaui Wood mid on the
bosky banks of Thames; it so pniues feminine cu
no.sity to tleclare that you will
-walk frotn lire unto tire,
From pnssaasespatati eeaaftBaweengkt,
without explaining piecisclv what it is you mean to
do.
Ami everyone will ?ay, a? you walk your mystic way,
If this young m,? a expresen linnself in terms too tleep
for nu?,
Why, erbai a very aaagatar, dsep yeeag man this deep
youiitf man must lel
We cannot timi a note of true A'elinjr in Mr.
Wilde's hook, from the first pagarte the last. We
cannot believe liwn w In n he boasts of his -reepublican, nor when he assures Liberty, in a sonnet,
that he loves her only because her reign? of terror,
her ?reat anarchies, and the roar of ln-r ?leinocra
ciee, mirror his wildest passions and (??ve hi.s
rage a brother. We do not Ix-liev?? that h?- has any
wild passions, or any rages, or any lixe?l beliefs. We
do not even trust the silicei it of his asthelic pro
fossions. There is no true ring in these verses:
epirii of Beaut) tarry still while.
?'??-y are not tieinl, tlnnc amieiit votaries,
Rome few there ure t?t whon thv riiillant smile
Is better thnu a thoiisani liefur:???,
Thouirli all tic noltly slalll of Waterloo
Klst? up in wrath ?gainst them tarry still, th?rc arc
a lew.
Who for thy sake would give their ruunl?iooil
consc? rate Un ir being, 1 at least
Have done so, made thy lips my dally food,
And in thy temples found a goodlier ft as:
Than thin starvisl age rim inv?? ine, spile of all
Its itew-fotiutl creeds so u-cptical ami so dogiiiatlcal
We laugh when Mr. Wilde describes himself as
tho last Emlymiou," ami do we lutigli when ho
exhorte his aonl to get out of th? degenerate island
of Butani
O come out of it,
Come out of it, my Soul, thou art nut tit
For tin? vile trsttic-liouse, wlu-re day l?y day
Wisdom am', p \en me are avid at man,
And tin- rude pasple raga ?'im ignorant crics
Against au hell of en tunes.
ft mars ray caini wh.-refore in dreams of Art
And lofti-st ?nil ure I would stand apart,
Neither for i.txl, uor fur his t-ucmlcs.
Far from drifting with every passion" ho ?loca
nothing; but strike attitudes and compose aBBBaiggg
en familiar poetical themes. His stmlics arc often
quite siio.ssfid inform, in ihvtlim, iu ricliiiess of
diction, in felicity of metapbor?, and in the simula?
tion of emotional expreaamn but tiiey are cutindy
voul of aentiimnt, ami oficu. where feeling must
haveshowu iteelf if the writer had capable of
it, they are perfectly inane. In justification of this
judgment we may rt-fer the r?>nder to the BBBBasI of a
brace 'of piece? entitled Her Video and My
Voice. No one can rea?! that flat and placid plaint
of a aUasaiAed lover without perceiving that Mr.
Oscar Wilde U not a poet.
We have said, however, that there is something
in hie venes. If not [toctry, what aro tln-y They
are pretty good amides of a sort of ?lecorativo art.
Luscious epithets and archaic nouns are joined, in
long-drawn sentences chiefly descriptive we have
?aarhed ani meh awntenee BO? no fewer whan
thirteen a_?tine etanaaei and the efleel i*
thut of it li.'.riiton.s in gergOOei IHK-'. Tin?
a i> enormously overloaded with similis;
?p ace escori are drawn with a
.me fulness ?if detail] wliieli
profess to deal with th,? tragedy of ptattoB
are In ?act priaoinally eonoerned with lower? and
trees and the oolor nf bare legt j bnt llr. Wilde uu
?tersi.'uiils th decorativi uses of word? le? is H'o an
artist who sets a brilliant palette, without havtng
?m Id? o to tr:? oafei t.> canvass, l ta styl?e tevereJ of
hiepieeee"impressionsM: one is harmony,0 a
mi re -tn iv in gold and red, having no mot mean
rag than the bai.onerata of colors and meet of
he others are labelled in Pre?en, or Latio, or
Greek, in order to heighten their effect, Just
at the of piotare is modified by th" frame.
Often, however, Mr. Wilde fails even in the ari of
ornament; this the eaee when he In?
dulge? in all i 1 i-i t i m
Sweet, 1 Mame yon not, for mtne the hrnlt was, bad
nut Ii tutu iineli?ub ?1 j seen the
fuller air, the larger day.
Proni the artldnessof my wasted pesalon l had struck a
i.ei ?er. clearer toosT,
i.it tome li?-' of freer freedom, batti dwlth
some n..(?..?-'.H'Miieii wrong.
His rbymee are torn itimee fais his quantities are
uncertain, bis rhythm, general!. Suent, bocoin tot>
oasionally insufterable. One of hit favorite word?
is pavilion," and he invariably gives 11 nearly tbe
Frenchsonndof pavilion, with tin- tirona accent
?m (li?.? Urei s.\ liable and ;i weak eoceni on the Lati
-the ?luff.?Ill,
That love child ol the apriag,
Das linger???! nn
To vex tlie roai u i?i jealousy,
Ami siili
Tin? harebell aproada ber azure pevittou,
We haremerlced eveinetaBoet this license.
Tu the following extracl there are linea whleh any
bo is requested to semi who may feel equal to that
exercise
?nil surely thta were governenee
Of Life In 'n?1 t angoet oninl'treionoe,
nroTurh whteh the rational mtelleol would Und
In pass! iu Its xpri selon, and inere sen ic,
ignoble el lend tin? to tin? mind,
\n beine lolite?! with ?a harmony
alore ug anca] than that which binila tbe ?tare planetary.
doubt whether we can give a better ideaof
Mr. Wilde*? eharacterittice, the art, meh at it is, of
his etyle, and the beggarly poverty of hkthoagbt,
than by quoting two of hit thorter poemi
rjoPBKeeioN do maun.
Tin- Thamea nocturne .>f blm and !-rlChanged to a Hannoni In ?rray
A barge with ?xthre-eolorod hay
Drop! from the wharf and ohtU aad eoM
The ellow tog earae cr?ente j down
liie bridges, till lite houses' wall
s. 'niel euamreil to shadows, and St ?'.oil's
Loomed tike a bubble o'er the town.
Then suddenly arose the clang
of wakiu life; the street? were stirred
With country wagons; and a bird
new to tii?? guateuina roots and tang.
ll'lt nne ii i'e woman til alone,
Tlie da) II l.i ki? in.- h? r wan hair,
Loitered boneath io tua lamps Dare.
With Upa ol mm .uni he uri itone?
THEOCRITUS.
VIl.l.iM I.I t,
O Singer of Peraenhonel
in be .ii"i menaow? d?eol ite
Unni remember i. Uy
BtfU three r* the Ivy nit- the bee
Wllere li?i li. 1? si ule;
C) Hin,Bhaetths oalli on Hecate
and be ut the wild do ra b1 the gal
Doti thon remember>.??i>
siili by the Ughi and langhin
Potvpbemc bemoaus ins tate;
ti Stager ol Pcreephoael
Ami still in boyish rivalry
Tonna Daphnie challenges hit mate:
Dost Hum reineiubci Sleilj t
Mini r.?ieini keeps a u'o.it I"'"' thee,
Por tin e the I ^?i iphefda \v:iit,
Singer of Persephone
Host thou remember Bielly i
Nothing could he atora fatile than tenet pieeee
considered as poetry. Neither of enea eonteini an
l?lea. Their merit lies merely in the ?h'tt expres?
sion of a OBoee of the pletoreeane. Yet ii" they are
empty, they are al Leael trm?. They may ttand for
Mi. Otear Wilde'? best work. The "wild, weird,
fleshly things,'' in which he rails at Qod, and Pate,
ami Life, and weens for dead .1 iighl end tells his
paxamoar why the Jacinth weart eueh dread am?
broidery i doloront moan," and guivert m ith the
icrime," and aatnree uh that be is going to hell, are
really nothing ant halcyon ?in.I roeiferona pro?
eeeditnrs." 
</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064205/1887-06-29/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;
q=hypnosis+HYPNOTIC+hypnotic+hypnotism+hypnotized&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=0.01,0.167,1.138,0.871,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WHO IS OSCAR WILDE?
England is in the delirium of the esthetic
fever. It haa not to a daDgeroualy marked
degree been apparent in this country,
though there are signs of ita increasing
temperature even here. But in England
it is a raging fever, a feticism, and has
there one chief and grand high priest,
whose mission ia to elevate this worship to
ita loftiest standard.
He is the second son of the late Sir Wm,
Wilde of Dublin, and his name is Oicar.
His father was a distinguished oculist
and devoted arcb;t'ologist an antiquarian
widely known as such in his own country.
But ho was a wild fellow in fact as in
name, eccentric in personal manner and
appearance, rakish in habit, and bad
enough of scandal attached to him con
cerning women to make him famous in
society. His wife, a beautiful and talented
woman, wrote volumes of poetry and fic
tion. Of such a pair was born Oscar, who
has attained to the title "The Apostle of
the Esthetes." Now, what is it that he
advocates, and why is it that hi 3 name is
in all mouths in I'2ngland, and that the
sentimental and floridly artistic people of
America are reading and sighing over every
line that flows from hia pen
In the first place, Oscar wears his hair
at great length, and it sweeps a broad and
furred collar that well- Pressed men cannot
afford to wear. These speak doubtless of
the poetry and romance of his mother and
the eccentricity of his father. In the next
placa, though not yet 30, he has taken
warning by the follies of hia sire, and is
reasonably correct, which so surprises the
aristocracy that they are lost in admiration
at his exceptionally virtuous example.
In the next place he has real talent, ia a
good classical scholar, was a close student
at Trinity and Enniskillen, and haa been
successful without being brilliant as a
writer in London papers, lie is of a
poetical temperament, and won the New
degate prize for English verse. But he
has a creed, wherein his weakness resides,
and it is expressed in one word, esthetic.
The esthetic has its place, but too much
of it is like too much water in soup, and
Wilde is an exponent of too much water.
That the people should be cultivated to
higher and better views of art should be
brought into closer communion with the
beautiful in nature and art and to a clearer
appreciation of the best there is iv both, is
deairable but it is better that they should
know nothing of either than to grow maud
lin over it. Wilde aud his followers wor
ship the old the ancient is the idol of the
esthetes the modern is to them an of
fense they seek for the beautiful in that
longing, mystical and mysterious way that
results in nothing and leaves the searcher
wholly unsatisfied. They live upon hopes,
aspirations and desires, and dwell upon the
border land of a realm not to be approached
by common mortals. They talk of art
with a wealth of language, aud a famine of
thought. They are of those who are filled
with "gearchingsaftrr the infinite, longings
"after the unfathomable, but who regard it
"as vulgar to pay their debts." They go into
raptures over an ancient vase, a quaint bit
of table ware, or the harsh and angular
outlines of Japanese tracery, but are blind
to the beauty and worth that reside in the
master strokes of the strong arm of the
marine engine, or the wondrous grandeur
of the modern triphammer, which may
graze a feather or fashion a rail to bear tho
wheels of commerce.
Ojcar Wilde and his followers bend in
esthetic rapture over a human and heathen
production which to them it would be pro
fane to criticise in language that the aver
age people of the age can understand, and
concerning which their ctitics wander away
in tho mazy miata of expression that is
a pitiful groping in the dark for something
—they kr.o^ not what. They are the
"too too," tho utterly "too too," the
very very kind of people, who dream
over the impossible, acd arc altogether
too fragile for strong thoughts, vig
orous ideas and hearty expression.
Ot this class of people are the
young men whose locks polish their coat
collars, and maidens whose waists approach
their arm-pits in the effort to appear artis
tic Of this class of people are those who
cannot find in homely English a tit medium
for the expression of their thoughts. Of
thiß class of beings are those who are ever
searching for the beautiful, but who never
rind it who have their eyes set so far
above the common things of life that they
stumble over the deairable realities and
necessities of the present.
And of these Oscar Wilde is one of the
leaders indeed, the head and front. In
auch as he, and those of his school, the
esthetic taste is perverted, the true love
of art profaned and the aspirations tor the
beautiful reduced to sickly sentimentality.
The teachings of his school have invaded
the household, and turned the domestic
hearth into a cariosity shop have
driven out in many cases the cultured
taste for adornment, and substituted
an abnormal desire for the strange
and fanciful. And so the esthetic have
come to be real stumbling-blocks
to art progress, and a recent critical jjur
nal, The Hour, is led to question whether
this, their ohief apostle, is most knave or
most fool, for it ha does not believe iv
the tenets of his creed he must be a
"knave, and if he does, people of healthy
"minds and bodies can scarcely under
"stand a strong or strapping young man
"lusciously lunchiDg upon a lank, lean
"lily, or finding his greatest delight in the
"contemplation of a ten-mark teapot."
We would not be understood as depre
cating the taste which searches all the
world for the best, and plucks from the
past all that is pure and beautiful and
good all that will adorn, beautify and
elevate but we do condemn the perverted
taste that just now seems to be the chief
one esthetes possess, which riads oaly
beauty in the old, only grace in ths an
cient, only true art in the work of departed
ages only the grand in the decayed past,
only the best in the accomplishments of
the dead and g»no masters and we do
hold that the present lias quit-? a-i much in
it to excite tho love for the beautiful, to
elevate the tastes, to refine the sentiments,
to enoble the character, to quicken the
imagination, and to make it, to the earnest
lover of the true and good, an age of
beauty, grace and woudious accomplish
ment.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1882-01-01/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=OSCAR+WILDIS&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=0.611,0.029,0.42,0.321,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>OSCAR WILDIS 47eV W1JJCTICIEJ
Oscar Wilds who is expected hero within a
i1y or two Iq known In this country its one ti the most
Ointment tIuSCIPICI of zsthcttcistn Yet the generel
opinion of him anti ot timo cause whtcli ho e4reeeumto
h3 not been krmnmii by our acleal excutenco or tlicw
but rather by the amnuimng seuires on their tiorrnIiofl
1iieIi rein thuS to time Imate aiptrctt in reh Time
poet flitiring lii them stitires Yei cne Mnuttle who coolS
atter time cults begen wits sld to be eo other tlmOfl ttio
young Irish poet Ocar vtii lie wee ins Ic to tuiiTer
for soue of imli 1imtIfareet roiionrs hums II w a soil
timotime sat tip all imiglit mti a lily themi Pta woe repre
centem sittinc up all iitImi with s minllowar nnI tinaliy
53 going to E4oi itrmeima to ill imp elm niht tmth CII ctel
reIs Thus Aunerias first impteseinno toor Imot 01 the
te1 Oscar S Iile snl t time rool ethotlcIm but itt 511dm
tin motor VIlio ent elIcit tlmettcism as Do
inmluating sorceelmi prmittei ii 10 see
Time pubitcatlitu best mlmmer of ii ultimne o the Ol1fl
poets writIngs Sil umucli to disrcl tiitC I tmreikns A
wrttcr lii Time 5ie in oteekilm t time iocile Collie tilmie
ago mI
tAke a trims poet Mr Wills Is net Ilteeiie Tie iti op
porsimtly no ii 0151 bI tat pitt I 01 her tit i ii tim imi ii I k
ile th it bee it c wit etiir I a nit or nattIEr m ii iin IiS
lorin or In the iIl ii isralnoint to oil uitOterlii iint that
ft network or rsiltoiIs Aimi cii lisp lcvic q n
do not neceuortly lieu litCil on iii true iIamtIoilIt 5 must
iotlo hoC CtC ore mire t bs P51701 tim au 10011S rttctmrfro
Uiimt tterc is that lii time vorbI which is Letter 01111 g0id
Miii better than
Plie Iinurv that
liii base Inercimoll us ti1e tin lbs eie
Vliero noble tliotliuito aliti Utct1 smould enter ty
Agatni
One o tr wmutmeo most sttllclna chmtraeiritics I tile
53nhl silty with Ititmire Iii e Ii lmmr litomit t ii I its tutuS
eiiigist anti has limo ebility to uimnic pastoral ptdturea
that are genis orate
The mestheticisin oC Oscar wmlle me IfltdllCi to t C time
Imparting of beauty to everyday eimrrotindirms oft time
worhim in yere of benmmty ethertat or lncnrnt It
nmesna beauty In drece beauty irs decoration beauty cml
IlllpiICitT in langnoze it return frosts the tittiltam Iztn to
time epiritmiat Colne or Mr ViIles folioners exacter
sled the practice or liti timeortes Iii their pursutt ut
lmpltctty tiiC strippeml btauti ci it ctiurniiteumts nuti
then raved ocertts relnnante They wormlpmc4 llttt
ever wits sntmrpic wlietimeriteautiliit or flee They offct
ed a certtn return to Suture cmi in doing Co become
most unnatural mrons time musts of tlmi clam Gilbert
drew itt flmforne tromis time women his ha it Jne just
C flu Mcnrter lieU found amonz them liii ifoi11o cnj
ifi float ZLoun
Mr Vi1Ic wmmm coon appear here In public to tiefemi mile
fttth lie aso brings with him poem In mnuscrmpt cmi
a play Vera the mhittst itiieli he hope to produce</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1882-01-04/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=Qicar+Wilde&amp;
st=image&amp;
r=-0.343,-0.084,1.685,1.685,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>I Qicar Wilde
I New York 2A chilled crowd of
aesthetic human beings beat their
hands and stamped their feet on the
dock this morning while waiting
for the Arizona on which was their
apostle Oscar Wilde The big ship
stuck fast Gn a bank of mud 200 feet I
from the dock tugs pushed and
pulled the Arizonas engines worked
vigorously but mud was victor for
a time While the fight between
steam and mud was in progress the
shivering mass of humanity I
greeted with round after round
of applause the towering form on
the Arizonas deck It was of a I
man jeuthful In appearance He i
stood six feet four inches he has a
smooth face and longflowing locks I
an overcoat of bottlegreen cloth
a furlined and fur collar seal skin
cap and yellow kid gloves made the
man more conspicuous It was
Oscar Wilde poet and jouaialist
I am here to greet lecture and see
the country he said with a hearty
laugh Will I stay long Really
I cant say It depends on circum
stances My felow voyagers have
given me such glowing description
of the country 1 am in also I will I
see what there is in your great me
tropolis and the far west has at
tractions unless it is misrepre I
sented that I must witness and 1
am anxious to see something of
Mexico Lighting a fresh cigar
ette Mr Wilde continued Al
ready I have experienced some
thing of American courtesy I was
26 last October I shall remain
long enough to see what there is
worth seeing in America</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024738/1882-01-11/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=Oaear+Wild+Wilde&amp;
r=-0.257,0.837,0.639,0.489,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Oaear Wild., the tit lu te.
int- THEORIES, WRITINGS, ANT) PERSONAL
APPEARANCE.
As already announced. Oscar Wilde, the
poet, apostle, and high-priest of eetheti
cism, has arrived in New York from lang?
land, and UM world of fashion and letters,
which indulges in thc strange s|x>rt of lion
hunting, has since had ample Opportunity
to gratify it- weakness. Tho-, who had
only known Mr. Wilde through Dr. Man?
ner's caricature of Maudie, or Gilbert's
character of Bunthorne, were no doubt
disappointed at not seeing him walk down
Broadway pressing g lily to hts breast- but
this was compensated for by meeting a
young man with B*Te0IBt1cBR and peculiar!
tit-, and yet at thc same time with fresh
and Vivid ideas un art, keen iMTceptious.
and brilliant social qualities
Mr. Wilde was born in Dublin, and ls
twenty-six years old. His father was Sir
William Wiide, a celebrated phyttcbrn,and
his mother a woman of much poetical talent.
After securing high honors at Trinity Col?
lege, Dublin, young Wilde went to Mag?
dalen College, Oxford, anti graduated there?
from in 187s;. The acquaintance which In?
formed then- with John Ruskin undoubt?
edly gave color to Ids after life and
thought, and a subsequent visit to Italy
and Greece served to deepen his impres?
sions on art and beauty. since that linn?
he ha* published a number of sonnets and
translations from Greek ?TOgedieO. The j
idea nuning through ail ins poems seems tn
bc that beauty is above namiiiallsiii that
dowers an- better then factories, and hat
the hum of the bec and the murmur of the
brook nrc swelter than the clang of the
hammer and the whirl of tho spindle, lt
was a bold thought to try and IntUM suth
an Idea into thc brain of tbi- practical age.
and when Hie young enthusiast's devotees
In attempting to follow him never rose
above the lei el of a craze for blip- china I
and cracked teacups of UM reign of tineen
Anne, ur a rhapsody over a lily or BSUR
losror, then- wa- little wonder thal al
grotesque side of the subject was at once
eefand upon, and that he and his
theories were everywhere burlesqued, j
Mr. Wilde himself "admits that he and;
his companions al Brat went to Hr
Wildest extremes ii. dnss and cxpre?ions.
He SHIRR that thc groundwork of c-theti
ORRS ii that a knowledge of the beautiful
cannot he taught, hut must be personal,j
and can univ bc acquired by one's own eyes
and ears. The real Strength ?'f HM I Sthetk
movement, he thinks, [les in UM great
strength of beautiful design- ain-nig bandi- j.
craftsmen of the various eMfea, and he is of;
opinion that among women csjH-.-iallv I I
tlnr is a di-tinct tendencv towards the
Riost radical change, both "in the form of
tho dress and In thc introduition of
novel and beautiful colors. He con?
siders tliat at present velvet ls the most
beautiful drees for a man, and as a rule
wears gray or brown velvet himself. He
ls over six feet in height, with a full white
neck, ina.?ive face, prominent chin, rather
tun*lions lip*, mid blue eyes, the beardie*,
coiintemiriic being framtd in longbrowo
hair, part" d in the middle and loosed back?
ward (vr his shoulders. li-dtiiaore Sun.
RIB riBST I.KCTT'KK ft; ARRRBGAs
Oscar Wilde lectured Monday night {og
Large and fa-hiui)able audience af bicker
Baa Hall, lb Was drewsed in a black dress
coat, while Psst, an CXtriHIell loW-CUt
shirt, with flowing white silk cravat, black
Kia, H chose aa his subject "The
igiiah Rennalstance," which, he said,
w.y? til' ;?--'me of art, and all teachings
would amount to nothing if thc workmen
were not -1wounded by beautiful things, I
lor ll tlicj did not see them they could not
make thorn. Art should not lie, as lu the
past, onlf a contrast with snrrounrlinK
iniieiy. In eoiuhuion, BC ?ald: "iou
have all heard of those two flowers dear to
the i*tbrie's heart, the roar and the lily.
But wo do not love Mien for thc reason
elven bv Mr. Oilliert, nor for any voiretn
hle pretorenro, but U-cati^c they ure the
most perfect specimens of denten?the rose
with lt* leonine beauty, and the lily the
emblem of rhastitv and parity. Then,
why look further for the secret of life,
when thcieeret of life ts art r"</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053573/1882-01-20/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WILDE OSOAR,
THE LOVEH OPTHEDIG SUNFLOWER.
Ills Arrival at the Capital of the Greatest Coontry
en Ksrth, With Mllf., Wax.Caadles.Knre.
Breeches, Pamps, and Fur-
fotlj Long llalr.
Mr. Oscar Wilde, the exponent of teslhotlclsm,
arrived In Washington yesterday afternoon and
took rooms nt the Arlington. When It becamo
dark ho declined to uso tho gas, hut ordered wax
candles, aud then ho appeared contented, as ho
sat smoking a clgarctto lu a short embroidered
Jacket, with ruby silk cuffs and facings, and
wcnrlng kneo breeches and black silk stock
ings, with low. cut patent leather shoes, lied
by wide silk ribbons. His lower Jaws aro
strongly developed, but ho has n flue, broad
brow. Tho eyes are blue, and, like all his fea
tures, are large. His long brown hair Is carelessly
parted In tho centra of tho forehead, and allowed
to fall lu disorder over his lennlno neck and
Hyronlc shirt-collar. This collar Is cut low, and
brought together by n wldo white sntln lie. Ho Is
over six reel hlgli.nnd well proportioned. An ob
server, Judging by his npiicarnnce, would tnko
him tn bo ubiuit thirty years old. Ills manner Is
quiet, nud he has tho habit or leaning his head
upnn his arm, nnd or placing one nrm nklmbo,
wllh his hand at tho side, which Is ono or tho
positions In tho opera or "Patience." Hoal'n, In
a seemingly natural manner, crooks his right knee
when standing, which Is one or Iho "Pallcnco"
poses.
"the ritiLosoriiY or xsmmcivt,"
said Mr. Wilde, In conversation, "Is that tlio so
rrel oronjoyment In llfo Is lo be able to under
stand nnd apprcclato tho beautiful. Peopla crosi
continents lo sco a lake or a mountain or a water
fall, whllo tho simple creatures who llvo about
thcso scenes aro nolo to discern only earth and
water. Tho four great poets or tho early part or
this century Wordsworth, Shelley, Kcat, and
llyron wcro grossly misunderstood In their lire
time by tha Hrltish pnbllc, sn much sn Hint ono
was driven to the Cumberland wlldsnnd the others
to foreign graves. Kven to-day tho masses ol Uio
people, owing to their groveling und unbcautllul
surroundings, nro not able to apprcclato
tho poets. 1 would llko to sco every one
nblo to apprcclato Iho artistic quality or the
simplest thing around them and thus learn or
higher things limn inoney-gettlng, Mygrcntot
object In visiting this country Is to sco what effect
thcso Ideas will have upon an unprejudiced pcoplo
who arc not wedded to old conventionalism. I de
slro particularly to urge the Importance or lending
children to estlmalo tho beautiful, and teaching
them to uso their eyes aud cars nnd bauds. I
would have Americans mnkofor themselves Iho
linmtlftil objects they bring from tho older world.
The key-note of I his ago 1 discontent. People arc
not salf-flcd becauso they do not enjoy lire, nnd lo
enjoy lire they must bo nblo to undcrstuiid thu
licniilirul In tho simplest things. The ladlcaaro
taking the right step lu tho dccoralloii or their
homes and In Ihu draperies or Ihelr persons; but
the men will bo slow In receiving Impressions. I
do not believe lu making society n fancy ball but
I see no reason why men should not wear brown
or black clct Instead of cloth, nor do I sco why
knee-breeches nru not more becoming and dig
nified than tho ridiculous trousers which men ad
hero to."</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053573/1882-01-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025287/1882-03-17/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde&amp;
r=0.325,0.84,0.5,0.383,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>OSC AH WILDE.
The Appearance of Utterly Too Too, All
But, Last Evening
Cjuitc a large audience assembled at the
Opera house last night to listen to the apostle
of rcstheticieni. It is probable that the larger
portion were attracted by curiosity rather than
any idea of ali terary feast. Oscar made bis ap
pearance upon the stage withopt introduction.
He was dressed in purple silk velvet, wide
sleeves, cut away coat and kuee breeches. One
hand was encased in a white kid glove and
the other sported a lace handkerchief.
A long lace neck tie, with bow in
front, encircled his neck. His hair was
parted in the middle hung down upon|his coat
collar, even partly covering his cheeks and
completely concealing h s ears. His eyes had
a dreamy, languid look and as he commenced
his lecture he had the general "Aw, this ie a
dweadfultwiresomc country^ 1 air.
His style of delivery was merely a plain sort
of talk. He had a roll of manuscaipt, which
he occasioaally took in his hand, but spoke
without referring to it. There was almost no
gesticulation beyond fumbling with
his watch seal, which was evidenly less ex
haustive than more violent motions.
The subject matter of his lecture was "art, 11
consisting of a sort of lament that there was
ro little "art," especially in this country, and
depicting the art that had existed centuries
ago in the old world, and the progress now
being made in art cultivation in^England.
He spoke in a decided English
aw-dialect, and his brogue gave
no trace that he was an Irishman. He was
shocked by our buildings, by th« mud in the
streets, and especially by the rooms and furni
ture in the hotels. Almost the only smile
provoked during the evening was when he de
picted the lack of "art" in American hotel
furniture.
The lecture was well worded, and at times
quite poetical. It was certainly harmless and
does not entitle Mr. Wilde to either abuse or
ridicule. It was simply the smooth
sentences of a languid poet, which
strike the ear somewhat melodiously with
out arousing any overwhelming enthusiasm
or creating sufficient excitement in the listen
er to cause him or her to burst a blood vessel.
There is undoubtedly room for a great deal
of advancement, in "art" in this busy coun
try, and if Oscar succeeds in accomplishing
anything in this direction he will have done
no harm In fact, he is an entirely tame and
I harmless young man, on the rostrum at least,
and it probaoiy pays him to devote himeelf to
"art."</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89058370/1889-11-06/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A CHAT WITH WILDE.
The Apostle of JBathetloism as He
Appears In His London Home.
The Value of the Lute Cruaa.de The Poet
Has Cot Bis Hair, Put Away His
Knee Hreeches and t Now
a Money-Maker.
Special Correspondence.
London, Oct. ia 1S89.
HE Oscar Wilde
who made himself fa-
mousiQ America a lew
years ago is not the Os
car Wilde of to-day. The long hair has
been cut and is now short and curly.
The knee breeches have been put away
carefully, the lackadaisical air it no
longer worn, and the Oscar Wilde of
London to-day is a straight, strong, broad
shouldered athletic fellow, with no non
sense about him, and an evident determina
tion on bis face to make fame and money.
The Wilde craze, so far as England is con
cerned, is over. Mr. Wilde will question
this yet there are thousands of people, men
and women, who believe that Wilde
did much good in his late crusade,
and he has still a very respecta
ble following, but nothing like what
one would have been led to believe
from a perusal of the satirical Gilbert's
"Patience." 1 saw Oscar Wilde on Fleet
strpet to-day, and would not have known
him had not an English friend, pointed him
out to me. Hi lookud as Ilnj;H'ih ia liis
dress as in his manner, uud conducted him
self as thousands of other broad-shouldered
young fellows whom you will hnd at Oxford
or Cambridge, or in the big commercial
houses of London and Liverpool. He was
looking in the window of a second-hand
book-store. He carried an armful of papers
and a thick blackthorn stick in hi band.
There was nothing about him to attract at
tention. He might perhaps be picked out
of a crowd for a professional man. In a re
cent newspaper article it was reported
that Mr. Wilde had grown very
stout and very inartistic looking in
the matter of dress. This does him a great
injustice. As all the world knows, ho has
an artistic caste of countenance, and his
proportions are massive. He is not a favor
ite among men. Englishmen seem to look
upon him as something of a curiosity.
Women take more kindly to him. He is
chiefly known now by his contributions to
the magazines, work in which ha is most
assiduous. Punch calls his latest article
"Oscar Wilde's Mad Fancy." His time is en
tirely occupied. He lectures now and then,
writes special articles occasionally, does a
book review once in awhile, and every other
day spends a couple of hours or so editing
the Ladies' World, or the Women's World
as he now calls it, and performs the difficult
C&amp;
3
THE EVOLUTION OP WILDE
task of managing a large staff of feminine
contributors in a masterly fashion. He fre
quently drops in at tho Lyric Club, although
he belongs to half a dozen others in London,
and it was there over a cigarette and a straw
drink that the writer had a brief chat with
him.
"Your school of aostheticism, Mr. Wildo,
I began, "seems to have died out!"
"Oh, no," was tho quick rejoinder, "it has
not. There does not seem to bo the inter
est in aesthetic matters that thcro was
some years ago, but tho schoobhas not died
out not by any means."
"Then tho progress has been satisfactory
to you."
"Oh, yes, yes," was the reply, "perfectly
satisfactory;" and then he added after a
puff at his cigarette, "perfectly; how could
it be otherwise!'
"It was said in a leading newspaper not
long since that you had grown tired of what
was called 'the ajsthotic fad' and did not
desire to bo identified with the movement
any longer."
To this view of the matter Mr. Wilde
offered a distinct, implicit and somewhat
contemptuous denial; one of those denials
which are far better expressed by looks and
gesticulations than by words. It meant
that such an idea was ridiculous. "Of
course things change," he said. "They
have their various stages, the develop,
and require different treatment. But I
have not changed, as ray articles in the late
magazines on the subject will show."
"Has the progress of assthetioism been
more marked in this country or America)
"Oh, it is difficult to dran any hard and
fast lines where the change everywhere
has been so great," was the reply. "For
the same reason it is perhaps hard to note
the uuvttui-e. Every thing is uifleront, and
no comparison can be drawn. Both coun
tries have made satisfactory progress."
"Do you think the poor people havo Bene
fited equally with the rich in the develop
ment or artistic grace!
"Well, of oaurse, the rich ojan have their
artistic hangings, their fringes, their
tapestry and vary many things which the
poor can not have. Still, they havo gained
much recently. They have their People's
Palace, their music and the like, and this
all through our endeavors. I think on the
whole you may safely say that the common
people have benefited very much."
'What are some of tho benefits afforded
by the Ketmaisanco school!"
"Lookat col ir. The bow colors in dress
in tapestries ana in fringes. It is ull beau
UfUL"
"Whataboutdress?"
"Weil, you may change the Englishman's
religion, but you must not change hu dress
la other countries it is different. In your
own it is umerenu no court dress, no tra
ditional uniform which extends everywhere
in this country. There is, of course, some
hope for a change of beauty in America."
"ispeaking of America, American people
took well to your plans, did they not, and
your visit there was agreeable!
"(Jaitc so, repaed Mr. Wilde, '-the
Americans arc charming peopie. They
treated me very generously.
Then he repeated the word charming
nan a dozen times, wnicn l learned after
wards is a pet word of his. It pervades h
conversation and in? articles alike.
Mm
"Americans are so quick to catch a
point," he went on. "1 lfie thqat very
much. They treated me better than 1 had
expected. They are charming people."
"Do you think the Americans adopted
your ideas with more eagerness than the
English people!"
"No, I did not imply that. I like the
Americans. It is a pleasure to lecture to
them. The American audience is all atten
tion. It sees your ideas and it grasps your
points at once. The people are smart,
quick-witted, and if they like a thing they
warmly express their approbation."
"You lecture occasionally now, Mr.
Wilde!"
"Yes," was the reply, "and I havo re
ceived a great many letters from all parts
of America and from England on the sub
ject. None of these letters are of much im
portance. Many of them contain words of
hearty praise. These 1 remember. There
am a few others not so pleasant, but I have
forgotten them."
He lit a fresh cigarette, crossed his legs
in a comfortable sort of way, was lost in
silenco for a moment, and when he spoke
his thoughts were apparently running on
literature. Ho introduced the subject by
saying that a nation bad only one way of
expressing its better instincts. "England
expresses hers through her literature,
Greece did the same, and the literature of
these two nations stands forth incom
parable," he said.
"And America,"
"Oh, America expresses hors by energy.
What marvelous workers the Americans
are. No wonder they all make money so
rapidly. Yours, indeed, are a wonderful
people."
He rose to go. He explained that he had
to dine out, which he does very often, by
the way, and that ho had first of all to see
his mother and wife. It may interest
American readers to know that the leader
of the aesthetes takes a great deal of pleasure
In his homo life, that ho is comfortably if
not luxuriously situated and that he is much
sought after by good company. Ho is an
inveterate first-nighter, and when ho has
nothing else to do he spends an hour or two
to great advantage in the British Museum
scanning someof the treasures of that won
derful collection. He is making money, and
those who ought to know say he has a com
fortable bank account. Lady Wilde, his
mother, Is often seen in London. She is an
inveterate diner-out, believes in the opera
and the theaters, and is often seen at
late dances. She is still a beautiful wom
an, well preserved, has splendid mental
capabilities, writes pretty verses and is evi
dently pioud of her big son. She is an ar
dent home-ruler. She is also the mother of
another son not so well known as Oscar-
Willie Wilde a man who has the money
making instinct more thoroughly developed
than any other member of the Wilde family.
Mrs. Oscar Wilde is a lovable woman
who has a targe circle of acquaintances, and
who entertains in a small, but very satisfac
tory manner. She is a charming figure in
the ball-room, which her talented mother-in-law
frequents, and many of the leading
lights of art, literature and science crowd
her snug little drawing-room on a reception
nieht. There is always music, some good
readings, singing and light refreshments.
It is a place worth going to if you get an in
vitation. Mr. Wilde mods so many friends
in America that you are almost certain to
meet one or two American men and women
there. The hours are late, but every mo
ment is enjoyable.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071158/1895-04-04/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1895-04-11/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde&amp;
r=0.014,-0.036,0.377,0.289,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>OlCA1 IDl1 HOOKS
T7 Win Resaala oa thft Hhelve of th
Llbrarle ofNtw Tork
Thr seem t b no disposition on the part of
those ID charge of the chief llbrarle of New
York to follow the example of the British
Museum and the trustees of th Newark Free
Library by Issuing a bun ata nst the book of
Oscar Wild The works of Wilde b
Wid work Wide are by no
means popular with the library natrons of this
city and In several of these Institutions his
book are not to b found At those In which
they are kept the demand for them Is reported
I very UchL In p aklnc about the books
written by Wild Mbrarlau William T Peoples
of the Mercantile Library said yesterday
W bav the works of tn author on our
ehllTr and w certainly hal not withdraw
thm from circulation In fact I se no reason
why we should Il fore the recent Uevelop
toentshls books wee sid to be b very clever
and no particular fanlt was found with them
Now that these revelations have ben made
mae
people profess to se pomethln terrlbl
pople prfeu 1 Nmethlne In
Dorian Gray and other of his works Hut
apart from the question of Wildes morality or
Immorality the taking of these books from the
helve of our library will not stop the demand
wi thlman
for them and if a certain book I to b keot any
where a public library Is I certainly the place for
I Our patrons are nearly all mature and If I
should detect a run ou Wildes books among
01 Wlda bok Imone
those upon whom they would probably work an
Injury I would certainly stop it No we cannot
take Mr Wildes name olt hU bk and I do
not see how we can withdraw his works from
circulation
Librarian nutler of the Xew York Society
Library said that the only work of Wilde on
the shalvs of that Institution wer Dorian
Gray Intention and his bak of poem
No I do not think the trustees will order them
withdrawn he continued and personally I
see no reason why they should be a I ban
ner heard tham objected to on the score of
Immorality of text There has been little or no
works call for Dorian Gray and less for his other
Jacob Schwartz Librarian of th Mechanics
and Tradesmans Society raid that the books of
Wild would not b withdrawn from that
library I ha her no objection t the
book themselves he said and I sec no reason
why they shonld b out unu r the bin We
have Dorian Graya it originally appeared in
jMmilncotO Vuiudif and ua ccvlrt not remove
It from the library without siwlllne the entire
11111n tntro
volume of that particular publication Several
books have ben withdrawn from this library nil
account of the text but none because of the
author character
Librarian Hcnjamln of the Harlem Library
one of the nlde t Institutions of Its kind in the
city said that Wildes book had not been with
drawn I hlve nerd no objection t them
h continue and I see no rtason why they
Khould not remain on our shelves There has
been scarcely any call for his works
At the headquarter of the Nw York Free
Clrculatlnc library In Bond street and at the
branch Library iio Second avenue It was said
that the books of Wide were cot on the shelve
	  </text>
      </result>
	  
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1895-05-26/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde&amp;
r=0.236,0.933,0.489,0.375,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>OSCAR WILDE CONVICTED
Sentenced to Two Years' Im
prisonment at Hard
Labor.
Jurors Make Pertinent Inquiries
Concerning- a Warrant for Lord
Alfred Douglass.
LOjSDON, Esq., Mag 25.— Oscar Wilde's
trial having reached the final stage, the
Old Bailey courtroom was filled with in
terested spectators to-day. Sir Frank Lock
wood, Solicitor-General, concluded his ad
dress to the jury.
After the arguments were finished Jus
tice Wills began summing up at 1 :30 p. m.
The general tenor of his address was favor
able to Wilde.
During the address of Justice Wills to
the jury the foreman asked whether, in
view of the intimacy between Lord Alfred
Douglass and Alfred Wood, one of the
men whose name has been brought promi
nently into the case, a warrant for Lord
Alfred's arrest had ever been issued. The
Judge replied that he thought not.
The foreman then asked if it had ever
been thought of. To this the Judge re
plied he could not say. He added that the
suspicion that Lord Alfred Douglass would
be spared if guilty simply because he was
Lord Alfred Douglass was a wild idea and
a matter which they could not discuss.
The present inquiry was as to whether the
man in the dock was guilty.
The jury found Wilde guilty on all the
counts of the indictment, including the
charge with reference to persons unknown,
who were also pronounced guilty. The
announcement of the verdict caused a
great sensation in the court, as it was the
general impression that Wilde would be
acquitted.
When the foreman of the jury delivered
the verdict, Wilde, who had entered the
prisoner's dock a moment before, rose
from the chair on which he had been
seated throughout the trial and stood
with his arms on the rail of the dock.
The silence which prevailed throughout
the courtroom was really painful as Justice
Wills ordered that Alfred Taylor should
be also summoned before him.
Then in a voice trembling with emotion
the Justice said:
"I never before had such a case as this
to deal with. Two men such as you are by
the nature of your crime lost to all sense
of remorse for what you have done. To
think that yon, Taylor, and that you,
Wilde, a man of culture, should be guilty
of the offenses charged.
"There is no doubt but that the verdict
is a just one, and I shall give you the full
penalty allowed by law, and I only regret
that it ia not more severe. You are both
sentenced to hard labor for the term of two
years."
Wilde did not look at the Judge while
the sentence was being pronounced. His
eyes roved around the room and his face
never changed color, and he looked like a
man who had made up his mind to make
the best of a bad situation. Taylor smiled
when sentence was pronounced.
As Wilde turned in the dook and started
to go back to the prisoners' room the
crowd yelled ♦'Shame!" "Shame!" This
shouting caused Jnstice Wills to rise and
exclaim in a loud and determined voice,
"Silence, silence!"
During the time the jury was debating
on the verdict Lord Douglass strolled out
of the courtroom and into the courtyard,
where he walked about nervously, smoking
a cigarette.
His face still showed traces of his recent
encounter with his father, his left eye be
ing much disclored. Dunne the final
stages of Wilde's trial to-day there was an
immense crowd in front of the Old Bailey,
and the windows of all the neighboring
houses were filled with highly interested
spectators.
Oscar Wilde and Taylor were, after the
conclusion of the trial, conveyed without
delay to the Newgate Jail, where they
waited until warrants were signed for their
sentence.
Both men were then conveyed in the
prison van to Pentonville, where they will
serve out their sentences unless a pardon
should be granted or they should be trans
ferred to another prison before the expira
tion of their sentences.
	  </text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1895-06-16/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde&amp;
r=0.108,0.02,0.691,0.529,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-05-17/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde&amp;
r=-0.035,0.426,0.734,0.562,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>OsCAK WILD I S FUTURE.
He Does Not Intend to Efface Him
self, aud Will Write Again.
London, May 17 Oscar Wilde lias broken
his long enforced silence. To u newspaper
representative who visiited him iu Reading
prison yesterday he announced Ins plans
for the future The teirible punishment
he has suffered has not broken hi.s spliit
nor impaired his stieugth. He will try to
live down the shame lie has brought on him
self and will not llee fiom this country
In reply to the interviewer's first ques
tion, Wilde said:
"My health physically is good, but my
brain is weary As to my futuie, I am in
the hands of a lew faithful ftiendt. To
them I will deliver myself up, and with
them chiefly lies my destiny To them
alone will I communicate my dearest am
bition. At piesent my brain is too weak,
too worn, too tired, butthepowei that isiu
me will resume its sway. I shall write
again soon, but not yet. I am too tiled,
too distressed.
"Do you purpose leaving England?" he
was asked.
"Not at present," was the reply. "I am
In the hands of a few friends. They will
decide everything for a while. I do not in
tend to efface myself I shall get to work
again before long; in fact, the very mo
ment I feel well enough For the present,
thanks to the friends to whom I have al
luded, I shall retire into absolute seclu
sion. I shall see no one, speak to no one
but them. The public will hear from me
through my next work, and not before it
is ready, and not by any other means."
"Will it bear your own name?"
"Most assuredly, as I am at present dis
posed. The place where I shall seek se
clusion will not be far from London. Myre
than that, I cannot say."
Wilde will be released from prison ac
cording to present arrangements, between
C.30 and 7 o'clock on Wednesdiy morning,
where he will be met by his friend, Frank
Harris, who intends to take him in a cab to
Windsor, fourteen miles distant, for break
fast.</text>
      </result>
	  
	<result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1900-12-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=Oscar+Wilde&amp;
r=-0.525,-0.045,1.938,1.483,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>OSCAR WILDE DEAD IN
t h SMALL PARISIAN HOTEL.
STATIST DEMANDS THE
BOER WAR BE STOPPED.
English Writer Passed Away
England's Leading Financial Journal Pro
poses That Government Begins
Negotiations.
Surrounded by a Iew
Friends.
ABSCESS OF THE BRAIN.
7
J,ast Days of Once Petted So-
cial Lion Passed in Com
parative Penury.
;b special. t,i t.i.i.

r rem--, ..v. v
New York Herald Corri'.in.)-0-car Wilde
died at 2.30 o'clock thl afternoon at a small
holel In the l.-ttln Quarter.
For three davs lie had lain urconxoious
or In delirium from the effects of an abscess
In his far which the doctors could not lo
cate evactlv The inflammation from this
gradually mcuntrd to his brain.
He dieu attended by a few faithful frienJs
who declined to accept the general verdict
of the world against lilm. His end mav
be compared to that of Verlaine, the
Parisian "guttersnipe poet." as he a
called It is intercs'lng to note that "Mr an!
Mr. Pavenlr.' a play with the author-
."hlp of which Wilde was credited. Is now
on the boards In Iondon The majority
roi.sider it erj shocking, jet every one
rushes to sec It In order to satisfy popular
curlos.tj.
Wilde. It N declared, recched one-fourth
of the profit" of the piece. In which Mrs.
Patrick Campbell has made a successful
Appearance, jrt he died almost In want.
i
msn n fall or wilde.
Oscar Wilde enjoved In his early life ever
thing cord-iclve to a brilliant literary career.
He may be said to have Inherited genius.
I HI father was the famous Dublin surgeon.
Sir William Wilde, who not on! possessed
a European reputation in his profesloi, but
a distinguished as an archaeologist and
man of letters. The houe in Merrion Square
was celebrated for the Catherines that took
place there In the hospitable salon of Lady
Wilde, who. under the name of Sperlnza,
cas herself an authorcs.
VjfAe bo was filled with the feror of the
jr-s-C imagination and had eirl heard ev
f it-,''fcct of science, art and politics dls
IjV his father's dinner table bj the
cj-.,yien of letter-? or public life whom
IrTS.3r supplied cr Europe and America sent
to visit the famil. He was educated pri
vately and traveled much In France and
Germany before he began his, college career.
This was exceptionally distinguished, for
he carried off the chief prizes for classical
scholarship at Trinity College. Dublin, and
t Magdalen College, Oxford.
Ruskln was lecturing on "Florentine Art"
at he tirre. and Oscar Wilde wa one of hi
devoted dlscipU-s, going even so far, in spite
ef a tendency, already confirmed, to Sb
arltlsm. to follow the professor in the task
he set his pupils to make a rfiSd ouMde Ox
'ford. Ruskln left '"ixfon u tOsew Wf-'j
-sf remained to four -ta r g i v.; i-t." J
tlrcle of eclectics in art, music and poetry,
surrounding themselves with Damascus
tiles, blue china and drawings of the Birne
Jones school.
WANTS TO OPERATE
HOT-WATER PLANT,
Bill Introduced in City Council at
Request of Imperial Electric
Light Company.
OFFERS CITY COMPENSATION.
Measuie AUo I'tovides for Repair
of Streets Where Conduits Are
to 1. Built Brief House
Session.
ii By reuuest ilr tVic-iHn ...r.i .nr.
i.rioon Introduced In the Clly Council a onl
I to authorize tne Imperial KI-ctrIc Light,
Si Heat and Power Comp.nj to construct, cj--
erate ani maintain a heating and hot-water
plant within the clly limits, the franchise
to expire on April 1 is to
The hill would, if lusted, allow the com-
j mu juiiM in ana ui-
ficr any ami all streets, allpjs and puollc
;y,w" pnn being" subject to the ap
2provalt Jn adance or work, of the Board
1 Blftt u
rr u inue sireeia may no lorn up
J? .vltn rnnctt-itttnr. i. nit .n,t, i
ja u..u, uilu ixtt olacuisi Will uc
'(jetore(i to their former normal condition.
1 ytcoruing to tne Judgment of the Street
It Commsiorer, tho company to remunerate
f 'no city for repairs r..cejsltated by faulty
work.
The bill recites that on January 1 and
I July 1 of each jear the company mill pre
I r J?nt ,nc cu' Comptroller a statement of
ifj ?r0S3 recpIPts for the preceding six
1: umu n.-ct:iie in corn-
pfi -Mnsatlon from the compan 1V per cent
V L" iu BroRS recc'Pts in the region boundtd
Avenues, and 1 wr ,.nt f.m ,tiA .ai......
eatsldeof these lines.
-..aw. unvitu uirfe amenamenis 10
rernser St. Louis Transit Company ordi-
i"?r: Hodses, staling that propertj -owners
i.- na entered isorou conmintnt mnMi fnr
i. m .j T E-
'"-uiwiaerjuon of the House bill allow-
&amp;
L&amp;
.Z "-"Par Ochsmann to build and operate
&amp;
2z.jkrr vt- llIU -"ii-c vn ourtiary
IEsEm vaiica a pudiic neanng ror next
tSffi- y afternoon at 4 o'clock. Water Com-
-usuiuuer r jaa, replying to Mr. Kratz's res
olution, explained in a communication that
water mains distributed about the
(trcib) win be under ground by the end of
.uecember. Work was delated, he 'wrote, by
tne sink. r.4 uv.i.. n AM.i..
sS&amp;
SAuinsi
I??l3i4 The till rnnkln" !r nH.lflnnn1 onnrnnrla.
P tion of
t Wat
Hon n Kri .t S
k. I.er Ratei was sent to engrossment
fc" was beat to engrossment.
AJ JfpUowlng bills were passed: One glWng
ui(irouer tne right to pay taxes on
"r,'1?, A Armory; another relating to a
mui Poorhouse appropriation: others for
S..2, .recoBstructlon3; another pemlttlng the
.iH?w Railroad Company to build a
J"ca track Jnto the Buck Stove and Range
hSrJ"?7 Plant; another appropriating
tt Waterworks extension, and an
other amindlng the original new City Hos
pital ordinance. Chairman Richards an
nounced that his Committee on Legislation
iu consider several bills at 4 p. m. next
Tuesday. v
The House of Delegates, with Mr. Hart
rnann la the chair, last night broke all rec
ord for s.iort sessions. Ir. Hartmann pro
eetd to call out the regular order of bust
"n the Houee adjourned without do-
PfcCAR WILDK
As ho looked when ho visited St I.011I3
Going to ltal. Oscar Wlldr found a nm
inspiration. He went back to Oxford to
write poems full of tho feeling of Kniinn
Catholicism, and was only turned asIJo
from entering the church lt-elf by a tour
In Greece.
The Hellenic Ideal now took the plice
of the Catholic, and a olume of po.try
proclalmed his demotion to the gods and
goddesses of the ancient world
Comes lulu I'-iutt.
I The verses that l.c published never raiI
him out of the arm of minor poets, but
before the public In a role which attracted
attention, both In Enjland and Americi.
He started on lecturing tours as the apos
tle of "Aestlietlclsm." with the avowed
aim of relieving the dull atmo-phere of
ordinary households b the Introduction of
refinement and taste. But In the personal
advocacy of this crcid he was manifestly
a poseur, and his eccentric dress and man
ner affordel ample material for jest and
mill satire as found ixprcs-lon In Filbirt's
wit
The taslo for epigram crew on Ocar
Wilde as the jeara passed on He now
strove to show his powers as a plavw right,
and In "Lady Windemere's Fan" gained
much appreciation for dialogue, sparkling
with wit and cjnlcism. In the piece that
followed, 'A Woman of No Importance."
the straining at producing effect became
more manifest.
As a writer of a new class of plays Oscar
Wilde had. however achieved a distinct
position, when the blow fell which removed
him from the pale of society.
A profound senation was caused In Lon
don when it was known that the Marculs
of Queensbury had tzdeen the extraordinary
means of sending a libelous post-card to
Oscar Wilde's club. No other course was
left to Wilde but to brine an action for
coinages. In the course of that suit the
scathing cross-examination of Mr. Carson
cut away the ground from tho complain
ant's feet. His plea that art was above
morality was ruthlessly set addc.
Uon-nfall Wns Complete.
He lost his case, was prosecuted on a
criminal charge of a vile character, and, be
ing found guilty, he was sentenced to two
j ears' Imprisonment.
Wilde's downfall was complete. His wife
int family deserted him, his plajs were
withdrawn by theatrical managers on both
sides of the ocean, and ha was left with
out rtjouice.
After his release he went to raris, where
5 csterday he died in miser- almost squalor
surrounded only by a few friends of for
mer das.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93051662/1882-02-18/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=oscar+wilde</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99068116/1895-05-23/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;
q=oscar+wilde</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WILDE’S SECOND TRIAL
Begun in Old Bailey Before Many Inter
ested Spectator*.
London, May 23. —The second trial
of Oscar Wilde was begun in the Old
Bailey court before Justice Willis.
There was a big crowd of interested
spectators present. Wilde was very
restless and looked careworn. The
solicitor general, Sir Frank Lockwood,
in opening the case for the treasury,
said that the indictment covered acts
of gross indecency during the period
extending from February to October,
1893. He then recited the charges
made against Wilde in connection with
Edward Shelley, Alfred Wood and
others.
The Marquis of Queensberry was
present at the trial of Oscar Wilde.
During the morning session Wilde was
taken ill and was obliged to leave the
court.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85035720/1923-10-06/ed-2/?sp=7&amp;
q=oscar+wilde&amp;
r=0.576,0.754,0.554,0.424,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064299/1922-06-23/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;
q=oscar+wilde&amp;
r=-0.078,0.415,0.639,0.489,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WHY WILDE PLAYED THE FOOL
Adoption of Eccentric Garb Made
Public Talk and Compelled the
Attention of Publishers.
When Oscar Wilde announced that
he was coining to America to lecture
every one in literary circles was
greatly interested, not to say vastly
excited. Even those who did not
know Wilde's fame as poet and
writer, or had not even read his
books, were also interested. They
were anxious to see Oscar Wilde on
account of his characteristic ]>erson
ality and his peculiar manner of
'dressing.
Wilde affected an individual style
all his own when it came to clothes.
He proclaimed himself to be an
"esthete"—one looking for .the beau-
tiffti ifi art, and- searching for the-
'truth.lit life.
Wilde's costume was a black velvet
suit with knee breeches and silk
stockings. He had his hair curled
by a hairdresser, and wore it very
long. In his buttonhole or in his
hand was always a rare flower.
His wit prompted him to adopt
this rig. He decided that "it pays
to advertise." Before adopting his
original style of dressing Wilde had
dilfieulty in having his work accept-
ed by publishers. But, it is said,
/after becoming famous through his
unusual costume, Wilde had no
trouble in selling his manuscripts.—
Mark Stuyvcsant, in the Cleveland
Plain Healer.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090528/1901-02-12/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;
q=oscar+wilde&amp;
r=-0.521,-0.441,2.042,1.563,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-electric-cars</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064454/1891-10-31/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;
q=Carriage+carriage+electric+Electric</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Building an Electric C'arriage.
A novelty among vehlieles in this
country, an electric carriage, is now
beinig coni)strucllted at the faet'rv of
IM. W. Qutinlan, in Brookline. Mass.,
front plans drawn front a photograph
of a similar carriage in nresent use in
London. The battery contains thirty.
two cells,aoid is jplaced in the rear end
of the body of 4ileo carriage. The
motor, which is of foreign manutfao
ture, rests between the hitd springs,
where it is attached to the body by
two hinge clasps in such a manner as
to allow it to swing when the motion
of the carriage is irregular, although
this swing is regulated by a connect
ing rod. The driving shfts of the
miotor extetd on eithcir side ibeyond
lthe sprinigs, and are fitted wilh cog
wheel attachittents which coninect by
atln endless chlati with larger cogwheels
on the inner side of the rear wheels.
Thie steering apparatus is on the left
side of the carriage platform. In case
of accildent to the amotor, shafts can be
litted to the c:u'riage, and horses at.
tached. When comnileted, tie whole
carriage will weighl about 2500
pouttds. All tlhe electrical work is
tlone by the loltiier-Cabot Cotl,:ny*.
-[New York ''Tribune.
</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024546/1891-12-09/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;
q=carriage+electrical</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SCRAPS OF SCIENCE.
Odd Pieces of Mechanism Evolved
by Meditative Brains.
ELECTRICITY TLAYS ITS PACT.
Carriages and Fans Are Iropelled Yitll
out Animal Energy.
PAVEMENTS MADE FROM OAK AND ICON
An electrical carriage has been shipped to
Chicago from Des Moines, Iowa. It may
arrive to-day, and as soon as its storage bat
teries can be charged it will be sent spin
ning alont; the boulevards. It was built for
ordinary usage and it is said to have carried
12 people at a speed ot 14 miles an hour
and can run continuously for 13 hours be
fore the energy is exhausted. The motor
ued is rated at four-horse power, and
has an armature of the Siemens type with
special-wound coils. The prominent feature
of the carriage is the storage cells, 24 in
number placed in three sets of eight each.
The weight is said to be but 32 pounds per
cell audio yield three-horse power hours of
energy per cell.
The carriage ha a special gearing and a
ball and socket motion to the axle, while a
peculiar hub device allows for any obstacles
encountered. The motor is carried by a
framework underneath the body of the car
riage and is geared to the rear axle. The
steering device is attached to the front uf
the axle and is controlled bv a handwheel in
the front of the carriage. It is said to be
so delicate in action that the course of the
chicle can be altered bv a slight touch.
The switch for throwing the motor in and
out ot circuit is moved by the foot of the
one in charge. This carriage is said to have
ascended grades or 17 per cent without
severe strains.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1892-08-11/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;
q=electricity+Electricity+Morrison+wagon+Wagons+William</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GOOD BYE, HORSES I
Wagons May Now Be Run by
Electricity.
Chicago, Aug, 10.— A novelty in the
way of a wagon propelled by electricity
was seen on the streets of Chicago yes
terday. Some time ago President J. B.
McDonald, of the American Battery
company, purchased several patents
from William Morrison, of Dcs Moines.
Among other things was a park wagon
equipped with a small three-horse-power
motor and twenty-four-cell storage bat
tery. Yesterday Mr. McDonald fitted
the wagon with new batteries and gave
it a trial. With five persons in the
wagon it left the barn on Monroe
street and traveled to the company's
office. The run was made in twenty
two minutes, which was considered a
satisfactory, considering that the wagon
was delayed at a bridge and that fre
quent stops were, made on account of
the crowds in the streets down town.
It is calculated that the wagon can
make ten miles an hour easily with the
present motor and can climb any bill in
the city.</text>
      </result>
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1895-12-03/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;
q=carriage+carriages+Company+company+electric+Electric+electricity+Morris+Salom+Wagon+wagon+wagons&amp;
r=0.284,0.338,0.41,0.314,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-02-02/ed-1/?sp=25&amp;
q=Carriage+carriage+carriages+electric+Electric+electrical+electricity+Horseless+horseless+Morris+Salom+wagon</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The Horseless Carriage.
It is not outside the realm of possibility
that in the century soon to dawn the
horseless carriage may be as familiar on
the public highway as the bicycle is to
day; as familiar, in fact, as the family con
veyance of the period. Of course' good
roads are a prime requisite for the success
of the motocycle, but good roads are
bound to come, and it is to be hoped that
the agitation for them that has been set
on foot all over this country will not be
void of desirable, results even before tha
MUELLER MOTOCYCLE.
[Reproduced from the Cosmopolitan.]
clnse of the present century. Good
smoothly paved roads being a ccrtninty of
realization at no very remote date, "the j
i prospects of the horseless carriage seem to
j be quite flattering, if the judgment of the
fiiendsof the new invention" can bo relied!
upon. They contend that the horse may j
bo dispensed with and the highest measure
|of speed and comfort attained over j
smoothy paved boulevards in a vehicle pro
pelled by mechanical power. It is worth i
while to take a look at some of these up
to-date vehicles.
The "PJlectrqbat 1 is the original name
given by Morris Salom of Philadelphia j
to the first electric wagon constructed in i
that city. It was ihe joint work of a me-
chanical engineer and an electrician. The
i wagon was run hundreds of miles over
the streets of Philadelphia without seri- j
i ous mishap. Its tot.il weight, including
I the battery, is 4250 pounds, and the max;- j
mum mileage on one charge of electricity
la from h'fty to one hundred, according to j
speed and grades, the maximum speed at- j
tamable being- fifteen miles an hour.
Charles A. Duryea of Peoria, 111., ha 3
successfully applied the gasoline motor to
horselessvehici.es. The Duryea motor re
sembles an ordinary, heavily buih buggy,
weighs 700 pounds,* and has ball-bearings
An Electrobat.
[Reproduced from the Cosmopolitan.]
and rubber-tired wheels. It has an inge
nious mechanism for steering and changing
the speed without a moment's loss at time.
The cost of running this carriage is one
fourth of- a cent a mile, and a supply of
gasoline can be carried sufficient to nm
the machine 150 miles. Upon goo* roads
a SDeed of twenty miles is claimed.
There are numerous rivals for popularity
in the motocycle world. The Mueller
patent, for instance, recently won a prize
in a contest for economy of operation,
coming in a close seconci'to the Dnryea
machine. In order to stimulate invention
and do what they can to hasten the com
ing of the age of the marvelous carriage
the publishers of the Cosmopolitan, from
which publication the illustrations of
motocycles on this page are taken, offer
premiums amounting to $3000. These
premiums are to be awarded to motor
carriages presenting the greatest number
of points of excellence as exhibited in a
trial trip to be made from the New York
office of the Cosmopolitan on the 30th of
May to the Cosmopolitan building at
Irvington, and thence back to tbe starting
point.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-12-05/ed-1/?sp=25&amp;
q=cab+electric+electricity+New+New-York+vehicle+Vehicle+vehicles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>NEW VEHICUM ?it l*OCTOBg
There are young nn^n In N\v-Y?rk who can
remember when tin? only telephone lina in th??
city connected a r????m in Tht? Triltime Building
with th? American institute. People used In
come t? that room anil listen to other? talk. Blng
or whistle al the other end of the lino, and ex?
clamations of wonder and surprise were beard
whenever the Imperfect instrument was >x
aniine?!. The telephone wan l?M>k?d upon at Hint
tlm?? a scli-ntlflc t?>>, and in much th?? same
?Kht as the motor vehicle is regarded by many
people at this time. Hut the telephon?? has 1???- j
come a necessity, and, In the same way, many
people predict that tho boraeleee carriage win
Oeaae to be looked upon aa a novel plaything
and take Its place among the neoe?Itlesi.
In some parts of Europe the horseless vehicles
have become popular and comparatively cheap,
and, the novelty having worn off, they are em
ployed in a practical way. In New-York the
horseless cnrrlage has not y?-t become popular,
and the vehicles which are seen OB the Btreet? I
are for the most part the property of cab com-
panics, by whom they are rented to the people
win? wish tfacts that the few mot??r vehicles which have
been sold to private individuals have niv-n eat?
isf.i. lion, that th?? c ?st off maintaining th?'ni la
?mall and that the Btreeta ??f New-Tor?, are
gradually being Improved ao that the vehicles
will run without Jolting, make tn.inufa ?turer?
lielii-v.? thai Hier?? ?a ill Boon be a boom in tliut
direction.
c. .1. Harrington, superintendent of the Elec?
tric Vehicle Company, said thai bla ion?, m
h recently ordered one hundred additional
canias;???, and thai there would b? room in their
place to stop? and take -care of a number ??f
vehicle? f??i other people.
?Jt costs much less to keep a homeless wagon
than an ordinary outfit," be said, and it enn do
mur.? work. Th?? horse, if driven more mile? on
one ?lay than hexertion, will be worthlesa the nexl day, while
the iunior wagon can be recharged when its
electric supply is exhausted ?ml go right ahead
?gain. w? shall ask 1 for every twenty-flve
mii- charge, and will also receive a amount
cie.u? and in repair. Th?? coat of running the
vehicle will depend &lt;n the number &lt;f miles.&quot;
Among the few peopl?? in N? w-V??rk who drive
motor vehicles an? (?livr II Belmont and
W. E. Busby. Mr Belmont'a turnout created
some excitement at Newport last summer, and
was on?? of the sights of tli?? pia???. Mr. Dusby
guillas his boraeleee vehicle along Riverside
Drlv?? nearly every day It? builder, Andrew I,
UuV.r, sai?! that it show???! n?> m??r?? wear than
an ordinary vehicle which ha?l travelled half aa
many mil? s. This carriage is kept in Mr. BUS
by'? stabl??, w 1???p? its motor is supplied through
th.? regular Edison current at the regular reten.
The bill for chartiifiK it the fust month It ran
was $1035, and it tan six bjndred miles In that
time. The av?rai,'!? cost for electricity la two
??cuts a mile, but th?? price would be considerably
less if the own-T of the vehicle had his own
electric plan, Tins faci baa been dem?r*natrated
by J. R, Whiting, ol Stamford, Conn., who has
an electric generator for lighting his house, Hla
horselesa vehicle I? charged by tins generator,
an?l this brings tli?? coal down to l?*ss than one
????ni a mile,
br Will:.m, H Hutehlnsofi ?ff Brooklyn, has
ordered horseless stanhope phai ton, and he
will one off tin? pioneers ot his profession In
the use off tins style off vehicle. Bui tbe great?
est addition? in ti??? line will probably l?? m the
ahape ot business wagons. an ordei under way now lor a delivery wagon
for a large depart meni More a osi of I-.',?*??'!,
and if Ihe vehfcle provea satlefactory the con
csrn will take iifty more. The wagons will make
twenty-five miles a day and can be run at the I
rete of i.vo power of not more lhan ">n cents day Aside
from 'osi ?if Storage and repairs, the ???t ?>r
maintaining ??ii?? ?>f these delivery wagons a yenr
waa placed at th?? following figure by Mr. Rlker:
?nteres! on Investment.flRfJ
800 working ?lays al "ill centi. lull
Total *SHl
Tnis i? leas than it would to draw ih?? vehlcl?</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026853/1897-12-22/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;
q=CABS+cabs+Electric+ELECTRIC+vehicle+vehicles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ELECTRIC CABS IN NEW YORK.
Homeless Vehicles Hare Become a Fix*
tare In the Biff City.
Electric cabs, hansoms and broughams
are a sucoesB in New York, so
ELECTRIC HANSOM USED IN NEW YOBK.
much of a success that the company
operating them has just given out an
order for 100 new vehicles. Daring
Jane, the first moath of their operation,
a total number of 632 calls were
received, averaging between thirty-Wb
and twelve per day, carrying 1680 passengers
4603 miles at rates similar to
the horse-cab system, and each month
sinoe that time has seen a steady increase
in the service.
The best resalts obtained from these
vehicles show that about -1.25 horsepower
is supplied for a propulsion of
2000 pounds over ordinarily level roads
at a speed of ten miles an hour. This
consumption of power is a trifle over
two and one-third times that of similar
work on rails, which indicates that the
equipment of the battery is carefully
-ii _ f xi J
adapted to trie total weigni 01 tue vemcle
and just sufficient for practical
traveling capacity. The maximum
weight of a battery for a hansom weighing
3000 pounds is 1200 pounds for a
distance of twenty-five miles at the
maximum speed of twelve miles or at
an average speed of six miles.
i
|B|||g^gg|gg^.
IB
m
irrniiw?i|
H
YORK.
by Kmpp at the World's Fair at Chicago,
oould resist a shot from It.
A vehiole to travel twice this distance
could readily be built, but it
would need to be twice its weight in
order to accommodate twioe the bat
tery equipment, xnis type 01 venicie
is constructed -with the view of a speed
of from six to twelve miles 'an hour,
but a vehicle can be built to approximate
thirty miles an hour, although it
would necessarily be made as a raoing
apparatus and not fit for street work.
Two one-and-one-half horse-power
motors, weighing 172$ pounds each,
ore found sufficient for a hansom, and
are Operated at a maximum speed of
1350 revolutions per minute.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1899-02-05/ed-1/?sp=18&amp;
q=car+carriage+carriages+cars+electric+electrical+electricity+horseless+vehicle+vehicles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE day of the horse is passing
away. Already the practical de
monetlzation of the faithful!
equine might be said to be taking!
place, and before another cen- J
tury shall have elapsed he may have be
come a zoological curiosity. His yen- j
erable bones will be seen mounted and I
on exhibition in museums. The small
boy ot the twentieth century will won
der what sort of animal Equus cabal
lus really was and will marvel at the
Ca t that he was once harnessed and
made to haul heavy loads.
The beginning: of the end was in sight
when electricity first supplanted the
horse as a means of propulsion for
street cars. Then the bicycle came,
sprang at once into popular favor and
rendered still more limited the' uses of
our once essential quadruped.
But now stili greater changes are
taking place. The introduction of the
automobile on streets of American cit
ies is slowly but surely driving out the
old fashioned hansom and the two horse
orougham, and now even the lorrie team
and the long overworked draft horse
are to become "things that were."
The recent formation of a company in
New York city with a capital of some
$100,000,000 to exploit compressed air as
a motive power for all trucking and
carting business in Greater New York
shows still again how surely the reign j
of the horse is passing away. He will
of course continue, for a time at least,
to remain the pet and the trained speed
ing animal of the wealthy in the city
and the helpful friend of the more hum
ble farmer in the country. But as time
goes on and urban population becomes
more and more dense it will be seen, to
be even more necessary in order to ob
viate congestion of traffic in city streets
and to maintain a proper degree of san
itation and cleanliness to allow only
self propelling- vehicles on the public
streets of our towns and cities.
The outcome of this will be a vast
Improvement in the condition and
smoothness of all city streets, the abo
lition of the objectionable cobblestone
is paving material and the elimination
of the ear piercing noises which now
make a pandemonium of the average
metropolitan thoroughfare.
It is true, motor vehicles for pleasure,
traffic and business purposes have been
somewhat slow of adoption in this coun
try. The horse has held his own here
with remarkable pertinacity, for it has
been in European cities, and particular
ly in Paris, that the automobile indus
try has flourished to the greatest ex
tent. The principal reason why Ameri
cans have been in no undue haste to
sulopt motor carriages re the fact that
mechanically these have not hitherto
been sufficiently developed to render
them acceptable for general use. The
motive power employed in most of them
has been unsatisfactory because of lack
of efficiency in some cases and extrava
gant expense of operation in others.
But American brains and American en
ergy have been at work on the problem
for the last few years, with the result
that the objections referred to have
been practically removed.
The general public, as a rule, has not
the opportunity of seeing the gradual
;:!:ti laborious approach to perfection of
any important mechanical invention.
This same general public is usually as
tounded at the miraculous appearance
i some new wonder, while the men
who have been laboring for years to
bring about this apparent mechanical
miracle foresaw the inevitable long be
fore the busy world had thought of such
a ihing. For some time now jokes have
been made about the passing of the
horse, but until the last year or so it
was never really thought that the pe
riod of equine usefulness had so nearly
approached its close.
It was vaguely felt that changes
might come about in time, for the idea
of mechanical instead of animal trac
tion power is as old as the history of
human thought itself. Even Homer
himself describes the god Vulcan as be
ing engaged upon the construction of
a great hall on wheels, which he de
.-cubes as &quot;self moving and wonderful,&quot;
and Juno is made to command Vulcan
to create tripods which shall run by
■•■!v&lt;&gt;s. thus rendering better serv
!ce to the gods in their meetings on
Mount Olympus.
in the thirteenth century the English
philosopher Roger Bacon wrote in one
of his works. "They will make carriages
which will run with the greatest imag
inable swiftness without any harnessed
whatever."
The earliest horseless carriage which is
preserved today is one now on exhibition
in Paris at the Conservatoire dcs Artes
et Metiers. This machine was invented
by Cugnot in 1769 and was made to op
erate by steam, the energy of which
was applied through two perpendicular
piston tubes. The principal reason per- j
haps why the French steam automobile
was not brought to a state of compara
tive perfection during the last century
was the beginning of the revolution.
The turbulence which accompanied that
event naturally turned men's minds
from .peaceful and civilizing pursuits to I
thoughts of warfare and the deposing of 1
NUGGETS FROM EVERYWHERE.
Senator Simon of Oregon has been
taking banjo lessons. "Are you improv
ing?" some one asked him recently.
"J'.wh'T tl*it or the neighbors are get
ting inure used to it," he replied.
f>n ,in occasion a bishop was consol
iriK a costermonger for the loss of his
I j l l to son. The poor fellow was rocking
tf. and fro in his distress. He suddenly
!'.'.kf fi -,it i]i: bishop and, with tears
running down his cheeks, said, "D'ye
tliink I could c;et the young beggar
ituffd?"
The late Senator Morrill, though he
monarchs. But it was in all likelihood
from the Cugnot steam carriage that i
Stephenson indirectly obtained his idea j
for a locomotive on rails.
j At the Exposition Universelle in Paris
I in 187S a steam automobile was exhibit-
I ed very like that of Cugnot, the only
j difference being that the frame of. the
j more modern vehicle was built after the
J plan of a common road carriage and not
jas a velocipede. This automobile, how- I
ever, was not a very satisfactory ma- j
chine, and it was not until 12 years later
that MM. Serpollet and Archdeacon in- i
vented a steam automobile, with which j
they journeyed from Paris to L.yons in
ten days. In 1894 the automobile first
gave promise of actual adaptability for j
general transportation and traction j
purposes. In that year the editor of the
Petit Journal organized the first auto
mobile race, which was run from Paris j
to Rouen. In this contest the steam
horseless carriage, while proving itself
cumbersome, noisy and uncouth in ap
pearance, showed itself superior to its
electrical and gasoline propelled rivals
of that time. The following year an
other race was run, this time from Paris
to Bordeaux and return, but in this test
it was the electrical carriage that prov
ed itself the superior machine.
Up to this time the construction of
these carriages had been conducted
along the ugly lines of a buggy or four
wheeled cart instead of seeking an in
dividuality for themselves through de
j signs more fitting to their peculiar qual
ities. Today, however, it might be said
that they have evolved an individuality
of their own. Automobile mechanics is
an art the nicety of which is only un
derstood by those who are of the pro
fession.
But one of the great difficulties that
still face the constructors of horseless
carriages is the problem of expense. A
Parisian made automobile victoria, for
instance, costs some $800 and an auto
mobile tricycle $300. The heavier car
riages are proportionately expensive.
This costliness of manufacture, how
ever, is a drawback that time will put
right,- just as has been the case with
the bicycle. But while the initial outlay
for an automobile Is still very large this
is more than compensated for by the in
significant extent of operating expenses,
the fuel for the petroleum propelled ye-
hides costing merely 1% cents per hour.
The development of the automobile as
a thing of beauty will take place only
when its place is assured and its use is
general, when people of means and
fashion will begin to demand certain
characteristics of design and finish to
differentiate their carriages from the
vehicles of the livery and the cab stand.
There are a number of New York la-
probably took up less space in The
Congressional Record than any of his
colleagues, always made a speech early
in the session and sent a copy bound
in Russia leather to every senator and
a paper bound copy to every voter In
Vermont.
Congressman Elect John L. Burnett
of Alabama, who will probably be the
smallest man in the next house, is an
able lawyer. When he first appeared
before the supreme court of Alabama
to argue a case, he stood up behind a
high bench on which lawyers were ac
-1
THE ST. PAUL GLOBE SUNDAY FEBRUARY 5, 1809.
dies who have their own private auto
mobiles and may be seen any day
speeding noiselessly along the more
fashionable streets of that city. It takes
some skill and experience to operate
one of these powerful horseless car
riages, for, after all, they are mere lo
comotives and not unconnected with
danger in the hands of the inexperi
enced. In Paris the authorities require
each operator of an automobile to pass
a practical examination, after which
he is given a certificate of efficiency.
The local history of Paris, neverthe
less, .for the past two years has been
lively enough with runaways, collisions,
upsets and explosions of a more or less
serious nature. New York has also had
its list of little accidents.
There is one thing that the motor car
riage demands, and that is good roads.
We are already indebted to the bicycle
for an improvement in the condition of
our highways, but when the automobile
comes into general use both the great
unthinking public and governmental
bodies will become impressed with' the
necessity for a better class of roadmak
ing. As things now are, the United
States stands lowest on the list of ad
vanced countries in the matter of good
highways. Another advantage of the
use of the horseless vehicle will be that
our streets will be found more health-
customed to lay their books and pa
pers. "May it please the court," be
gan the diminutive counsel, when the
chief justice broke in, "Mr. Burnett, it
is the custom of lawyers to rise while
addressing this court."
jOn a recently bitterly cold night
Speaker Reed had occasion to ride on a
street car the conductor of which neg
ligently left the door open, to the great
discomfort of the passengers. Mr. Reed
beckoned to the railway official and
when the latter came inside asked,
"Why have you got your collar turned
up, my friend?" "It's mighty cold," re
sponded the conductor, "and I want to
keep warm." "So do the rest of us,"
ful and cleaner than is now possible.
j Stabling will no longer be necessary in
cities, and there will be more room on
j city streets. The wearing noise of traf
fie will be hushed, and pneumatic tires
and silent generators *or storage batter
ies will do away with the roar of wheels
j and the rattle of horses' feet. In our
country, fortunately, there is no legis
lation and no popular prejudice against
I the automobile, as in England, for in
stance, where only a little over a year
i ago prohibitory legislation with regard
to the use of such carriages in London
was repealed. Until this action was
taken it was necessary that all horse
less carriages should be preceded by a
man on foot or on horseback bearing a
I red flag as a warning of the approach
of the terrible engine of destruction.
Animal power has ever been capri
cious and uncertain, while machinery is
j reliable and always sure. An automo
bile does not require continual atten-
tion, as does an animal. While not in
use the automobile entails no operating
expenses, and all that can be charged
to its idleness is the interest on the
original outlay for its purchase. Nor
will it grow old and die, like a horse.
When its day's work is done, it can be
run into a shed and stand there until
once more called upon to do service.
So long as it remaijis one of the deep
rooted characteristics of man, the most
restless of all animals, to be in the
place where he is not he will see to it
that his means of transportation are as
expedient, inexpensive and comfortable
as circumstances will permit. It has
taken him some time to reach the age
of the automobile, but it might be said
that such an age has at last arrived.
The passing of the horse furnishes
food for much profound thought and
reflection. It is a farreaching question, j
affecting almost all kinds and condi
tions of men. What will become of the
smith who hitherto eked out his frugal
existence in the wayside village under
the spreading chestnut tree? What will
become of the hay and feed man who
has so long and so profitably catered to
the inner wants of our old time equine
friend? What will become of the farm
er and his hay crop and his field of
oats? What will become of the costly
livery stable and the harness maker and
the veterinary surgeon?
It is no easy matter to figure out the
Immediate or even the ultimate im
provement in the general condition of
affairs which will result from the adop-
observed the speaker. "Suppose you
shut the door!" It is needless to add
that the passengers were comfortable
during the remainder of the trip.
A characteristic of the late William
Black was his ignorance of his own
books, and it was very difficult to get
him to talk about his novels. It seem
ed that as soon as the proof sheets were
returned to the printers Mr. Black for
got all about his own creations, "in
talking to my husband the other day,"
Mrs. Black once said fto a visitor, "I
suddenly remembered an anecdote in
one of his novels which illustrated what
I was saying. Mr. Black laughed hearti
ly at the story and then turned eagerly
lion of the horseless carriage, when it
is borne in mind that many disturbing
elements enter into the problem. Al
ready there has been a great falling oft
in the production ef horses and a depre
ciation in the value of horseflesh, which
i has filled the farmer and the horse
breeder with apprehension. But, for
tunately, these questions have the habit
jof settling and adjusting themselves.
j When it is remembered that there are
j now millions of acres of land devoted to
the growing of crops for horse food
alone, which in time may and must be
I devoted to the production of food for
I the human beings who are engaged in
the manufacture of the very machines
that are displacing the horse, the prob
lem is not so intricate and the outlook
is not so dark as it at first seems.
The poor old cab horse has always
had his drawbacks as a working ma
chine, and even with an animal en
dowed with all the noble attributes of
I the horse the question of economics can
not be kept out of the calculation. It
costs at least 60 cents a day to keep the
ordinary steed that travels up and down
a city's streets, and if he chances to be
a cab horse and times are good he will
I travel about 25 miles, on an average, on
that amount of nourishment. But he re
j quires at least eight hours' sleep and
rest, to say nothing of an occasional
day off as a result of colic, which leaves
I him a working capacity of 16 hours.
Most of the time, however, he spends in
j loafing around on street corners and
dreamily digesting his 60 cents' worth
of oats and hay.
It is commonly supposed that all cab
horses live about 100 years, but this is
one of those popular errors which have
no actual foundation in fact. His ten
ure of life averages, appearances to the
contrary, about 15 years, and at 60 cents
a day His feed in that time will amount
to only $3,275, for which, if he has
led an industrious, sober and unpam
pered life, he covers some 109,500 miles.
This newfangled automobile that is
elbowing its four footed rival off the
streets of the city, on the other hand,
will travel the same distance for about
$1,000, expended in fuel or electricity,
and while doing so will never have to
be sent to the blacksmith shop to be
shod, the average cost of repairs being
no more than that for the ordinary car
riage hauled by horses.
A French writer who has made a
study of the horseless carriage a spe
cialty has been figuring out its ultimata
to me, 'But where did you hear so good
a story?' My husband wouldn't be
lieve it was in one of his own books
until I found it for him."
Senator Frye of Maine says that
while in Paris he needed a hair cut, so
he studied carefully the necessary por
tion of his "French Conversation Book"
and did his best to make the barber
understand. "I don't understand Dutch,"
said the person addressed. "Do you
speak English?"
A good story is told by Rudyard Kip
ling at his own expense. During his
stay in Wiltshire, England, one sum
mer he met little Dorothy Drew, Mr.
Gladstone's granddaughter, and, being
possibilities and prophesying as to its
future.
He forecasts that the size of the auto
mobile, while not yet greatly differing
from the ordinary one or two horse
wagon, will increase in time to an enor
mous extent and that its weight may
even reach a Vegister of thousands of
tons. The liveryman will be replaced
by the dispenser of coal, electricity and
1 petroleum, and instead of water troughs
1 along the principal highways there will
be seen innumerable electric storage de
pots.
This French prophet attempts to
straighten out the economic knot by
1 forecasting that the horse will in time
become a delectable and much sought
after feod animal. He holds that a life
of leisure will restore the proper amount
of succulence to the flesh of the now
overworked quadruped, and that a time
will come when horse steaks will be
served at all restaurants and their con
sumption will be looked upon as a mat
ter of course. This Parisian prophet also
foresees the traveling shop and the itin
erant theater. An immense automobile
will carry along both actors, scenery and j
playhouse. On the upper floors of the
great wheeled building will be the
apartments of the company, who will
not have to pack and unpack their be
longings each day.
A train de luxe will become the fash
ionable means by which pleasure out
ings will be taken, and summer travel
ing will no longer be done on dusty and
crowded railway trains. A circuit court
will move from town to town in full
session on wheels, and even funeral
processions will consist of a number of
automobiles linked together like a train
of cars.
All this sounds more or less like a
page from a fairy tale book or the idle
dream of a mere visionary. It repre
sents, nevertheless, something far more
substantial, for it is the conviction of a
farseeing and scholarly French scien
tist, who has had the opportunity of
studying the different inventions which
are slowly but surely being brought to a
state of perfection in his own country,
which may well be called the birthplace
and the home of the horseless carriage.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062245/1902-02-02/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;
q=Automobile+automobile+AUTOMOBILE+automobiles+electric+electrical&amp;
r=-0.104,0.472,0.757,0.579,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AI3S ANNE-
awash InC tjms artt Aurrcufte
jar
Connecticut Avenue Is the Favorite Speeding
Ground of Notables Who Know How to
Guide Their Own Machines Rapid Growth
of a Sport That Has Fastened on Capital
Fashion
Ct I HE men who pared the streets of
I Washington said a visiting
A chauffeur gazing down the
broad expanse of Pennsylvania
Avenue must have had In mind the au
tomobile I have driven ray machine
through Paris London Berlin and New
York but Washington ah it Is the para
dise of the chauffeur
This opinion seems to be held In com
mon by the owners ot automobiles who
have had the opportunity ot driving over
the smooth asphalt pavements of this
city Because the wide streets of Wash
ington are not overovvded with traffic
the amateur chauffeur may drive his au
tomobile at will with the greatest degree
of ease and safety The speed too at
tained on the busiest thoroughfares of
Washington is remarkable when com
pared with the slow fitful headway made
in other large cities
Imagine a man with pleasure in view
driving his auto up Broadway in the
morning or afternoon during business
hours and yet about noon a few days
ago Col Henry Jlay shot down Pennsyl
vania Avenue in his big red wheeled Win
ton easily maintaining hi3 position b the
side of a swiftly moving electric car from
the Treasury Department to the Pennsyl
vania Railway Station an approximate
distance of two thirds of a mile Had he
been no disposed Colonel May might have
continued the entire length of the Avenue
on to the Eastern Branch Bridge with
out checking his speed or discommoding
any citizen of Washington And Pennsyl
vania Avenue is Washingtons principal
thoroughfare
Wit Ting fang for a Race
Mr Wu Ting fang the Chinese Minis
ter who seemed n a great hurry dashed
past Colonel May in a light locomobile
driven by an expert chautfeur The great
Oriental diplomat was gowned as usual
in the Honing rotes typical of hi3 coun
try and seemed to highly enjoy the ex
hilarating motion through keen air He
nodded pleasantly to Colonel May and
made a gesture as if challenging a race
but the latter not being a foreign am
bassador and immune from police regu
lations declined the contest Judging
lion ever from the appearance of Colonel
Mays heavy rcd w heeled carriage one
would not have hesitated long in I1I3
choice of a favorite had the race taken
place
Today Washington Is filled with auto
mobllists Five cars ago there was not
one in the District of Columbia Mr W
J Ios3 was our first chauffeur On March
10 1S37 Mr Foss arrived in Washington
from Hartford Conn and unpacked an
electrical carriage in the freight depot
of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad
Shortly afterward or to be more explicit
at tuenty minutes past oclock in the
afternoon he made his first appearance
on Pennsylvania Avenue in the first au
tomobile to appear on the streets of the
Capital
Previous to the arrival of Mr Foss
f I 0
1
fw
W
Ay
THE TIMES WASHINGTON SUNDAY FEBRUARY 2 1902
I IT IS PARADISE CRIES THF WASHINGTON CHAUFFEUR
y
5
i I ii hi
there had been much agitation in the
columns of the local press concerning the
possible danger that might result to
pedestrians and horse3 from the intro
duction of self propelling vehicles Into
Washington In order to prove that the
local press was unnecessarily alarmed
Mr Toss drove his automobile direct to
the offices of the Commissioners of the
District of Columbia and Invited Mr John
Wight then Chief Commissioner to take
a drive To test the safety of the ma
chine and the advisability of permitting
it to be operated in Washington Mr
Wight accepted the invitation and sur
rounded by an unexpected escort of Li
cyclists loafers and small boys the two
gentlemen made a tour ot the city</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1907-12-11/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;
q=CARRIAGE+electric+Electric+electrical+electricity+Vehicle</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1907-01-13/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;
q=electric+vehicles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>M
vy t I k
Ip sa es s sJ
J yu t fi WHAT IS EXCELLENT IS PERMANENT PERMANENTIt EMER MERSON MERSONi o or
i r It Is Conceded That America Leads the World WorldIn WorldBAK r rIn
In the Manufacture of the Electric Type of Automobile in View of Which It Is Significant ThatBAKER That ThatBAKER
BAKER BAK Rufact 0 ELECTRIC CTRicfwhVE VEHICLES VEHICLEShaveTearned iiaCLES I 1 1aveearned
t
haveTearned a reputation that stands for superiority in the automobile world The name is synonymous with quality qualityThey qualityK
J K They are built by the Baker Motor Vehicle Company of Cleveland In a plant that Is the largest lar st and best equipped of Its kind in the world where electric electricvehicle electricvehicle electrict
t vehicle manufacture is the sole and single purpose TheBaker is not a vehicle to the making of which its producers give half thought thouchthalf half time timeTh 1 1The 1The
The Th best materials procurable procurableskllled skilled workmanship workmanshipartistic artistic treatment of a high order ordergood good ood taste In finish and upholstery upholsteryeach each has its share In making mllkln the BAKER BAKERA
A STANDARD FOR THE ELECTRIC TYPE OF AUTOMOBILE I
J For ForRefinement ForRefinement
Refinement Refinementof
of ofDetail 1 1Detail
Detail DetailThis Detailr
r
This ThisCarrlace ThisCarrla
Carrlace Carrlacet Carrla i iIs e
t Is IsWithout IsWithout T
Without Withouta WithoutPeer
a ar aBAKER
a
Peer PeerI
I
BAKER LANDAULET LAHDAULETo
o
A AGraceful
Graceful GracefulCarriage GracefulCarrlaire GracefulCarriage
Carriage CarrlaireSpecially CarriageSpecially CarriageSpecially
Specially SpeciallyAdapted SpeciallyAdapted SpeciallyAdapted
Adapted Adaptedfor
for forLadles forLadJeG forLadle
Ladles LadlesDriving LadJeGIJrlvlnc LadleDriving
Driving
I I I I I 1ALSO I
I I IALSO
BAXER BA ER QUEEN VICTORIA BAKER GENTLEMANS 9 ROADSTER ROADSTERALSO ROADSTER
ALSO SUBURBANS RUNABOUTS COUPES IMPERIALS STANHOPES STAN HOPES SURREYS DEPOT CARRIAGES VICTORIASI VICTORIAS VICTORIASRICE VICTORIASC
1790 BROADWAY NEW YORK CITY CITYTELEPHONE CITYU CITYTELEPHONE
C U B t RICE R I C E TELEPHONE 2830 COLUMBUS COLUMBUSC
C 9
I
TI</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1916-05-07/ed-1/?sp=27&amp;
q=electric+vehicles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BIG EXHIBIT PLANNED
OF ELECTRIC VEHICLES
To Be Held in Chicago in Connection
With Electric Light
Association.
Coincident with the thirty-ninth annual
convention of the National Electric
Light Association in Chicago, May
22 to 26. there will be an electrical exhibition
in the Auditorium Theater at
which will be displayed electric vehicles
of all types, both passenger and
commercial and accessories, batteries,
charging apparatus, etc. The National
Electric Light Association, with
whom the Electric Vehicle Association
of America affiliated recently, will cooperate
in every way possible toward
the Exploitation of electric vehicles.
It is anticipated that several thousand
central station (electrical supply
companies) representatives, including
executive, will attend the convention,
and it is believed that the exhibit will
afford the manufacturers of electric
vehicles an unprecedented opportunity
to acquaint influential central station
interests with the merits of the electric
vehicle. Effective co-operation in promoting
general public interest in the
electric vehicle is confidently expected
from this source.
The exhibition committee has announced
the arrangements made for
the display of electric vehicles and accessories.
The exhibits will be located
in the Auditorium Theater, which is a
part of the Auditorium Hotel. There
are entrances to the exhibition floor
from any part of the hotel, and it is
also connected with the Congress and
Annex Hotels by a tunnel, making an
exceptional arrangement both for
members as well as exhibitors.</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1912-09-24/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;
q=electric+vehicles</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>by improving your deliveries
Below are some of New
York's prominent users
of Electric Vehicles
11
In a number of instances, electric vehicles
have been in continuous service for the last ten
years and are still giving perfect satisfaction
Sorao Electric Vehicle Users
Acfcatt MWMlI A Cadlt Company
AdatajtprM Corop-my
AaoUna Company
Altlcan. Son U Company
Alt-nan B. A Company
American Bank Note Company
American Express Company
American Meter Company
American Museum of Natural
History
Anheuser Butch Arsocy
Armour ft Company
Arnold, Constable ft Company
Atlas Safe and Machinery Trucking
Company
Austin, Nichols It Company
Beatlleston Woers
Bernhelmer It Schwartz Company
Beet Company
Boettger Company, Henry W.
Bonwi., Teller Company
Brooks brothers
Brown, S. 8. Company
Central Brewing Company of N. Y.
Central Union Gas Company
Chllde Company
Claflin Company, H. B.
Colgate S Company
Columbia Storage Warehouses
Consolidated Gas Company of N, Y.
Cnrtis-Blalsdelt Company
Cuthman, L. A,
Cuihman, 8. Sons
Peering, Milllken Company
Plamond Rubber Company of N. Y.
Doelger, Peter
Ebllng Brewing Company
Beret, George
Swing, Bacon Henry
Firestone Tire sod Rubber Co.
Fith, George P.
FUUchtnar.n Company, Ths
Franklin Simon 4c Company
Gates, Church E. ft Company
Qeneral Baking Company
Osneral Electric Company
Glmbel Brothers
Globe Storage and Carpet Cleaning
Company
Ooldenberg Brothers Company
Gor ham Company
Qreenhut-Bitgel Cooper Company
Anderson Electric Car Co (Detroit Electric)
Broadway and 8oth St. (Potaengtr and Commercial)
Atlantic Vehicle Co 1600 Broadway (Commercial)
Bibcock Electric John WanamjVer, Agent Broad
way and Attor rises (Pauenger)
Biker Vehicle Co 1798 Broadway (Pasienger and
Commercial)
Champion Electric Vehicle Co 100 William Street
(Commercial)
Commercial Truck Co of America 1780 Broadway
(Commercial)
Couple Gear Co 149 Broadway (Commercial)
Field Electric Bus Co 30 Church St (Passenger)
General Motors Truck Co 240 Welt 59th Street
(Commercial)
The New York Edison Company
55 Duano Street
Branch Offlcss for ths Convsnlenes of ths
AeUreM MMae A'drees PWa
424 Broadway Spring M0 J34W.42dSt Bryant 5282
126 Deknoey St. Orchard 190 SSt Third Ava.. Plain CMS
Griscom-Spencer Company
Groh's Sons, M.
Gutfeeund's Olympia Market
Hammscher, Schlemmer Company
Harlem Hospital
Hearn Son, James A,
Helde, Henry
Horn Hardart Company
Hornthal Company
Hupfel, J. Cbr. G. Brewing Company
Hyde tt Sons, A. O.
Jaecket A. Company ii
Jaeckel H. Sons
Johnson It Company
Keith Proctor's Theatres
Kendall Nail and Supply Company
Lewandos
Ltchtenstetn Millinery Company
Lincoln Safe Deposit Company
Loewer'e V. Gambrinus Brewery Co.
Luchow, A.
Macy, R. H. ft Company
Maillard, Henry
Manhattan Storage Company
McCabe Hanger Mfg. Company
McCreery ft Co., James
Merritt, Stephen Embalming Ca
Metropolitan Opera House
Meyrowiti, E. C.
Mirror, The
Morgan Steam Laundry Company
Mors ft Rogers
Motor Delivery Company
Mount Sinai Hospital
Nathan Manufacturing Company
New York Butchers' Dressed
Meat Co.
New York Edison Company, Ths
New York Hospital
New York Public Library
New York Ry. and 8.8, Thne
Table Co.
New York Railways Company
New York and Springfield Despatch
New York Talephone Company
New York Transfer Company
New York Zoological Park
Newcomb, P. J. Mfg. Company
NUaa-Bsment-Pond Company
Ovington Bros. Company
In New York City Electric Vehicles
in New York
Plercy, H.C. ft A. I. Contracting Co.
Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company
Police Department
Poppe, Edward Company
Presbyterian Hospital
Repettl, L.
Rockefeller Institute Hospital
Routs, Charles Broadway
Runkel Brothers, Inc.
Ruppert, Jacob
Safety-Armorite Conduit Company
Schaefer, P. ft M. Brewing Co.
Schant, Joseph
Shaw, Alex. D. Company
Sills, J. S. ft Sons
8il, A., Inc.
Simpson-Crawford Company
Singer Sewing Machine Company
Slater, J. J.
Sloans, W. J.
Speyer Company
Sprague Electric Work
Stelnway Sons
Stern Brothers
Sulxberger Sons Company
Taylor, H. E. Company
Third Avenue Railroad Company
Thurn, Madam L.
TiRany It Company
Tiffany Studios
United Cigar Stores Company
United Dressed Beef Company
United Electric Light It Power Co.
Vantlne, A. A. Company
Vienna Pressed Yeast Company
Wanamaksr, John
Ward Bread Company
Webber, Richard
WeUbecker, Chsrles
West End Storage Warehouss
Wettcott Express Company
Whitman, Clarence It Company
Williams, Ichabod T. tt Bona
Williams Printing Company
Williams, R. C. Company
Wisconsin Condensed Milk Co.
amplefi Bros.
are Sold by
General Vehicle Co 505 Fifth Ave (Commercial)
Healey Co 1654 Broadway (Passenger)
Holt-Chandler Co (Flanders Electric) 1931 Broad.
way (Pasienger)
Hupp-Yeatt Electric Cor Co 19S9 Broadway. (Pai.
aenger and Commercial)
International Fritchle Co 505 5th Avenue (Passenger)
Lantden Co 1784 Broadway (Commercial)
Rauch ft Lang Broadway and 58th St (Passenger)
Studebaker Bros Co of N Y Broadway 59th St
(Passenger and Commercial)
Walker Vehicle Co 30 Church St (Commercial)
Ward Motor Vehicle Co Concord Ave and East
143rd St (Commercial)
At Your Service
Phone Worth 3000
Publlo
I Allreee Pha
27E.12BthSt. Harlscn4020
I 162 E. 149th Si. Metros 3340</text>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91064011/1911-03-03/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;
q=electric+vehicles</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
	  
	  <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015415/1910-09-17/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;
q=electric+vehicles&amp;
r=-0.026,0.128,0.52,0.398,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>

